[
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What property of a sound wave is most commonly associated with loudness?",
        "Answer": "AMPLITUDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the MOST common term for the behavior of light where it appears to bend around small obstacles or the spreading out of waves as light passes through pinholes or slits?",
        "Answer": "DIFFRACTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Upon which of the following does the mass of a body MOST directly depend:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "its magnetic properties",
            "X": "how much volume it has",
            "Y": "the amount of matter it contains",
            "Z": "its location"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Mary and Joe are on a merry-go-round.  Mary is seated near the center of rotation and Joe is on the outer edge.  Which of the following BEST describes their motion:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Mary has a greater acceleration than Joe",
            "X": "Joe has a greater acceleration than Mary",
            "Y": "neither Mary nor Joe are accelerating",
            "Z": "both Mary and Joe have the same acceleration"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Martin is swinging a yo-yo in a large room with a circular motion perpendicular to a level floor.  If the yo-yo breaks away from its string at the top of the yo-yo\u2122s circular path, in what direction will the yo-yo initially move:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "at an angle between horizontal and vertical",
            "X": "straight up, toward the ceiling",
            "Y": "straight down, to the floor",
            "Z": "horizontally, tangent to its original circular path"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the BEST term for the tendency of any mass at rest to remain at rest?",
        "Answer": "INERTIA"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes the most common functions for which most transistors are used:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "to switch on and off or amplify electronic signals",
            "X": "to allow electric current to pass in only one direction while increasing or decreasing the voltage",
            "Y": "to store electrical energy",
            "Z": "to regulate the frequency of electrical sine waves"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the abbreviated name of the most common field effect transistor in modern electronic circuitry:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "DET",
            "X": "MOSFET",
            "Y": "BJT",
            "Z": "BFET"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes how and why electrical resistance is related to temperature:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "as temperature increases, resistance decreases because electrons move faster",
            "X": "as temperature increases, resistance decreases because electrons are lost from the conductor",
            "Y": "as temperature increases, resistance increases because protons move faster",
            "Z": "as temperature increases, resistance increases because atoms vibrate more, increasing electron scattering"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 10-kilogram hay bale is raised to 5 meters above a barn floor and is then lowered to 4 meters below the floor.  Relative to its starting position on the floor, what is the final gravitational potential energy of the bale, in joules, if g is rounded to the first decimal place?",
        "Answer": "\u0152392"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which of the 4 basic forces of the universe is most directly related to the ability of various metals to be hammered and formed into various shapes?",
        "Answer": "ELECTROMAGNETIC"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given that the speed of sound at 0\u00baC at sea level in dry air is 331 meters per second, what is the speed of sound through dry air at sea level, giving your answer in proper SI units rounded to the nearest whole number, if the temperature of the air is 12C?",
        "Answer": "338 METERS PER SECOND"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is closest to the radius of a hydrogen nucleus:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1 micrometer",
            "X": "1 angstrom",
            "Y": "1 picometer",
            "Z": "1 femtometer"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider a planet where g equals 5.0 meters per second squared.  Ignoring friction, if an object started from rest, how far would it fall vertically off a cliff in 4.0 seconds, giving your answer in standard SI units?",
        "Answer": "40 METERS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "During positron emission, which of the following most likely occurs:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "a proton changes to an electron",
            "X": "a proton changes to a neutron",
            "Y": "a neutron changes to an electron",
            "Z": "a neutron changes to a proton"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following 4 isotopes that release energy if they undergo fission:  helium-4;  hydrogen-2;  uranium-235;  iron-56",
        "Answer": "URANIUM-235"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "As opposed to spontaneous emission, what is the type of emission, first theorized by Albert Einstein, where a photon interacts with an atom\u2122s electron which, when it returns to a ground state, emits a coherent photon?",
        "Answer": "STIMULATED EMISSION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Order the following 4 choices from the one with the LOWEST temperature to the one with the HIGHEST temperature:   copper freezes;  water boils;  solar corona;  lead melts",
        "Answer": "WATER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The Meissner effect is most directly associated with which of the following:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "superconductors",
            "X": "rare earth magnets",
            "Y": "very strong electromagnets",
            "Z": "Tesla coils"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rounding g to the first decimal place, how many newtons are required to keep a 120-kilogram sled moving at a constant velocity across a pond if there is a frictional coefficient of 0.20 between the sled and the pond\u2122s surface?  Round your answer to the nearest whole number.",
        "Answer": "235"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes Fermat\u2122s principle:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "light disperses in a specific medium depending on the medium\u2122s refractive index",
            "X": "light follows the path of least time between two points",
            "Y": "the angle of incidence can be greater than the angle of reflection",
            "Z": "light always travels in the same medium at the same speed"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the ideal mechanical advantage of a wheel and axle, if the diameter of the wheel is 500 centimeters and the radius of the axle is 2.5 centimeters?",
        "Answer": "100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What physical property of neutrinos, which was confirmed in the past decade, contradicts earlier assumptions that neutrinos travel at the speed of light?",
        "Answer": "MASS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the angular velocity, in radians per second, of a wheel with a radius of 250 centimeters and a surface velocity of 50 meters per second?",
        "Answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a satellite  moving in a circular orbit is raised to another circular orbit 3-times as far from the Earth's center and where the kinetic energy of the satellite is 3-times less, by what factor does the centripetal force on the satellite decrease?",
        "Answer": "9"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rounded to the first decimal place, how many kilowatt-hours of energy are used if 10 amps flows for one day though a circuit with a resistance of 2 ohms?",
        "Answer": "4.8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes the Balmer series:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "a series of quantum numbers indicating certain energy levels",
            "X": "hydrogen atom spectral line emission",
            "Y": "a sequence of elements that are produced chronologically in supernovae",
            "Z": "the energy spectrum of the early universe"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to the Standard Model of Particle Physics, through what force would the top quark decay?",
        "Answer": "WEAK FORCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following did J. J. Thompson use that primarily led him to conclude that electrons were basic particles of atoms and carried electric charge:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "a compass and batteries",
            "X": "a solenoid",
            "Y": "cathode ray tubes",
            "Z": "electromagnets"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider a satellite that is a uniform sphere rotating about its axis.  What is its moment of inertia, giving your answer in scientific notation and in kilogram meters squared, if it has a mass of 10,000 kilograms and a diameter of 200 meters?",
        "Answer": "4 \u00d7 107"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What was the most sensitive device Coulomb used to measure the electric forces between pith balls?",
        "Answer": ""
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Order the following 3 choices from the MOST penetrating through a thin sheet of cardboard to the LEAST:  beta rays;  alpha rays;  x-rays",
        "Answer": "X-RAYS;  BETA RAYS;  ALPHA RAYS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the radioactive decay scheme of uranium, what is the final stable element produced?",
        "Answer": "LEAD"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider an astronaut on the Moon and g is exactly 1/6th of g on Earth. If he threw an object vertically upwards with an initial velocity of 1.6 meters per second, how many meters up would it be after 1 second, rounding your answer to the first decimal place?",
        "Answer": "0.8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following would a Leyden jar most likely be considered:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "an electroscope",
            "X": "a capacitor",
            "Y": "a resistor",
            "Z": "a Tesla cage"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many joules of energy are used by an electrical appliance operating on 8 amps of current flowing through a 20-ohm resistance circuit for 5 minutes?",
        "Answer": "384,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the most common name for the field, which is believed to act somewhat like a fluid that fills space and endows quarks with mass?",
        "Answer": "HIGGS FIELD"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Order the following 3 isotopes from the one with the LOWEST nuclear binding energy to the HIGHEST:  iron-58;  hydrogen-2;  oxygen-16",
        "Answer": "HYDROGEN-2;  OXYGEN-16;  IRON-58"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes how the most accurate value for the gravitational constant has been determined:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "through theoretical calculations from General Relativity",
            "X": "through theoretical calculations using the masses and motions of certain celestial bodies",
            "Y": "through theoretical calculations from quantum electrodynamics",
            "Z": "through experimentation"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes how Thomas Young produced sufficiently coherent separate light sources in order to produce interference patterns:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "passing coherent light through 2 closely spaced holes in the same opaque screen",
            "X": "passing incoherent light 1st through an opaque screen with a single hole, and then through a 2nd  opaque screen with 2 holes",
            "Y": "passing polarized light through 2 holes in a single opaque screen",
            "Z": "passing laser light through 2 holes in a single opaque screen"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "To early astrophysical researchers, the Sun was originally found to emit about one-third of the expected amount of neutrinos.  Which of the following BEST explains why:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "about 66% of the neutrinos were deflected by the Earth\u2122s magnetic field",
            "X": "two-thirds of the neutrinos were too energetic to be detected",
            "Y": "neutrinos were changing flavor on their way to Earth",
            "Z": "original estimations of the numbers emitted by the Sun were incorrect"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If you were using a 50-millimeter camera lens and changed the lens aperture from 8.0 to 5.6, about how much LESS light would the lens be allowing to pass through it:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "60% less",
            "X": "50% less",
            "Y": "35% less",
            "Z": "22% less"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes spin quantum numbers:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "orientation of intrinsic angular momenta of electrons",
            "X": "centripetal accelerations of atoms",
            "Y": "angular momenta of only hadrons",
            "Z": "centripetal acceleration of electrons"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the spin of the muon, in quantum units?",
        "Answer": "\u00bd"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Uranium-238 and plutonium-239, primarily decay by what mode?",
        "Answer": "ALPHA"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name of the instrument invented by Charles Wilson and used in the early 1900\u2122s in many experiments to show the tracks of charged particles passing through a chamber?",
        "Answer": "CLOUD CHAMBER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By words or numbers, identify all of the following 4 choices that MUST be true for 2 objects in thermal equilibrium:  1) they both must radiate no energy in any direction  2) they must be at the same temperature  3) they both must have the same thermal expansion coefficients  4) they must have the same internal energy",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many kilojoules of thermal energy, rounded to the first decimal place, must be lost from a 250-gram block of Teflon with a specific heat of 1 kilojoule per kilogram kelvin, to lower the block\u2122s temperature from 125\u00ba C to 75\u00ba C?",
        "Answer": "12.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "During beta minus decay, what nucleon type is reduced by one?",
        "Answer": "NEUTRON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true of the Hall effect:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "it can be used to measure the strength of a magnetic field",
            "X": "it is a consequence of a current carrying wire in a magnetic field",
            "Y": "it was one of the first direct indications that negative charges are what move in conductors",
            "Z": "it cannot distinguish between positive and negative particles"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name of the universal constant that relates atomic spectra of elements to that of hydrogen?",
        "Answer": "RYDBERG CONSTANT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assuming the universal gravitational constant is 6.67 \u00d7 10\u015211  newton-meters squared per kilogram squared, what is the gravitational attraction, in newtons, between two, 10-kilogram perfectly uniform spheres separated by a center-to-center distance of 10 meters?",
        "Answer": "6.67 \u00d7 10\u015211"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST explains how a radium isotope with a half-life of about 1,600 years can be found in the crust of the Earth that was formed millions of years ago:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "its decay is slowed by the pressure of the Earth",
            "X": "the radium is replenished by decay of longer lived radioactive elements",
            "Y": "the radium was replenished by meteors and asteroids over the millennia",
            "Z": "the radium is recycled from the Earth\u2122s core where magnetic fields slow the decay"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is probably the most significant limitation for PET scans being used in remote rural hospital sites:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "lack of properly trained personnel",
            "X": "the proximity to production facilities for short-lived radioisotopes",
            "Y": "the high level of radiation requiring special training and increased radiation risk",
            "Z": "difficulty in PET radiotracers binding to receptors when imaging certain human tissues"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes how one would compute the speed for a sound wave through a liquid:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the square of the density of liquid divided by its bulk modulus",
            "X": "the square of the bulk modulus of the liquid divided by its density",
            "Y": "the square root of the density of liquid divided by its bulk modulus",
            "Z": "the square root of the bulk modulus of the liquid divided by its density"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all the leptons that are produced during beta minus decay?",
        "Answer": "ELECTRONS AND ANTINEUTRINOS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What boson is the only particle predicted by the Standard Model of Particle Physics that had not yet been observed as of June 2008?",
        "Answer": "HIGGS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Through what two particles is most of the energy released by a star like our Sun?",
        "Answer": "PHOTONS AND NEUTRINOS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to one of the most common color triangles, if blue and green are primary colors, what is the third primary color?",
        "Answer": "RED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the most common name for the pattern of light and dark lines produced when coherent light is passed through two horizontal slits in a thin opaque sheet, causing superposition of waves projected on a wall?",
        "Answer": "INTERFERENCE PATTERN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Although in many respects difficult to define, what term is MOST often described as a push or a pull that can cause an object to accelerate?",
        "Answer": "FORCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the MOST common term for the inwardly directed force exerted on an object to keep the object moving in a circle?",
        "Answer": "CENTRIPETAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What specific law of motion most directly implies that every action has an equal and opposite reaction?",
        "Answer": "NEWTON\u2122S THIRD LAW"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Jay walks to his car and drives to the store.  The trip takes 20 minutes.  Jay figures how far he traveled on foot and by car and divides the distance by how long the trip took. Which of the following BEST describes what Jay has computed:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "total velocity",
            "X": "average acceleration",
            "Y": "average speed",
            "Z": "instantaneous velocity"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the MOST common term for the type of energy that is most directly related to the energy of atoms, molecules and other small particles that are in random motion within a system?",
        "Answer": "THERMAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In electrochemical cells, what is the most common term for the electrode that acts as the negative electrode?",
        "Answer": "CATHODE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the SI unit of electric charge?",
        "Answer": "COULOMB"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Giving your answer in kilometers per hour per second, what is the average acceleration of a truck traveling on a straight road from 10 kilometers per hour to 50 kilometers per hour in 1 minute and 20 seconds:",
        "Answer": "0.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the most common term used to describe the velocity of an object at any one discrete moment along its path?",
        "Answer": "INSTANTANEOUS VELOCITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What lepton was the first to be discovered?",
        "Answer": "ELECTRON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In one cycle of alternating current, 180\u00ba is given to the point at what fractional amount of the way through the cycle?",
        "Answer": "\u00bd"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the speed of sound in a certain medium is 360 meters per second, what is the wavelength, in meters, of a sound-wave that has a frequency of 60 hertz?",
        "Answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the most common instrument used for measuring gas pressure:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "manometer",
            "X": "anemometer",
            "Y": "tensitometer",
            "Z": "flow-meter"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is TRUE of a sound wave traveling in dry air at STP at a constant velocity:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "if frequency increases, wavelength increases",
            "X": "if frequency increases, wavelength decreases",
            "Y": "if frequency decreases, wavelength decreases",
            "Z": "if frequency increases, wavelength stays the same"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many neutrons does the most common isotope of hydrogen have?",
        "Answer": "ZERO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many neutrons and how many protons are present in a single oxygen-15 nucleus, respectively?",
        "Answer": "NEUTRONS = 7;  PROTONS = 8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Jan is riding her bike northward on Main Street at 20 kilometers per hour and applies her brakes.  In what direction would a physicist MOST likely record her acceleration?",
        "Answer": "SOUTH"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If 200 coulombs pass through a wire in 0.5 seconds, what is the average current, in amps, passing through the wire?",
        "Answer": "400"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The nucleus of what element is the same as an alpha particle?",
        "Answer": "HELIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following 4 choices that would typically be considered to supply electromotive force:  transformers;  generators;  batteries;  conductors",
        "Answer": "TRANSFORMERS;  GENERATORS;  BATTERIES"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the part of an electric motor that functions as an electromagnet:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "ballast",
            "X": "relay",
            "Y": "armature",
            "Z": "brushes"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Using g rounded to the first decimal place, how much does an  80-kilogram person weigh on Earth, giving your answer in proper SI units?",
        "Answer": "784 NEWTONS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A boat\u2122s velocity has a northward velocity component of 15 kilometers per hour and an eastward component of 10 kilometers per hour.  Which of the following BEST represents the direction of the boat\u2122s motion:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "35 kilometers per hour northeast",
            "X": "35 kilometers per hour southwest",
            "Y": "18 kilometers per hour northeast",
            "Z": "12 kilometers per hour northeast"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the frequencies of the first and second overtones, respectively, for a string vibrating at a fundamental frequency of 440 hertz?",
        "Answer": "FIRST = 880;  SECOND = 1320"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following most commonly functions to limit current to one direction:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "capacitor",
            "X": "transformer",
            "Y": "resistor",
            "Z": "diode"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Debbie pushes a 10-kilogram box of books with a horizontal force of 500 newtons.  What is the acceleration of the box, giving your answer in standard SI units, if friction is neglected?",
        "Answer": "50 METERS PER SECOND SQUARED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the device in a galvanic cell that completes the electric circuit by connecting the two sides of the cell with an inert electrolyte:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "electrolytic reservoir",
            "X": "cathode",
            "Y": "conducting wire",
            "Z": "salt bridge"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many joules are in a single watt-hour?",
        "Answer": "3,600"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Radon is primarily produced naturally on Earth most directly from the decay of what element?",
        "Answer": "RADIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By words or numbers, name all of the following 4 choices that are TRUE for an object moving at a constant speed:  1) it must have a constant velocity  2) it must be constantly moving in the same direction  3) it can be accelerating  4) it must have a constant weight",
        "Answer": "3) IT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the electric charge and mass of the carrier particle for the electromagnetic force?",
        "Answer": ""
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the intensity of a sound is 10,000 times as loud as another sound, by how many decibels do the two sounds differ?",
        "Answer": "40"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider an electric charge moving through a magnetic field.  A force acts on the charge perpendicular to the direction of the charge\u2122s motion and direction of the magnetic field.   Which of the following is the MOST common name for this force:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "B field",
            "X": "Lorentz force",
            "Y": "electrodynamic force",
            "Z": "Faraday force"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes the Lorentz Contraction:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "reduction in the mass of a body as it approaches the speed of light",
            "X": "reduction in the length of a body along the direction of motion as it approaches the speed of light",
            "Y": "loss of kinetic energy when any object slows",
            "Z": "loss of potential energy when any body emits electromagnetic radiation"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the MOST common name for the electrical device often made of two parallel conducting plates separated by a paper insulator all rolled into a cylinder to function in storing electrical energy?",
        "Answer": "CAPACITOR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the SI unit of capacitance equal to one coulomb per volt?",
        "Answer": "FARAD"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What was the electrolyte used in the first voltaic piles built by Volta?",
        "Answer": "BRINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the resistance, giving your answer in standard SI units, of an electric device operating on a 9-volt battery that requires 0.05 amps to run?",
        "Answer": "180 OHMS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following colors of light has the greatest angle of refraction in normal glass:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "yellow",
            "X": "green",
            "Y": "orange",
            "Z": "blue"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If a beam of white light passes through a prism, which of the following colors color will emerge on the other side at the lowest angle with respect to the incident beam:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "orange",
            "X": "indigo",
            "Y": "green",
            "Z": "blue"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following are the most important calibration references that Celsius used to devise his temperature scale:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "melting point and boiling point of water",
            "X": "ice-point and freeze-thaw point of water",
            "Y": "specific gravity of water",
            "Z": "boiling point and steam point of water"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the MOST reliable measure of the remaining percentage of stored energy in a lead acid battery:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "pH of the electrolyte",
            "X": "voltage remaining in the battery as measured on a voltmeter",
            "Y": "amount of oxygen gas released",
            "Z": "specific gravity of the electrolyte"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In triboelectric charging, when one object loses electrons, the object that accepts the charges acquires the same number of charges that the other object has lost.  What law most directly governs this equal exchange?",
        "Answer": "CONSERVATION OF CHARGE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider an organ pipe open at both ends.  For a standing wave in the pipe, what is the wavelength of the fundamental tone, in terms of the pipe\u2122s length?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the magnitude of the focal length of a spherically curved convex mirror in air, where R stands for the radius of curvature:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "R divided by 1.22",
            "X": "R divided by 2",
            "Y": "R divided by 1.5",
            "Z": "R times 4"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An emergency floodlight draws 1 ampere from its battery pack.  How many coulombs will flow through the light in 4 hours?",
        "Answer": "14,400"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following MOST directly determines the permittivity of a material:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "ability of the material to magnetize",
            "X": "electrical susceptibility",
            "Y": "electrical insulation capacity",
            "Z": "electrical conductivity"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the SI units for permittivity?",
        "Answer": "FARADS PER METER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the general term for the process of making different types of semiconductors by adding slight amounts of impurities into the silicon matrix?",
        "Answer": "DOPING"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What specific type of semiconductor is produced by doping silicon with arsenic?",
        "Answer": "N-TYPE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the electrolysis of water, if the production of each molecule of oxygen requires 4 units of  electricity, each hydrogen molecule will require how many units of electricity?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the maximum number of 100-watt light bulbs that can run on a 110-volt residential circuit protected by a 15-amp fuse without blowing the fuse?",
        "Answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The escape velocity for a 100 kilogram object to leave planet Earth is approximately 11,000 meters per second. Which of the following is the escape velocity in meters per second for a 200 kilogram object to leave Earth?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "5,500",
            "X": "11,000",
            "Y": "16,500",
            "Z": "22,000"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A proton with a charge of 1.6 x 10-19 coulombs is moving with a speed of 2 x 105 meters per second when it encounters a uniform magnetic field of 2 teslas in a direction perpendicular to the proton\u2122s motion. Providing your answer in scientific notation to two significant figures, what is the magnitude of the force in newtons experienced by the proton?",
        "Answer": "6.4 x 10-14"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 10 kilogram object falls to the surface of a planet where the acceleration due to gravity is 6.5 meters per second squared. If the object is falling at terminal velocity, what is the drag force on the object in newtons?",
        "Answer": "65"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 2000 kilogram car moves with a steady speed of 10 meters per second up a hill that is inclined 10 degrees above the horizontal. Describe the magnitude and direction of the net force on the car after 10 seconds.",
        "Answer": "THERE IS NO NET FORCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 5 kilogram ball is thrown at a wall with a speed of 10 meters per second. If the ball rebounds with a speed of 7 meters per second, what was the magnitude of the impulse that the ball experienced in kilogram meters per second?",
        "Answer": "85"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An airplane is scheduled to travel to a city that is 100 miles due north of the departure city. If there is a wind that blows from east to west at a steady rate of 100 miles per hour, and the plane travels at a speed of 200 miles per hour in still air, then which of the following directions should the plane be directed?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "30 degrees north of east",
            "X": "60 degrees north of east",
            "Y": "30 degrees north of west",
            "Z": "60 degrees north of west"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT correct?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "All planets travel in elliptical orbits with the Sun at the center of the ellipse",
            "X": "The period of a simple pendulum is independent of the mass of the bob",
            "Y": "Gravitational force is a conservative force",
            "Z": "The kilowatt-hour is a unit of energy"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "There are crossed electric and magnetic fields given, respectively, by 5.0 X 106 newtons per coulomb in the x direction and 0.5 tesla in the y direction. A proton traveling in the positive z direction experiences zero resultant force due to these fields. Which of the following is the speed of the proton in meters per second?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "107",
            "X": "2.5 x 106",
            "Y": "106",
            "Z": "10-7"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A solid sphere, a solid cylinder, and a hoop are rolled down an inclined plane without slipping. Given that they have identical masses and diameters, what object reaches the bottom of the ramp first?",
        "Answer": "SPHERE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The ground state energy of the hydrogen atom is  \u015213.6 electron volts. Which of the following is the energy, in electron volts, of the second excited state of hydrogen?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3.4",
            "X": "1.5",
            "Y": "-1.5",
            "Z": "-3.4"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A glass rod with index of refraction n is submersed in an oil bath. Which of the following indices of refraction should the oil have in order to render the rod optically invisible?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Less than n",
            "X": "Greater than n",
            "Y": "The same as n",
            "Z": "None; it\u2122s impossible"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "As a planet travels around a star in an elliptical orbit, identify all of the following four quantities related to the planet that are conserved: 1) angular momentum; 2) total energy; 3) angular velocity; 4) kinetic energy.",
        "Answer": "1, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When a ray of light traveling through the air reflects off the surface of a puddle of pure water, it undergoes which of the following changes in phase?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "360o",
            "X": "180o",
            "Y": "90o",
            "Z": "0\u00b0"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A force displaces an object. The force vector is 3i plus 2j plus k newtons and the displacement vector is 2i plus 6j minus 5k meters. Find the work done in joules.",
        "Answer": "13"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is true about the magnetic field inside an ideal infinite solenoid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It increases linearly as the radius of the solenoid increases",
            "X": "It is zero",
            "Y": "It is uniform",
            "Z": "It decreases continuously along its axis"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An ambulance is approaching the scene of an accident with a speed of 30 meters per second. Its siren has a frequency of 1500 hertz. Providing your answer with two significant figures, find the frequency in hertz of the siren heard by a stationary person waiting for the ambulance, given that the speed of sound is 340 meters per second.",
        "Answer": "1600"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following actions would increase the magnetic force between two parallel current-carrying wires?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Decreasing the length of both wires",
            "X": "Decreasing the current flowing through either of the two wires",
            "Y": "Decreasing the distance between them",
            "Z": "Increasing the distance between them"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A water hose has inner radius 4 centimeters and its nozzle radius is 1 centimeter. The speed of water inside the hose is 3 meters per second. Find the speed of water coming out of the nozzle in meters per second.",
        "Answer": "48"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An airplane traveling faster than the speed of sound passes over a stationary observer on the ground. When does the observer hear the sonic boom?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Only before the plane breaks the sound barrier",
            "X": "When the plane is directly overhead",
            "Y": "After the plane has passed by",
            "Z": "As the plane is approaching the area"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "During the formation of planets in the solar system, a spinning gas disk started to contract due to gravitational forces. Which of the following was an ensuing effect regarding this gas disk?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It rotated faster",
            "X": "It disintegrated due to gravitational forces",
            "Y": "It bulged out to form spheres",
            "Z": "It stopped rotating"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 9 volt battery is connected to a 9 ohm resistor. The current flowing through this circuit is found to be 0.9 amperes. Neglecting the resistance of the wires, what is the internal resistance of the battery in ohms?",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The root mean square current of an alternating current is equal to the direct current that does which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Dissipates an equal amount of power in a resistor as the peak power dissipated by the alternating current",
            "X": "Dissipates an equal amount of power in a resistor as the average power dissipated by the alternating current",
            "Y": "Produces the same average voltage across a resistor as the alternating current would",
            "Z": "Provides the same average current in a resistor as the alternating current would"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following scientists made the theoretical prediction that electromagnetic waves travel through a vacuum at the speed of light?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "James Clark Maxwell",
            "X": "Michael Faraday",
            "Y": "Heinrich Lenz",
            "Z": "Heinrich Hertz"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "During the season when the Northern Hemisphere experiences winter, the Earth is located closest to the Sun. Which of the following effects does this have on the Earth\u2122s revolution speed?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The Earth revolves faster around the Sun at this point",
            "X": "The Earth revolves slower around the Sun at this point",
            "Y": "The speed of revolution at this point is proportional to the cube of the Earth-Sun distance",
            "Z": "The speed of Earth\u2122s revolution is always constant"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If you drop an ice cube into a mixture of alcohol and water and you notice that the ice floats, which of the following can you conclude about the liquid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The liquid is mostly water",
            "X": "The liquid is mostly alcohol",
            "Y": "Nothing, because information on the temperature of the liquid is not given",
            "Z": "The liquid contains exactly equal amounts of water and alcohol"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The Rayleigh criterion defines a limit on which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Resolution in an optical system",
            "X": "Particle velocity in an inelastic collision",
            "Y": "Sustainable pressure for a given material",
            "Z": "Shear stress for a given material"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "How many electrons are required to make up a net negative charge of 1 coulomb?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1.6 x 10-19",
            "X": "6.2 x 1018",
            "Y": "1.6 x 1019",
            "Z": "6.2 x 1019"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A pendulum attached to the ceiling has a mass m, a length L,  [theta] with respect to the vertical. If the pendulum [PEN-juh-luhm] is released, then which of the following is the equation for the kinetic energy of the pendulum at the lowest point in its oscillation?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "mgL",
            "X": "mgL (1 -  [m g L times the quantity 1 minus the sine of theta]",
            "Y": "mgL cos",
            "Z": "mgL (1 - cos)"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If thermal energy is supplied to an insulated solid substance and the temperature does not change, which of the following is true of the solid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It has a high value of thermal conductivity",
            "X": "It is undergoing a phase change",
            "Y": "It has a very low specific heat",
            "Z": "It has a high specific heat"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the frequency, in hertz, of a 50 megavolt photon, given 6.6 \u00d710 joule seconds as Planck's constant and 1.6 \u00d710 coulombs as the elementary charge?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1.2 \u00d710",
            "X": "8.3 \u00d710",
            "Y": "1.2 \u00d710",
            "Z": "8.3 \u00d710"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Three resistors with resistances of 20 ohms, 40 ohms, and 60 ohms are connected in series to a 6 volt battery. What is the voltage drop in volts across the 20 ohm resistor?",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "You sit on a pier and look straight down into the pond below. The apparent depth of the pond from the surface of the water is 5.0 meters. Which of the following is the real depth of the pond in meters, given that the refractive indices of air and water are, respectively, 1.0 and 1.3?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.3",
            "X": "3.8",
            "Y": "5.0",
            "Z": "6.7"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Given that the electric potential at infinity is zero, which of the following is true midway between two positive charges of equal magnitude?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The electric field is zero and the electric potential is zero",
            "X": "The electric field is zero and the electric potential is nonzero",
            "Y": "The electric field is nonzero and the electric potential is zero",
            "Z": "The electric field is nonzero and the electric potential is nonzero"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Kirk\u2122s hearing has minimum audible intensity of 1.0 x 10-12 watts per square meter. If Kirk listens to a sound of intensity 1.0 x 10-11 watts per square meter, what is its sound level in decibels?",
        "Answer": "10"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to Heisenberg\u2122s uncertainty principle, it is impossible to simultaneously measure which of the following in a particle with arbitrary precision?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Position and mass",
            "X": "Position and linear momentum",
            "Y": "Linear momentum and energy",
            "Z": "Position and electric charge"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A simple harmonic oscillator has an amplitude of 2 centimeters. Find the value of the displacement x, in centimeters to the nearest tenth, where the kinetic potential energy of the oscillator is equal to its potential energy.",
        "Answer": "1.4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When a light ray enters into a medium with a higher index of refraction, which of the following is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Its speed increases but its wavelength decreases",
            "X": "Its speed decreases but its wavelength increases",
            "Y": "Both speed and wavelength increase",
            "Z": "Both speed and wavelength decrease"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer in scientific notation with two significant figures, what is the wavelength, in meters, of a 50 mega-electron volt photon, given 6.6 x 10-34 joule seconds as Planck's constant and 1.6 x 10-19 coulombs as the elementary charge?",
        "Answer": "2.5 x 10-14"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is true about the rest mass of a photon?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is always zero",
            "X": "It depends on its wavelength",
            "Y": "It depends on the speed of the inertial observer",
            "Z": "It depends on the medium in which it moves"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An electron is moving at a speed of 1.5 x 107 meters per second. Which of the following is its de Broglie wavelength in meters, given that the mass of the electron is 9.1 x 10-31 kilograms and that the Planck constant h is 6.63 x 10-34 joule seconds?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "5 x 10-11",
            "X": "5 x 10-12",
            "Y": "2 x 1011",
            "Z": "2 x 1012"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is equal to one tesla?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "100 newtons per ampere meter",
            "X": "10 newtons per ampere meter",
            "Y": "10 millinewtons per ampere centimeter",
            "Z": "10 kilograms per ampere second squared"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A puck is nudged due south on a flat, level and frictionless table at a latitude of 30\u00ba north. If the puck's initial speed is 3 millimeters per second, how many millimeters west has it gone after traveling 0.6 meters south?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.1",
            "X": "4",
            "Y": "40",
            "Z": "110"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The  concept of inducing an EMF by rotating in a magnetic field is the fundamental physical effect needed for the function of which of the following devices?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ceiling fan",
            "X": "Transformer",
            "Y": "Electric dynamo",
            "Z": "Electric motor"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A mass of 10 kilograms is rolling down an inclined plane. The plane has a height of 20 meters and a horizontal extent of 40 meters. What is the mechanical advantage of the inclined plane to the nearest tenth?",
        "Answer": "2.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a hydrogen nucleus resonates at 200 megahertz in a field strength of 4.7 teslas, the same nucleus will resonate at what frequency in megahertz at 14.1 teslas?",
        "Answer": "600"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A spacecraft is in circular low-Earth orbit at an altitude of 400 kilometers and needs to be transferred to a circular orbit at an altitude of 120,000 kilometers. Providing your answer with one significant figure, what is the delta-v required for the spacecraft to get into the Hohmann transfer orbit, if the initial velocity is about 7,500 meters per second?",
        "Answer": "3000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name the process by which the loss of an orbital electron results from an inelastic particle collision?",
        "Answer": "IONIZATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A piston containing an ideal gas at a temperature of 300 Kelvin and pressure of 2 bar expands isothermally from a volume of 3 cubic meters to 30 cubic meters. How much work is done by the gas in megajoules to the nearest tenth?",
        "Answer": "1.4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A plane wave of red light goes from the air into a glass block. Which of the following describes how the wave changes?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The frequency decreases",
            "X": "The speed increases",
            "Y": "The wavelength decreases",
            "Z": "The amplitude increases"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Imagine a uniform meter stick supported on a knife edge at the 40 centimeter mark. The right end of the meter stick with the 100 centimeter mark swings down. To balance the meter stick, at what centimeter mark should you hang an object with mass equal to that of the meter stick?",
        "Answer": "30"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two identical positively charged spheres are separated by a distance much bigger than their radii so that electric and gravitational forces are balanced. If the mass of each object is multiplied by 4, by what factor should the charge on each be multiplied so that the two forces still balance?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2",
            "X": "4",
            "Y": "8",
            "Z": "16"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A car is travelling at a constant 30 meters per second for 10 seconds. The car then undergoes constant deceleration for 5 seconds, coming to a stop. How far in meters did the car travel during the entire 15 second time interval?",
        "Answer": "375"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the effect on the resistance of a wire if it is replaced with an equally thick wire of a material of higher resistivity and longer length?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The effect cannot be predicted without knowing the actual value of the resistivities of the materials",
            "X": "Resistance increases",
            "Y": "Resistance decreases",
            "Z": "Resistance is unchanged"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 2 henry inductance coil is connected in series to a 100 ohm resistor to create an LR circuit. If this circuit is connected to a 12 volt power supply, what are, respectively, the initial current in the circuit and the final current in the circuit after it has been connected for a long time, both measured in amperes?",
        "Answer": "INITIAL CURRENT = 0, FINAL CURRENT = 0.12"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A top that is spinning on a table begins to precess. Which of the following would decrease the rate of precession of the top?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "An increase in the torque that the top experiences due to gravity",
            "X": "A decrease in its moment of inertia",
            "Y": "A decrease in its angular velocity",
            "Z": "An increase in its angular velocity"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two parallel plates of equal area are separated by a distance of 20 millimeters. If the plates are connected to a 12 volt battery, providing your answer in scientific notation with one significant figure, what is the magnitude of the electrostatic force in newtons that a microcoulomb charge between the plates would feel?",
        "Answer": "6 x 10-4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the amplitude of a simple harmonic oscillator is decreased to 50% of its initial value, providing your answer as a decimal, compute the ratio of its final energy to its initial energy.",
        "Answer": "0.25"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Three capacitors with capacitances of 2 microfarads, 2.5 microfarads, and 10 microfarads are connected in series. Find the combined capacitance in microfarads.",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the current in amperes for a simple circuit with a potential difference of 100 volts and two 10 ohm resistors in parallel?",
        "Answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Some scientists have predicted the melting of polar ice caps due to climate change. Which of the following changes would be caused by the melting?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The moment of inertia of the Earth would increase",
            "X": "The moment of inertia of the Earth would decrease",
            "Y": "The angular momentum associated with the Earth\u2122s rotation would increase",
            "Z": "The angular momentum associated with the Earth\u2122s rotation would decrease"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "For a small ball at the end of a string, calculate the angular momentum in joule seconds if the ball weighs 3 kilograms, has a tangential velocity of 10 meters per second, and has an orbit with a 10 meter radius?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "33.3",
            "X": "100",
            "Y": "300",
            "Z": "900"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a photoelectric experiment, if the intensity of the incident light beam is unchanged while the frequency of the light beam is increased, which of the following is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The number of photoelectrons emitted per second increases",
            "X": "The maximum kinetic energy of the photoelectrons emitted increases",
            "Y": "The maximum kinetic energy of the photoelectrons emitted decreases",
            "Z": "The maximum kinetic energy of the photoelectrons emitted remains unchanged"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A ray of light is moving through a vacuum at an angle of 60\u00b0 from the vertical, when it enters an oil with a horizontal surface where the ray is bent so that it makes an angle of 30\u00b0 with the vertical. Which of the following best represents the index of refraction of the oil?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.5",
            "X": "1.0",
            "Y": "1.7",
            "Z": "2.0"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A communications satellite is orbiting the Earth at a speed of 3000 meters per second. What would be the orbital speed in meters per second of a similar satellite that is 4 times as far from the center of the Earth as the first satellite?",
        "Answer": "1500"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 5 kilogram mass is oscillating on a spring with a spring constant of 20 newtons per meter. What is the frequency of the oscillation of this mass in radians per second?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 200 microfarad parallel plate capacitor is connected to a 6 volt battery. Once the capacitor is fully charged, it is disconnected from the battery and a dielectric is inserted between the plates with a dielectric constant of 5. Expressed as a decimal, what is the new voltage across the capacitor?",
        "Answer": "1.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A proton enters a uniform magnetic field that is oriented perpendicular to the motion of the proton. Which of the following will NOT affect the radius of the circular path in which the proton moves?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The velocity of the proton",
            "X": "The magnitude of the magnetic field",
            "Y": "The momentum of the proton",
            "Z": "The position of the proton in the magnetic field"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A long wire is carrying 10 amperes of current. Providing your answer in scientific notation, what is the magnetic field in teslas due to the wire at a radial distance of 2 meters from the center of the wire?",
        "Answer": "1 x 10-6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A long wire carrying a 3 ampere current is placed in a magnetic field of 1 tesla so that a straight 2 meter segment of the wire makes an angle of 30\u00b0 with the field direction. What is the magnitude of the force in newtons on the wire segment?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A charge of +1 nanocoulombs is placed at the origin, and a charge of +4 nanocoulombs is placed 10 centimeters away. Providing your answer in centimeters to the nearest tenth, at what distance from the origin is the electric field zero?",
        "Answer": "3.3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A block floats at rest with 1/3 of its total volume below the surface of the water. The block is pushed down until it is completely submerged. Which of the following is the magnitude of the net force on the block when it is released?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Half of the block\u2122s weight",
            "X": "Equal to the block\u2122s weight",
            "Y": "Twice the block\u2122s weight",
            "Z": "Three times the block\u2122s weight"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 2 kilogram box is pushed forward with a 10 newton force while it experiences a 5 newton force of kinetic friction in the opposite direction. Providing your answer to the nearest meter, after 3 seconds, how far has the box moved?",
        "Answer": "11"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A student is in a rollercoaster that is going through a loop on the inside of the track. At the top of the loop, the normal force on the student has a magnitude of 100 newtons. If the student\u2122s weight and mass are 500 newtons and 50 kilograms, respectively, then what is the magnitude of the student\u2122s acceleration at the top of the loop in meters per second squared?",
        "Answer": "12"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A pendulum that has a period of 2 seconds on the Earth is moved to another planet where the period is now 4 seconds. Given the acceleration due to gravity on Earth as 10 meters per second squared and providing your answer to two significant figures, what is the acceleration due to gravity on this new planet in meters per second squared?",
        "Answer": "2.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "You stand 2 meters from a point source of sound. Ignoring any effects due to reflection and providing your answer as a fraction in simplest form, by what factor would the intensity of sound be multiplied if you were to move to a position 3 meters from the source?",
        "Answer": "4/9"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A wave pulse travels along a string with a speed of 20 meters per second. If the tension in the string is 100 newtons, providing your answer as a decimal, what is the linear density of the string in kilograms per meter?",
        "Answer": "0.25"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Capacitance is inversely related to which of the following properties of a plate capacitor?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Area of plates",
            "X": "Distance between plates",
            "Y": "Dielectric constant",
            "Z": "Absolute permittivity"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A figure skater goes into a spin with her arms outstretched, having a moment of inertia of 2.5 kilogram meters squared and an angular velocity of 5 radians per second. If the skater pulls her arms in and reduces her moment of inertia to 1.5 kilogram meters squared, what is her final angular velocity to the nearest radian per second?",
        "Answer": "8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The 2011 Nobel Prize in Physics was awarded for the demonstration of which of the following properties of the expansion of the universe?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is speeding up",
            "X": "It is slowing down",
            "Y": "It will reverse itself",
            "Z": "It is constant"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A wheel spinning at a rate of 20 revolutions per minute slows steadily to a stop in a time of 30 seconds. If the wheel has a radius of 0.5 meters, through what distance to the nearest meter does a point on the rim travel during this time?",
        "Answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the potential difference in volts for a simple circuit with a current of 6 amperes and three 10 ohm resistors in series?",
        "Answer": "180"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Vectors F and R are given by, respectively, 2 i minus 3 j and  i plus 4 j. What is the cross product R X F [R cross F]?",
        "Answer": "-11k"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An unpolarized electromagnetic plane wave is incident on a linear polarizer whose transmission axis is parallel to the y-axis. After passing through the polarizer, which of the following best describes the oscillation direction of the magnetic field?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Along the positive and negative x-axis",
            "X": "Along the positive and negative y-axis",
            "Y": "A direction pointing in either the 1st or 3rd quadrant",
            "Z": "A direction pointing in either the 2nd or 4th quadrant"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 5 kilogram object moves with a velocity v = 2t 2 + 2 meters per second where t is in seconds. What is the net force on the object in newtons after 2 seconds?",
        "Answer": "40"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Three resistors are connected to a battery in parallel. The resistors have resistances of 1 ohm, 100 ohms, and 1000 ohms. The equivalent resistance of the circuit is nearest to which of the following values in ohms?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1",
            "X": "100",
            "Y": "1000",
            "Z": "1101"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If it takes 12 seconds total for a ball to travel straight up from the ground and fall back to earth, neglecting air resistance and given g as 10 meters per second squared, what was the maximum height it reached in meters?",
        "Answer": "180"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A proton is moving to the north when it experiences a uniform magnetic field that is pointing vertically downward. In which cardinal direction should an electric field be applied to keep the proton moving due north?",
        "Answer": "EAST"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the kinetic energy in joules to two significant figures of a car with a mass of 2000 kilograms moving with a speed 100 kilometers per hour?",
        "Answer": "770,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In an electromagnetic wave, the E field vector points in the  positive x direction and the B field vector points in the negative y direction. What is the direction of propagation of the wave?",
        "Answer": "NEGATIVE Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Let g represent the acceleration due to gravity at the surface of the Earth. A planet with one third of the mass of the Earth and one half of the radius of the Earth will have an acceleration due to gravity near its surface that is which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "one third g",
            "X": "two thirds g",
            "Y": "g",
            "Z": "four thirds g"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given the speed of light in a vacuum to be 3 x 108 meters per second, what is the index of refraction for a medium where the speed of light is found to be 2.5 x 108 meters per second?",
        "Answer": "1.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the exact speed in meters per second of an object with a mass of 2 kilograms, executing simple harmonic motion with amplitude of 2 meters, at the end of a spring with a spring constant of 8 newtons per meter, when the displacement of the object is half the maximum amplitude?",
        "Answer": "23"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A small marble is placed at the bottom of a hemispherical bowl. When the marble is displaced a small amount from the center, it oscillates about the bottom of the bowl. Which of the following changes would increase the period of oscillation of the marble?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Using a marble of larger mass",
            "X": "Using a marble of smaller mass",
            "Y": "Using a bowl of larger radius",
            "Z": "Using a bowl of smaller radius"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A current of 100 milliamperes flows through an ohmic circuit element across which the potential drop is 5 volts. Which of the following is the resistance in ohms?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "50",
            "X": "20",
            "Y": "0.2",
            "Z": "0.05"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A torsional pendulum consists of a disk suspended from a torsional spring. The torsional pendulum is set into oscillation when the disk is displaced through a small angle. Which of the following changes would increase the frequency oscillation of the torsional pendulum?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Decrease the moment of inertia of the disk",
            "X": "Increase the moment of inertia of the disk",
            "Y": "Decrease the torsional spring constant of the spring",
            "Z": "Decrease the angle through which the disk was displaced"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An object floats with 10% of its volume below the surface of the water in a pond. Find the average density of the object in kilograms per cubic meter.",
        "Answer": "100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the unit of the product of resistance and capacitance?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Farad",
            "X": "Ohm",
            "Y": "Mho",
            "Z": "Second"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "For photons traveling through a vacuum, a photon in the ultraviolet spectrum has which of the following characteristics, compared to a photon in the infrared spectrum?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Longer wavelength",
            "X": "Same speed",
            "Y": "Lower frequency",
            "Z": "Half the energy"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When a clay pigeon breaks into pieces after being shot, which of the following can be said about the shape of the trajectories of these pieces of clay?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They are always elliptical",
            "X": "They are always parabolic",
            "Y": "They are always hyperbolic",
            "Z": "They may be any of elliptical, parabolic, or hyperbolic depending on the speed of the components"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 1000 kilogram car moving with a speed of 6 meters per second collides perfectly inelastically with 2000 kilogram truck that is at rest. What is the change in kinetic energy in joules during this collision?",
        "Answer": "12,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 10 kilogram box is moving with a speed of 5 meters per second along a level surface. If the coefficient of kinetic friction between the box and the surface is 0.1 and the coefficient of static friction between the box and the surface is 0.2, which of the following is the frictional force in newtons that acts on the box, given that the acceleration due to gravity is 9.8 meters per second squared?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1.0",
            "X": "2.0",
            "Y": "9.8",
            "Z": "19.6"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Three 300-microfarads capacitors are connected in series to a 12 volt battery. What is the energy stored in one of these capacitors in microjoules after the circuit has reached steady state?",
        "Answer": "2400"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A mass is suspended from the ceiling by two ropes. Rope 1 makes a larger angle with the horizontal than Rope 2 does. Which of the following statements is true about the tension in the ropes?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The tensions in the ropes are equal",
            "X": "The tension in Rope 1 is greater than the tension in Rope 2",
            "Y": "The tension in Rope 2 is greater than the tension in Rope 1",
            "Z": "The tension in Rope 2 is zero"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 5 microcoulomb charge is uniformly distributed in a 1-meter diameter sphere. Given that the coulomb constant is 9 x 109 newton meters squared per coulomb squared, what is the electric field in newtons per coulomb at a radius of 0.25 from the center of the sphere?",
        "Answer": "0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the scientific term for a change in velocity per unit time?",
        "Answer": "ACCELERATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the most common term in physics for the product of mass times velocity?",
        "Answer": "MOMENTUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the most common term for the general type of wave that results from the vibration of a physical medium:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "mechanical",
            "X": "electromagnetic",
            "Y": "perfect",
            "Z": "pulsed"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is LEAST accurate:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "alpha particles are the same as helium nuclei",
            "X": "polarization of light supports the particle behavior of light",
            "Y": "a photon is a particle of light",
            "Z": "light slows down when it moves from a vacuum into glass"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A circuit with 2 different resistors wired in series will have a total resistance that is:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "equal to the sum of the two resistances",
            "X": "less than either resistance",
            "Y": "equal to that of the greater resistance",
            "Z": "equal to that of the lesser resistance"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the most common isotope of carbon?",
        "Answer": "CARBON-12"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two-thirds of the charge is removed from a capacitor without changing its capacitance.  The stored energy in the capacitor is now what multiple of the original:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1/3rd",
            "X": "1/9th",
            "Y": "3",
            "Z": "9"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If a sound is emitted in dry air at 27\u00bcC and takes 5 seconds to reach a person, how far away, in meters, from the sound source is the person:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1,655",
            "X": "1,682",
            "Y": "1,736",
            "Z": "1,873"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Thomas Young\u00d5s double slit experiments give the most direct and strongest support for which of the following:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the wave nature of light",
            "X": "the constancy of the speed of light",
            "Y": "the existence of the photon",
            "Z": "the particle nature of light"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Order the following 3 locations from the SLOWEST to the FASTEST for objects accelerating because of gravity:  Mount Everest;  North Pole;  New York City",
        "Answer": "MOUNT EVEREST;  NEW YORK CITY;  NORTH POLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A boy gets a sled for his birthday in July.  He exerts a  50-newton horizontal force as he pulls the 80-newton sled across the cement driveway at a constant speed.  What is the coefficient of kinetic friction, to the second decimal place, between the driveway and the metal blades of the sled?",
        "Answer": "0.63"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "It is now January and there is snow!  The coefficient of friction is now 0.10.  If a person weighing 500 newtons sits on the 80-newton sled, what horizontal force, in newtons, is needed to pull the sled across the snow at constant speed?",
        "Answer": "58"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A field emission microscope requires which of the following:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "a conductor with a very fine point",
            "X": "high energy alpha particles",
            "Y": "a light source with a wavelength shorter that the smallest observable feature size",
            "Z": "a low amplitude, time-varying magnetic field"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rounded to the nearest thousand, how many joules of work are done in pulling a wagon with a force of 2000 newtons over a horizontal surface of 10 meters, with a chain that makes a 45\u00bc angle with the surface?",
        "Answer": "14,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The scattering of alpha particles by a metal foil was first studied by:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Compton",
            "X": "Rutherford",
            "Y": "Bragg",
            "Z": "Rayleigh"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A pole vaulter with a mass of 150 kilograms is traveling at 25 meters per second just prior to landing on an air mattress which collapses and allows the vaulter to come to rest over a period of 2.0 seconds.  What was the force of the impact between the vaulter and the air mattress, in newtons?",
        "Answer": "1875"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following could most practically be used as a detector for the automatic door opening system you find at your local grocery store:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "infrared camera system",
            "X": "ultrasonic motion detector",
            "Y": "radar system",
            "Z": "optical camera system"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The radar system associated with the automatic doors at a local grocery store uses 10.5 gigahertz radiation.  If the door is to open for a person walking towards it at 1 meter per second, which Doppler shift must the radar system be able to detect:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "a red shift of 2 hertz",
            "X": "a blue shift of 35 hertz",
            "Y": "a red shift of 160 hertz",
            "Z": "a blue shift of 1.8 hertz"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Billy drops his teddy bear out of the car window 2 meters from the ground while his father is driving down Main Street at 20 meters per second.  In seconds to the first decimal place, how long does it take for the bear to hit the ground, assuming air resistance is neglected?",
        "Answer": "0.6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Using your rounded answer to the above question and remembering that the father is driving down Main Street at 20 meters per second, how far will the bear travel horizontally before striking the ground, rounded to the nearest whole meter and again assuming air resistance is neglected?",
        "Answer": "12"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the underwater pressure in atmospheres in a fresh water lake at a depth of 20 meters?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the resonant frequency, in hertz to the nearest whole number, of a three-component series circuit that has a 2 henry inductor, a 2 microfarad capacitor, and a 2 ohm resister?",
        "Answer": "80"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Often some of the strongest spectral lines in cold interstellar gas are produced by:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "neutral lithium",
            "X": "ionized iron",
            "Y": "carbon and iron",
            "Z": "calcium and sodium"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The cosmic background radiation discovered by Penzias and Wilson closely matches the radiation from a black body with what temperature Kelvin, to the nearest whole number?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The process in which an atom reradiates a photon after interacting with an incident photon of the same energy is called:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Rayleigh scattering",
            "X": "the Cherenkov effect",
            "Y": "Bragg\u00d5s Law",
            "Z": "Thomson scattering"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A protanomalous person has decreased sensitivity of the red cones in his or her eyes.  Which of the following color pairs will this person have difficulty distinguishing between:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "red and green",
            "X": "blue and purple",
            "Y": "yellow and turquoise",
            "Z": "dark navy blue and black"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a compound gearing arrangement where a 40-tooth gear drives an 80-tooth gear which is directly connected to a 50-tooth gear that drives a 100-tooth gear, the total reduction is a factor of:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2",
            "X": "2.5",
            "Y": "4",
            "Z": "5"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Elastic deformation is BEST described as:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the linear portion of a stress/strain curve",
            "X": "the ultimate strength of a material",
            "Y": "0.02% elongation",
            "Z": "permanent deformation"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What specific type of semiconductor is produced by adding phosphorus to silicon?",
        "Answer": "N-TYPE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many turns are in the secondary coil of a transformer that has a primary coil with 20,000 turns and is designed to step down 12,000 volts AC to 120 volts AC?",
        "Answer": "200"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What percent of energy in our Universe is believed to consist of dark matter and normal matter:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "4.4%",
            "X": "16%",
            "Y": "27%",
            "Z": "73%"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Order the following 4 substances from the one with the LOWEST dielectric constant to the HIGHEST at 20\u00bcC:  mica;  paraffin;  vacuum;  pure water",
        "Answer": "VACUUM;  PARAFFIN;  MICA;  PURE WATER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In using a frequency of light that causes the photoelectric effect, which of the following will occur when there is an increase in the intensity of the incident light beam on a metal surface:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the maximum kinetic energy of ejected electrons will increase exponentially",
            "X": "the maximum kinetic energy of ejected electrons will increase linearly",
            "Y": "it will increase the work function",
            "Z": "more electrons will be ejected from the metal"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true according to the Standard Model of Particle Physics:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "quarks carry color charge",
            "X": "hadrons are color-neutral particles",
            "Y": "quarks can be isolated from their hadrons",
            "Z": "the carrier particle for the electromagnetic interaction has zero charge"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a rock is spun on a sling with a frequency of 100 revolutions per minute, what is the rock\u00d5s period, in seconds?",
        "Answer": "0.6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 3-kilogram model airplane has velocity components of 5 meters per second due east and 8 meters per second due north.  What is the plane\u00d5s kinetic energy, in joules to the nearest whole number?",
        "Answer": "134"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Within the Standard Model of Particle Physics what particle is responsible for carrying the strong nuclear force?",
        "Answer": "GLUON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the principle or law that fundamentally limits the accuracy of specifying at the same time the momentum and position of a particle?",
        "Answer": "HEISENBERG UNCERTAINTY PRINCIPLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following was the big surprise in the classic gold foil experiments of Rutherford, Geiger and Marsden:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "alpha particles sometimes disappeared",
            "X": "electrons would not penetrate the nucleus",
            "Y": "the atom was mostly space as supported by the finding that most alpha particles continued on a straight path and hit the rear of the detection screen",
            "Z": "some alpha particles left evidence of having returned almost straight back to hit the front part of the detection screen"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Most of the early classical experiments with alpha particles were done by Rutherford and co-workers using a simple scintillation detector, which was a screen most commonly coated with what substance?",
        "Answer": "ZINC SULFIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the hydrogen nucleus has a lower binding energy per nucleon than the helium nucleus",
            "X": "the tritium nucleus contains 3 nucleons",
            "Y": "it is typically easier to fission U-238 than U-235 with slow neutrons",
            "Z": "fission fragments of a nucleus are more often about 60% and 40% of the original mass of the atom than 50% and 50%"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the Standard Model of particle physics, all forces arise because of the exchange of what fundamental class of particles?",
        "Answer": ""
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the focal length, in centimeters and giving the proper sign, of a convex mirror that has a radius of curvature of 12 centimeters?",
        "Answer": "\u00d06"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rutherford and coworkers in the early 20th century found that when alpha particles strike nitrogen-14 nuclei, they most commonly produce what element?",
        "Answer": "OXYGEN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the angular velocity, in radians per second, of a wagon wheel with a diameter of 2 meters and a surface velocity of 3 meters per second?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The dread pirate Roberts orders his crew into a 100 kilogram rowboat to sail to an island to look for buried treasure.  If the rowboat has a capacity of 1.10 cubic meters and is in freshwater, how many 50 kilogram pirates can board the rowboat before it would sink?",
        "Answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A material with a negative index of refraction has which of the following technologically significant implications:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "allowing imaging at resolutions below the diffraction limit of light",
            "X": "superluminal light",
            "Y": "improved spin coherence times",
            "Z": "realization of high temperature superconductors"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The experimental technique of x-ray diffraction would be inappropriate for obtaining which of the following physical parameters of a material:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "periodicity of a quantum well structure",
            "X": "the atomic spacing of a crystal lattice",
            "Y": "the amount of strain in a crystal lattice",
            "Z": "impurity concentration in an unknown crystalline sample"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider an electrician who is about to drill holes though a series of 2-inch by 10-inch by 16-foot floor joists that are supported only at their ends by walls.  Which of the following hole locations would DECREASE the load strength of each joist the LEAST:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "7 feet in from one of the supporting walls near the bottom edge",
            "X": "7 feet from one of the supporting walls near the top edge",
            "Y": "1 foot from one of the supporting walls near the bottom edge",
            "Z": "1 foot from one of the supporting walls half way down from the top edge"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A metal alloy beam 10-meters long expands in length at 0.25% per kelvin at temperatures about room temperature.  If the beam is heated from 0\u00bcC to 30\u00bcC, how many centimeters will it increase in length?",
        "Answer": "75"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST explains how a linear accelerator speeds up charged particles:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "creating large electric fields that push particles along on electromagnetic waves",
            "X": "using magnets to push them along their trajectories",
            "Y": "using superconducting magnets to accelerate particles to near light speed",
            "Z": "using synchrotron radiation to ionize particles which are then accelerated by superconducting magnets"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Particle accelerators used by physicists are generally linear or circular.  Which of the following is a major advantage of linear designs over circular:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "high energy electrons can only be obtained in linear accelerators",
            "X": "linear accelerators do not need the large, expensive magnets of circular accelerators and do not have as much radiation loss",
            "Y": "they typically can produce more chances for collisions because they use fixed targets",
            "Z": "they can be used in fixed target experiments while circular accelerators cannot"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the respective frequencies of the second and third harmonics of a string with a fundamental frequency of 262 hertz?",
        "Answer": "524 AND 786"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assuming that they roll without sliding, order the following 3 objects from the one with the SMALLEST rotational velocity down an arbitrarily long inclined plane to the one with the LARGEST, after 5 seconds:  a one-inch-diameter o-ring;  a three-quarter inch-diameter marble;  a quarter",
        "Answer": "A ONE-INCH-DIAMETER O-RING;  A QUARTER;  A THREE-QUARTER INCH-DIAMETER MARBLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The discovery of the cosmic background radiation was originally done with:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the Hubble space telescope",
            "X": "the Arecibo radio telescope",
            "Y": "a ground-based horn-shaped microwave antenna",
            "Z": "a microwave receiver in a high altitude hot air balloon"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following recently gave what many think as irrefutable evidence for the existence of dark matter:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the discovery of gravitational waves at the LIGO facility at Pacific Northwest National Lab",
            "X": "Chandra X-ray images of hot gases during a violent merger of the \u00d2bullet cluster\u00d3 of galaxies",
            "Y": "creation of quark-gluon plasma at the Relativistic Heavy Ion Collider",
            "Z": "the finding that neutrinos account for more mass of the universe than all the stars in the universe"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Physicists have developed theories, called Grand Unified Theories, that attempt to unify the forces of the universe into one.  As temperatures get higher going back through the early universe, which three of the four forces do these theories typically unify first?",
        "Answer": "ELECTROMAGNETIC;  STRONG;  WEAK"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Many physicists are highly critical of the rationale that seeks to explain phenomena of the universe by indicating that, if things had been otherwise, life and humans would not exist.  This is MOST commonly known as what principle?",
        "Answer": "ANTHROPIC PRINCIPLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a 100-kilogram bear climbs from the bottom to the top of a vertical 10-meter tree in 10 seconds, what is the bear\u00d5s average power output, in watts?",
        "Answer": "980"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two masses are hung in a physics lab.  These are tied to opposite ends of a weightless string which passes over a frictionless pulley.  If the masses are released from rest and mass #1 = 1 kilogram and mass #2 = 2 kilograms, what is the acceleration, to the first decimal place, of mass #1 and in what direction, up or down?",
        "Answer": "3.3 AND UP"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the MOST likely ultimate fate of the universe if mass in the universe is less than the critical density and there is no dark energy:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "it will eventually stop expanding and maintain a constant size",
            "X": "it will stop expanding and collapse",
            "Y": "it will expand forever",
            "Z": "it will expand at an accelerating rate and then nearly collapse, then expand again and continue to oscillate this way forever"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST explains why scientists believe the early universe up to a few hundred thousand years old was opaque:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "deuterium at those temperatures absorbed all electromagnetic radiation",
            "X": "there was no electromagnetic radiation",
            "Y": "free electrons scattered photons and prevented them from traveling very far",
            "Z": "the temperature had cooled so far that space without stars was a dark void"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "electrons are directly affected by the strong nuclear force",
            "X": "general relativity predicts the existence of black holes",
            "Y": "a deuterium atom has two nucleons",
            "Z": "many cosmologists believe that neutrinos make up about as much mass as all the stars in the universe"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Ashley, who weighs 450 newtons, is with her dad at the playground, and she is sitting on a swing that is 0.60 meters above the ground.  Her dad pulls her back and lets her go when the swing is 1.1 meters above the ground.  How fast, in meters per second to the first decimal place, is Ashley moving when the swing passes through its lowest position?",
        "Answer": "3.1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is MOST closely related to the movement of charge in non-ceramic superconductors:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "charge confinement",
            "X": "Josephson effect",
            "Y": "Cooper pairs",
            "Z": "Hall movement"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a standard characteristic of a laser:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "coherent beam",
            "X": "optical gain",
            "Y": "distinctly identifiable pumping threshold",
            "Z": "distinctly identifiable pumping turn-off"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "As reported recently in the journal Science, researchers have succeeded in producing a high efficiency organic LED.  They began with a blue emitting system and then added a single color light emitting phosphor to obtain white light.  What was the single color phosphor they used?",
        "Answer": "YELLOW"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A sphere of radius 1 meter contains uniformly distributed charge of charge density rho.  Assuming #/$! (rho over epsilon-naught) equals 30 volts per meter squared, what is the magnitude of electric field at a radius of 0.5 meters?",
        "Answer": "5 V/m"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the most common term for what Einstein first proposed to operate in empty space, but later rejected as his greatest blunder following Hubble\u00d5s discovery of the expansion of the universe?",
        "Answer": "COSMOLOGICAL CONSTANT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following 4 particles that are leptons:   muon,  photon,  tau,  electron",
        "Answer": "MUON;  TAU;  ELECTRON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If a car is going around a corner, which of the following statements correctly describes the relationship among the speeds of the wheels on the car:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the wheels all rotate at the same speed",
            "X": "the wheels on the inside of the corner rotate faster because they have less distance to travel",
            "Y": "the wheels on the inside of the corner rotate faster because they have more distance to travel",
            "Z": "the wheels on the outside of the corner rotate faster because they have more distance to travel"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many kilometers will a mosquito travel in 9.5 hours if it moves in a straight path with an average speed of 8 kilometers per hour?",
        "Answer": "76"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the SI unit for the product of newtons and meters:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "henry",
            "X": "watt",
            "Y": "erg",
            "Z": "joule"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a gearing arrangement where a 10-tooth pinion drives a 40-tooth gear, what is the gear ratio:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1 to 4",
            "X": "4 to 1",
            "Y": "1 to 10",
            "Z": "40 to 1"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Giving your answer as north, south, east, or west relative to a point on the Equator, in what direction is the Earth\u00d5s angular velocity as it rotates daily about its axis?",
        "Answer": "NORTH"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Ignoring air resistance, wind velocity, and the rotation of the Earth, if a projectile is fired directly upwards, the horizontal component of the projectile\u00d5s velocity:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "is zero",
            "X": "remains a non zero constant",
            "Y": "continuously increases",
            "Z": "continuously decreases"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Neglecting air resistance, at what angle above the horizontal would you aim your garden hose nozzle to obtain the greatest horizontal distance if the nozzle is at ground level:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0\u00bc",
            "X": "30\u00bc",
            "Y": "45\u00bc",
            "Z": "60\u00bc"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Tim hears water dripping from a faucet while trying to take a nap.  If he counts 20 drops in one minute, what is the period of the drops, in seconds?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the SI unit given to a volt per ampere?",
        "Answer": "OHM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the current, in amperes, for a 3600-watt electric conveyor operating on a 240-volt power source?",
        "Answer": "15"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The slope of a velocity versus time graph represents:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "acceleration",
            "X": "velocity",
            "Y": "position",
            "Z": "displacement"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Under which of the following conditions is the average velocity equal to the average of an object\u00d5s initial and final velocity:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "always",
            "X": "never",
            "Y": "only when the acceleration changes",
            "Z": "only when the acceleration is constant"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Stories have been told about opera singers breaking crystal glass by singing a certain tone loud enough.  What is the most common term for the property that would account for this happening?",
        "Answer": "RESONANCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the wavelength, in meters, of a sound wave that has a frequency of 600 hertz and a speed in a certain medium of 360 meters per second?",
        "Answer": "0.6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The area under the curve of a velocity versus time graph represents:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "acceleration",
            "X": "velocity",
            "Y": "displacement",
            "Z": "position"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "a spring scale can be used to indirectly measure acceleration",
            "X": "momentum is a vector",
            "Y": "impulse is a vector",
            "Z": "a change in direction of an object\u00d5s motion cannot affect its momentum"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the mass, in kilograms, of a 5-kilogram rock on a planet with a gravitational acceleration one-half that of the Earth\u00d5s?",
        "Answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the specific gravity, to the first decimal place, of a cubic foot of metal that has a density of 188 pounds per cubic foot if water has a density of 62.4 pounds per cubic foot?",
        "Answer": "3.0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "For a given time interval, when is the average velocity of an object equal to the instantaneous velocity for every time in the interval:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "never",
            "X": "always",
            "Y": "only when the velocity is changing at a constant rate",
            "Z": "only when the velocity is constant"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a tug-of-war, each person on a team pulls with an average force of 500 newtons.  What is the tension in the center of the rope if there are 10-man teams on each side:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0 newtons",
            "X": "2,500 newtons",
            "Y": "5,000 newtons",
            "Z": "10,000 newtons"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which one of the following 5 colors of light has the LEAST angle of refraction in normal glass:  blue;  green;  orange;  yellow;  red",
        "Answer": "RED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "For a standing wave on a guitar string, the first overtone represents what harmonic?",
        "Answer": "SECOND"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "At normal operating speed for a motor vehicle, how many times as much kinetic energy does a car have if its velocity is doubled?",
        "Answer": "4 TIMES"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Relative to the floor, what is the gravitational potential energy, in joules, of a 25-newton bag of beans on a shelf 5 meters above the floor?",
        "Answer": "125"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What color of light is produced when equal intensities of cyan light and red light are combined?",
        "Answer": "WHITE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the resistance, in ohms, for an electric stove that draws 24 amps on a 240-volt circuit?",
        "Answer": "10"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following colors of light would give the highest resolving power of a compound light microscope:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "infrared",
            "X": "orange",
            "Y": "green",
            "Z": "ultraviolet"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If  Jim expends 200 watts of power to vertically lift a 200-newton rock 3 meters high, how many seconds did it take him to lift the boulder?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a composite material:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "bone",
            "X": "plywood",
            "Y": "wood",
            "Z": "mild steel"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If  a 5,000-pound elephant is on one end of a plank at a distance of 5 feet from the pivot point and a 200-pound man is on the other end at a distance of 15 feet from the pivot, what will the available torque be, in foot-pounds, at the pivot while the plank is in motion?",
        "Answer": "22,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In an application where ductility is required, which of the following materials would be your BEST choice:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "grey cast iron",
            "X": "copper",
            "Y": "granite",
            "Z": "1040 steel"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT correct:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "percent elongation compared to the known value for a material is sometimes used to detect impurities in metal",
            "X": "the modulus of elasticity for a material is derived from its stress-strain curve",
            "Y": "ductile materials usually fail with little or no plastic deformation",
            "Z": "a steel sample that is loaded beyond its elastic limit will not return to its original shape when the load is removed"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following have largely replaced vacuum tubes that were used in electronics of the mid to later 20th century:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "capacitors",
            "X": "transformers",
            "Y": "transistors",
            "Z": "amplifiers"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true of uranium:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "it is very dense",
            "X": "all isotopes are radioactive",
            "Y": "uranium is sometimes used in counterweights in yacht keels",
            "Z": "there are only 3 isotopes of uranium"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the resulting electrical potential, in volts, when a charge of 12 coulombs is applied to a 1 farad capacitor?",
        "Answer": "12"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the magnetic field associated with the current on a straight long wire is inversely proportional to the distance from the wire",
            "X": "Kirchhoff\u00d5s first rule has to do with the accounting of total charges entering and leaving a junction per unit time",
            "Y": "superconducting quantum interference devices, or SQUID\u00d5s, are based on the Josephson Effect",
            "Z": "resistance and voltage are the two most common parameters used to characterize a resistor"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the strongest spectral line in the visible region of the hydrogen spectrum:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "red Balmer line",
            "X": "orange Lyman line",
            "Y": "green Paschen line",
            "Z": "blue Brackett line"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following has the highest vapor pressure at standard temperature and pressure:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "mercury",
            "X": "ethyl alcohol",
            "Y": "methyl alcohol",
            "Z": "acetone"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If 1000 pounds is applied to a spring with spring constant of 100 pounds per inch on top of a hydraulic piston, how many pounds of force is transferred to the piston:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1,000",
            "X": "900",
            "Y": "100",
            "Z": "zero"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If the atomic mass of carbon-12 is exactly 12 atomic mass units, why is the atomic mass of carbon not exactly 12 when listed on the Periodic Table:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the mass deficit",
            "X": "neutrons are not the same mass as protons",
            "Y": "it adds the mass of the electrons",
            "Z": "the presence in nature of about 1.1% carbon-13"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many nodes are there in the first overtone in a standing wave of a vibrating guitar string?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If g = 9.8 meters per second squared, to the first decimal place and in newtons, how many newtons of force are required to keep a 500 kilogram slab of granite moving across a horizontal surface at constant speed if there is a kinetic frictional coefficient of 0.10 between the surface and the slab?",
        "Answer": "490"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Astrophysicists, when referring to interstellar gases, typically use the Roman numeral I to indicate that an atom is:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "singly ionized",
            "X": "doubly ionized",
            "Y": "contains one proton",
            "Z": "neutral"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A draft horse has a hoof print of 50 square inches per hoof.  If the horse weighs 1,400 pounds, what is the pressure it exerts, in pounds per square inch, on the ground when all its hooves equally distribute its weight on the ground?",
        "Answer": "7"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Huygen\u00d5s principle can be used to most directly derive which of the following:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the speed of light",
            "X": "the law of diffraction",
            "Y": "the laws of reflection and refraction",
            "Z": "Fermat\u00d5s Principle"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When utilizing dissimilar metals in a device that operates over a large temperature range, which of the following factors is most important to consider in determining internal stresses:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "ductility",
            "X": "hardenability",
            "Y": "conductivity",
            "Z": "coefficients of thermal expansion"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many times as intense is 60 decibels than 30 decibels?",
        "Answer": "1,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the minimal force, in newtons to the first decimal place, that a mother must exert to vertically lift her 4 kilogram baby out of her play pen?",
        "Answer": "39.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In response to the development of incandescent lights, gas lights were vastly improved by soaking the mantles in what substance to help convert heat and UV energy into visible light:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "thorium oxide",
            "X": "titanium dioxide",
            "Y": "uranium oxide",
            "Z": "tungsten"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A hunter uses a 30-gram arrow that is fired by a bowstring at a velocity of 56 meters per second.  What is the impulse on the arrow, to the second decimal place in kilogram meters per second?",
        "Answer": "1.68"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the BEST expression of the speed of sound waves in various media:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the product of the elastic property times the inertial property",
            "X": "the value of the inertial property divided by the elastic property",
            "Y": "the value of the elastic property divided by the inertial property",
            "Z": "the square root of the elastic property divided by the inertial property"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a mandolin string is tuned to 880 hertz and is 28-centimeters long, what is the wavelength, in meters rounded to the second decimal place, of the sound wave produced by this string, assuming that the instrument is at 20\u00bcC and that the speed of sound is 343 meters/second?",
        "Answer": "0.39"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The index of refraction for a medium is:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the ratio of the angles of refraction of red light and blue light in the medium",
            "X": "the angle of refraction for monochromatic light in the medium",
            "Y": "the ratio of the speed of light in the medium to the speed of light in a vacuum",
            "Z": "the ratio of the speed of light in a vacuum to the speed of light in the medium"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If light of a single wavelength of 600 nanometers moves from air into a medium with a refractive index of 1.25, what is the wavelength, in nanometers, of the light as it travels in the denser medium?",
        "Answer": "480"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many 20-ohm resistors connected in parallel will produce 5 ohms of equivalent resistance?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assuming g = 10 meters per second squared, how many total newtons of thrust are needed to accelerate a 5,000-kilogram rocket vertically at 6 meters per second squared?",
        "Answer": "80,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many watts are equivalent to 1 joule of energy expended per minute of time?",
        "Answer": "1/60"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Michael, who has a mass of 100 kilograms, tries to ski jump with a velocity of 15 meters per second.  What is Michael\u00d5s momentum, in proper SI units, as he leaves the ski jump?",
        "Answer": "1500 KILOGRAM METERS PER SECOND"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Resonance in a musical instrument is MOST directly exemplified by:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "sympathetic harmonic vibration",
            "X": "destructive interference",
            "Y": "dissonance in the standing wave",
            "Z": "diffraction"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The specific heat of a certain metal is 0.750 joules per gram kelvin.  How much heat, in joules to the nearest whole number, will it take to increase the temperature of  0.50 kilograms of the metal from 25\u00bcC to 50\u00bcC?",
        "Answer": "9,375"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the acceleration, in meters per second squared, of a  10-kilogram snow sled that is on a frictionless horizontal surface if a horizontal force of 500 newtons is applied to it?",
        "Answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the speed of light in meters per second for monochromatic light of 780 nanometers in glass with a refractive index of 1.55:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1.5 % 108",
            "X": "1.9 % 108",
            "Y": "4.65 % 107",
            "Z": "4.65 % 108"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is generally NOT true regarding diffraction of light:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "when white light is passed through a diffraction grating, shorter wavelengths are diffracted the most",
            "X": "diffraction is wavelength dependent",
            "Y": "if laser light is passed through a diffraction grating it will produce an interference pattern as a series of dots on a screen",
            "Z": "white light passing through a diffraction grating is spread into a rainbow of colors"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 300-newton box is placed on an inclined plane that makes a 45\u00bc angle with the horizontal.  Find the component of the box\u00d5s weight parallel to the plane\u00d5s surface, in newtons to the nearest whole number:",
        "Answer": "212"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The lens-maker\u00d5s equation relates the focal length of a glass lens to the radii of curvature of the lens\u00d5s two surfaces and what other property of the lens?",
        "Answer": "INDEX OF REFRACTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Green light has a wavelength of 500 nanometers.  What is its associated frequency, in hertz?",
        "Answer": "6 % 1014"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a particle moves from a position of x = 5 meters out to x = 200 meters and back again to x = 5 meters, what is its displacement in meters?",
        "Answer": "0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the two features of displacement?",
        "Answer": "MAGNITUDE AND DIRECTION  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following choices is NOT an example of a rigid body?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Slinky",
            "X": "Wheel",
            "Y": "Pool ball",
            "Z": "CD"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which of the following are transmitted by electromagnetic waves: 1) radio, 2) television, 3) Rayleigh, or 4) P-waves?",
        "Answer": "RADIO, TELEVISION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a car is accelerating along a road, the force acting on the car that causes it to move forward is the reaction force from the car pushing on the ground. What is this reaction force due to?",
        "Answer": "FRICTION BETWEEN THE TIRE AND THE GROUND"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a car is accelerating along a road, what force due to the air does the frictional force have to oppose?",
        "Answer": "DRAG"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the two forms of electrical current?",
        "Answer": "ALTERNATING AND DIRECT CURRENT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the most common method of producing alternating current?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Circuits varying from parallel to series",
            "X": "Switches automatically turning on and off",
            "Y": "Turbines rotating backwards and forwards",
            "Z": "Magnets spinning in a coil of wire"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "How can 2 batteries and three capacitors be arranged to store the maximum amount of energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Connect the capacitors in parallel and the batteries in series",
            "X": "Connect the capacitors in series and the batteries in parallel",
            "Y": "Connect the capacitors and batteries in parallel",
            "Z": "Connect the capacitors and batteries in series"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What would be the total capacitance in microfarads and total voltage of 3 four-microfarad capacitors in parallel and two 1.5 volt batteries in series in a circuit?",
        "Answer": "12 MICROFARADS AND 3 VOLTS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "During a safety test, a small car and a truck move toward each other at the same speed and experience a head-on collision. Afterward, the two objects move away from each other along the same line. Which of the following is correct?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The truck will experience a greater speed than the car",
            "X": "The car will experience a greater speed than the truck",
            "Y": "The speeds of the truck and the car will be the same",
            "Z": "Sometimes the truck will experience a greater speed and sometimes the car will experience the greater speed"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Mercury or other liquid barometers work by balancing the force exerted by the atmosphere with what?",
        "Answer": "FORCE EXERTED BY THE LIQUID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Mirages, such as the silvery glimmer you sometimes see on a distant hot highway, are caused by heating of the air near the ground. What relevant property of the heated air is changed?",
        "Answer": "INDEX OF REFRACTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A steadily increasing force is applied to a box that remains at rest for some period of time and then begins to accelerate. Which of the following appropriately describes what happens to the frictional force during the experiment?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The frictional force remains constant throughout the experiment",
            "X": "The frictional force increases throughout the experiment",
            "Y": "The frictional force increases and then suddenly drops to a lower, non-zero value",
            "Z": "The frictional force increases and then suddenly drops to zero"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the total resistance, in ohms, of two resistors in parallel when both are 10 ohm resistors?",
        "Answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If the circuit breaker in a 110-volt circuit is listed at 30 amperes, how many 100 watt light bulbs could you have on that circuit, which includes a TV with 250 watts, a hair dryer of 1500 watts and a computer of 150 watts?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10",
            "X": "14",
            "Y": "18",
            "Z": "20"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is closest to the radius of a hydrogen nucleus:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1 micrometer",
            "X": "1 angstrom",
            "Y": "1 picometer",
            "Z": "1 femtometer"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider a planet where g equals 5.0 meters per second squared.  Ignoring friction, if an object started from rest, how far would it fall vertically off a cliff in 4.0 seconds, giving your answer in standard SI units?",
        "Answer": "40 METERS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "During positron emission, which of the following most likely occurs:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "a proton changes to an electron",
            "X": "a proton changes to a neutron",
            "Y": "a neutron changes to an electron",
            "Z": "a neutron changes to a proton"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following 4 isotopes that release energy if they undergo fission:  helium-4;  hydrogen-2;  uranium-235;  iron-56",
        "Answer": "URANIUM-235"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "As opposed to spontaneous emission, what is the type of emission, first theorized by Albert Einstein, where a photon interacts with an atom\u2122s electron which, when it returns to a ground state, emits a coherent photon?",
        "Answer": "STIMULATED EMISSION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Order the following 4 choices from the one with the LOWEST temperature to the one with the HIGHEST temperature:   copper freezes;  water boils;  solar corona;  lead melts",
        "Answer": "WATER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the three metals that generally comprise ferromagnetic materials?",
        "Answer": "IRON, COBALT AND NICKEL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many turns of wire should a solenoid have if you wish the magnetic field inside the solenoid to be 5 times as great as that of a solenoid with 100 turns of wire, if both have the same length and current?",
        "Answer": "500"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the acceleration of a falling body in meters per second squared after it reaches terminal velocity?",
        "Answer": "0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An object is dropped from an office window. The amount of air resistance is unknown. After 1 second of falling, which of the following cannot be true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The velocity is 1 meter per second",
            "X": "The velocity is 11 meters per second",
            "Y": "The acceleration is 0 meters per second squared",
            "Z": "The acceleration is 5 meters per second squared"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In an alternating electric current, what is the term most commonly used to describe the tendency of charged particles to travel along the surface of their conductor?",
        "Answer": "SKIN EFFECT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A transformer is often used in electric circuits to alter what quantity?",
        "Answer": "VOLTAGE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What term describes momentum transfer from a photon to a physical object ?",
        "Answer": "RADIATION PRESSURE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Nuclear reactions, such as those that occur in power generating reactors, are said to be critical when:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They are able to sustain their level of activity without an external neutron source",
            "X": "They have been shut down by the introduction of neutron poisons such as boron",
            "Y": "They are increasing in power at a rate faster than expected",
            "Z": "They are producing more thorium than uranium"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following does a Carnot engine convert?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Energy to heat",
            "X": "Pressure to volume",
            "Y": "Heat to work",
            "Z": "Work to pressure"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A heat engine operates with 60 kilocalories of heat supplied, and exhausts 40 kilocalories of heat. How much work, in joules, did the engine do? Provide your answer to the nearest thousand.",
        "Answer": "84,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Careful measurements have shown that the mass of a particular atom is always slightly less than the sum of the masses of the individual neutrons, protons, and electrons of which the atom consists. What is the difference between the mass of the atom and the sum of the masses of its parts called?",
        "Answer": "MASS DEFECT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 62 kilogram boy on a 1.50 kilogram skateboard moving at 1.2 meters per second steps off and lands on the sidewalk with a velocity of 1.1 meters per second. Providing your answer as a decimal rounded to the nearest tenth, how fast is the skateboard moving in meters per second?",
        "Answer": "5.3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following explains why extremely high energy is needed for fusion to work?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "To break the nuclei into two parts",
            "X": "To bind the protons and electrons",
            "Y": "To overcome the electrical repulsion between two positively charged nuclei",
            "Z": "To create the necessary supercold environment"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The temperature in the region of the Sun where fusion occurs is about how many degrees Fahrenheit?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1,000",
            "X": "50,000",
            "Y": "7,800,000",
            "Z": "27,000,000"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An electron-volt is the:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Energy gained by 1 electron falling through a 1 meter vertical distance",
            "X": "Energy of a visible light photon",
            "Y": "Energy of 1 electron accelerated through a 1 volt potential difference",
            "Z": "Energy of a typical electron orbiting a nucleus"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the world\u00d5s largest and highest energy particle accelerator, designed to collide proton beams at 7 teraelectron volts?",
        "Answer": "LARGE HADRON COLLIDER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If two sine waves are played with frequencies of 400 and 410 Hertz, at what frequency in Hertz will you perceive that their volumes are \u00d2pulsing\u00d3?",
        "Answer": "10"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If the fundamental frequency of a pipe open at both ends is 70 Hertz, what will its next two harmonics be in Hertz?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "105 and 140",
            "X": "140 and 210",
            "Y": "210 and 350",
            "Z": "210 and 420"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In determining the escape velocity of an object on Earth, which of the following values is generally least important?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The mass of the object",
            "X": "The volume of the object",
            "Y": "The radius of Earth",
            "Z": "The mass of Earth"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A spherical Gaussian surface encloses two point charges, q1 and q2, while a third point charge, q3, is placed outside the Gaussian surface.  The electrical field on the Gaussian surface is due to which of the charges?",
        "Answer": "q1, q2, AND q3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assuming that the light bulbs, wires, and batteries are all the same in two different circuits, how would the brightness of two light bulbs in series compare to the brightness of just one light bulb?",
        "Answer": "DIMMER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What will the power loss be in watts in a 100,000 volt transmission line carrying 10 amperes of current if the resistance of the line is 20 ohms?",
        "Answer": "2000  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When the path difference between two slits is an odd multiple of the light\u00d5s wavelength divided by 2, the waves arrive 180 degrees out of phase. What kind of interference does this represent?",
        "Answer": "DESTRUCTIVE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A beam of white light is incident on a triangular glass prism with an index of refraction of 1.5 for visible light, producing a spectrum. Initially, the prism is in a glass aquarium filled with air. If the aquarium is filled with water with an index of refraction of 1.3, which of the following is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The spectrum produced has the deviation of the beam opposite to that in air",
            "X": "The positions of red and violet are reversed in the spectrum",
            "Y": "The spectrum produced has greater separation between red and violet than that produced in air",
            "Z": "The spectrum produced has lesser separation between red and violet than that produced in air"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If Tajon applies 100 newtons of force on a 2-meter wrench at a right angle to the wrench and parallel to the plane of rotation, how much torque, in newton meters, is he applying to the bolt?",
        "Answer": "200"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What makes arches and domes more stable than flat roofed structures?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They transmit compressive forces along their length to the ground, uniformly bearing the load of gravity",
            "X": "Each section is under great tension, using the stronger dimension of the components",
            "Y": "Torsional resistance to sideways swaying ensures that such structures are stable, even in high winds",
            "Z": "The surface tension of the arched shape allows the building components to be hollowed out, saving weight."
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following has NOT been proposed as a way to test string theory?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Cosmic ray experiments",
            "X": "High energy particle collisions",
            "Y": "Electron mapping",
            "Z": "Precision tests of short-range gravitational forces"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A jet engine gets its thrust by taking in air, heating and compressing it and then ejecting it at a high speed. If a particular engine takes in 20 kilograms of air per second at 100 meters per second, and ejects it at 500 meters per second, what is the thrust of the engine in newtons?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "760",
            "X": "8000",
            "Y": "9100",
            "Z": "10,500"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A car of mass 700 kilograms travels at 20 meters per second and collides with a stationary truck of mass 1400 kilograms. The two vehicles interlock as a result of the collision and slide along an icy road. Which of the following is the approximate velocity in meters per second of the combined system?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "5.6",
            "X": "6.6",
            "Y": "7.6",
            "Z": "8.6"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is one way in which power can be calculated?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Subtracting the relative vectors F and v",
            "X": "The time derivative of work performed",
            "Y": "The strength of the force times g",
            "Z": "The second derivative of acceleration"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a wild shot, Guido flings a pool ball of mass m off a 0.68 meter high pool table with downward spin, and the ball hits the floor with a vertical speed of 6.0 meters per second. How fast was the ball moving vertically in meters per second when it left the pool table?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "6.7",
            "X": "5.7",
            "Y": "4.7",
            "Z": "3.7"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a totally inelastic collision, what happens to the two colliding objects?",
        "Answer": "THEY STICK"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "For a uniformly rotating object, what do we call the rate of change in the angle through which the object turns in one second?",
        "Answer": "ANGULAR VELOCITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If a solid cylinder and a hollow cylinder have the same outer radius and mass, which of the following is true regarding moment of inertia about the cylindrical axis?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The hollow cylinder has a greater moment of inertia",
            "X": "The solid cylinder has a greater moment of inertia",
            "Y": "The moment of inertia would be the same for both",
            "Z": "The moment of inertia depends on the speed of the cylinders"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Many physics quantities fall under two categories: scalars and vectors. Which of the following does NOT contain a scalar quantity?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Force, energy, mass",
            "X": "Velocity, pressure, time",
            "Y": "Weight, speed, work",
            "Z": "Acceleration, momentum, displacement"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two sounds of the same intensity will be perceived by the human ear to have the same loudness if:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The two sounds have the same pitch",
            "X": "The two sounds have the same pitch and the same timbre",
            "Y": "The two sounds have the same timbre",
            "Z": "The two sounds are below 100 Hertz"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "While waterskiing behind her uncle\u00d5s boat, Michelle is pulled at a constant speed with a force of 164 newtons by a rope that is nearly horizontal. If Michelle has a mass of 65 kilograms, what is the coefficient of sliding friction between Michelle and the water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.05",
            "X": "0.18",
            "Y": "0.26",
            "Z": "0.40"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In 1999, NASA lost a $125 million Mars orbiter because:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The atmosphere on Mars was so corrosive that the orbiter was destroyed",
            "X": "The engine did not fire",
            "Y": "The robotic arm jilted it out of orbit",
            "Z": "Lockheed Martin engineers used English units of measurement and NASA used the metric system"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Arturo, whose mass is 45 kilograms, is riding his 5.0 kilogram skateboard down the sidewalk with a constant speed of 6.0 meters per second when he rolls across a 10.0 meter long patch of sand on the pavement. The sand provides a force of friction of 6.0 newtons. What is Arturo\u00d5s speed in meters per second as he emerges from the sand?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0",
            "X": "1.8",
            "Y": "3.8",
            "Z": "5.8"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST explains how a radium isotope with a half-life of about 1,600 years can be found in the crust of the Earth that was formed millions of years ago:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "its decay is slowed by the pressure of the Earth",
            "X": "the radium is replenished by decay of longer lived radioactive elements",
            "Y": "the radium was replenished by meteors and asteroids over the millennia",
            "Z": "the radium is recycled from the Earth\u2122s core where magnetic fields slow the decay"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is probably the most significant limitation for PET scans being used in remote rural hospital sites:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "lack of properly trained personnel",
            "X": "the proximity to production facilities for short-lived radioisotopes",
            "Y": "the high level of radiation requiring special training and increased radiation risk",
            "Z": "difficulty in PET radiotracers binding to receptors when imaging certain human tissues"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes how one would compute the speed for a sound wave through a liquid:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the square of the density of liquid divided by its bulk modulus",
            "X": "the square of the bulk modulus of the liquid divided by its density",
            "Y": "the square root of the density of liquid divided by its bulk modulus",
            "Z": "the square root of the bulk modulus of the liquid divided by its density"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all the leptons that are produced during beta minus decay?",
        "Answer": "ELECTRONS AND ANTINEUTRINOS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What boson is the only particle predicted by the Standard Model of Particle Physics that had not yet been observed as of June 2008?",
        "Answer": "HIGGS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Through what two particles is most of the energy released by a star like our Sun?",
        "Answer": "PHOTONS AND NEUTRINOS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What causes low-pressure weather systems, such as tropical cyclones, to spin counter-clockwise in the Northern Hemisphere and clockwise in the Southern Hemisphere?",
        "Answer": "CORIOLIS EFFECT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Billions of tiny ice crystals rub together to produce electron imbalances within storm clouds. What do we see when electrons arc to another cloud or to the ground?",
        "Answer": "LIGHTNING"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term that describes the separation of visible light into its component colors by a prism?",
        "Answer": "DISPERSION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following colors of light has the most energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Yellow",
            "X": "Red",
            "Y": "Green",
            "Z": "Violet"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A child is holding a string with a yo-yo dangling at the bottom of it. As the child yanks the string up, the tension in the string will:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Decrease",
            "X": "Increase",
            "Y": "Stay the same",
            "Z": "Become negative"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When a girl wearing roller blades throws a ball in front of her, she slides backwards. Her movement is an illustration of which of Newton\u00d5s Laws of Motion?",
        "Answer": "THIRD"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer to the nearest degree, what is absolute zero in degrees Celsius?",
        "Answer": "-273 DEGREES CELSIUS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When air in a closed system is heated, what does it do?",
        "Answer": "EXPANDS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A rock is dropped from a building, and a second rock is dropped one second later.  Ignoring air resistance, what happens to the distance between the two rocks over time until one lands?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The distance between them will depend on the masses of the rocks",
            "X": "The distance between them will decrease",
            "Y": "The distance between them will stay the same",
            "Z": "The distance between them will increase"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When the drag force acting on a skydiver and the force of gravity are equal, how can you characterize his or her velocity?",
        "Answer": "TERMINAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which one of the following terms is used to indicate the natural tendency of an object to remain at rest or in motion at a constant speed along a straight line?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Equilibrium",
            "X": "Inertia (read as: i-NEHR-shah)",
            "Y": "Stability",
            "Z": "Interaction"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What are the two kinds of motion displayed by the motion of a bowling ball?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Oscillatory and rotational",
            "X": "Periodic and translational",
            "Y": "Translational and rotational",
            "Z": "Random and periodic"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How does the center of mass of an object change when going from a 1 g to a 0 g environment?",
        "Answer": "IT DOES NOT CHANGE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The acceleration of two different masses connected by a light string suspended by a light frictionless pulley is:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Less than 9.8 meters per second squared",
            "X": "Greater than 9.8 meters per second squared",
            "Y": "Equal to 9.8 meters per second squared",
            "Z": "0"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the term for the rate at which an object\u00d5s velocity changes with time?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Instantaneous velocity",
            "X": "Motion",
            "Y": "Speed",
            "Z": "Acceleration"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In 1901, 63-year-old retired schoolteacher Annie Edson Taylor went over the Niagara Falls in a barrel. The Horseshoe Falls have a height of about 51 meters. Using 9.8 meters per second squared as the acceleration due to gravity; about how long in seconds did it take for her to reach the water surface? Assume that her initial velocity was zero, and neglect the effect of the air on the barrel during the fall.",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Between 3 and 4 seconds",
            "X": "Between 5 and 6 seconds",
            "Y": "Between 10 and 11 seconds",
            "Z": "Between 27 and 28 seconds"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the most common instrument used for measuring gas pressure:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "manometer",
            "X": "anemometer",
            "Y": "tensitometer",
            "Z": "flow-meter"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is TRUE of a sound wave traveling in dry air at STP at a constant velocity:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "if frequency increases, wavelength increases",
            "X": "if frequency increases, wavelength decreases",
            "Y": "if frequency decreases, wavelength decreases",
            "Z": "if frequency increases, wavelength stays the same"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many neutrons does the most common isotope of hydrogen have?",
        "Answer": "ZERO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many neutrons and how many protons are present in a single oxygen-15 nucleus, respectively?",
        "Answer": "NEUTRONS = 7;  PROTONS = 8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Jan is riding her bike northward on Main Street at 20 kilometers per hour and applies her brakes.  In what direction would a physicist MOST likely record her acceleration?",
        "Answer": "SOUTH"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If 200 coulombs pass through a wire in 0.5 seconds, what is the average current, in amps, passing through the wire?",
        "Answer": "400"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When we measure the distance traveled by an object moving from one point to another, which of the following is always true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Magnitude of displacement is greater than or equal to distance",
            "X": "Magnitude of displacement equals distance",
            "Y": "Magnitude of displacement is greater than distance",
            "Z": "Magnitude of displacement is less than or equal to distance"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Jos\u201d and Rosie were spelunking in the caves in the Black Hills of South Dakota. They crawled through a multitude of passages, traveling a net 3 kilometers westward, 4 kilometers south, and 50 meters up. What was magnitude of their overall displacement to the nearest kilometer?",
        "Answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The Lorentz force acting on a particle moving in electric and magnetic fields depends on what two characteristics of the particle?",
        "Answer": "CHARGE AND VELOCITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The interior light in a car is left on for three hours. The light draws 1 ampere from the battery. How many coulombs flowed through the light?",
        "Answer": "10,800"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Lynne is standing still on a sidewalk. What is the name of the concept which describes why the siren of an approaching fire truck has a higher frequency than that of a fire truck that is stopped?",
        "Answer": "DOPPLER SHIFT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which theory attempts to unify physics by producing all known forces and particles as different vibrations of a single substance?",
        "Answer": "STRING THEORY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the process by which nuclear fission produces energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Combining lighter nuclei into heavier nuclei",
            "X": "Increasing the number of protons a nucleus contains",
            "Y": "Changing an electron's spin state following excitation",
            "Z": "Splitting heavier nuclei into lighter nuclei"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a challenge in using nuclear fusion as a controlled generator of power?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The fuels needed for fusion reactions are expensive and difficult to find",
            "X": "Containing the reaction once it has started is difficult",
            "Y": "Materials used to contain fusion reactions are affected by the high radiation levels",
            "Z": "Extremely high temperatures are needed to start the reaction"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following most commonly functions to limit current to one direction:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "capacitor",
            "X": "transformer",
            "Y": "resistor",
            "Z": "diode"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Debbie pushes a 10-kilogram box of books with a horizontal force of 500 newtons.  What is the acceleration of the box, giving your answer in standard SI units, if friction is neglected?",
        "Answer": "50 METERS PER SECOND SQUARED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the device in a galvanic cell that completes the electric circuit by connecting the two sides of the cell with an inert electrolyte:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "electrolytic reservoir",
            "X": "cathode",
            "Y": "conducting wire",
            "Z": "salt bridge"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many joules are in a single watt-hour?",
        "Answer": "3,600"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Radon is primarily produced naturally on Earth most directly from the decay of what element?",
        "Answer": "RADIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By words or numbers, name all of the following 4 choices that are TRUE for an object moving at a constant speed:  1) it must have a constant velocity  2) it must be constantly moving in the same direction  3) it can be accelerating  4) it must have a constant weight",
        "Answer": "3) IT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the electric charge and mass of the carrier particle for the electromagnetic force?",
        "Answer": ""
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the intensity of a sound is 10,000 times as loud as another sound, by how many decibels do the two sounds differ?",
        "Answer": "40"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The mass of a raindrop is 4 milligrams. Which of the following represents the correct mass in grams of the raindrop?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "4 \" 10-3",
            "X": "4 \" 10-1",
            "Y": "4 \" 103",
            "Z": "4 \" 106"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A freely falling object has a constant acceleration of 9.8 meters per second squared. Which of the following is correct?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The object\u00d5s displacement changes by 9.8 meters every second squared",
            "X": "The object\u00d5s acceleration increases by 9.8 meters per second squared each second",
            "Y": "The object travels 9.8 meters each second",
            "Z": "The object\u00d5s speed increases by 9.8 meters per second each second"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A poorly designed fishing bob does not float in a sucrose solution. Which of the following actions could be taken so the fishing bob would float?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Increase the volume of the solution",
            "X": "Decrease the volume of the solution",
            "Y": "Increase the concentration of the solution",
            "Z": "Decrease the concentration of the solution"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Water tank A has width W1 and tank B has width W2, where W1 > W2. The two water tanks are the same height, H.  If both tanks are completely filled with water, which of the following is true about the water pressure at the bottom of the tank?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Pressure cannot be determined",
            "X": "The pressure is greater in tank A",
            "Y": "The pressure is greater in tank B",
            "Z": "Both tanks have the same pressure"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following describes an electromagnet?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Straight wire carrying a current",
            "X": "Current-carrying wire wrapped around a core",
            "Y": "Permanent bar magnet",
            "Z": "Rock that is iron attracting"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A voltage difference of 10 volts delivers how much power, in watts, to a 1-ohm resistor?",
        "Answer": "100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What type of collision occurs when two objects collide and stick together?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Partially elastic",
            "X": "Perfectly elastic",
            "Y": "Partially inelastic",
            "Z": "Perfectly inelastic"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "For all collisions, all of the following properties are conserved except:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Total mass",
            "X": "Center of mass",
            "Y": "Kinetic energy",
            "Z": "Momentum"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the ideal mechanical advantage of a 24 inch lever if the fulcrum is located 6 inches from the resistance, which is at one end of the lever?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the mechanical advantage of a screw with a radius of 1 centimeter and a thread of 0.25 centimeters? Provide your answer to the nearest integer.",
        "Answer": "25"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which one of the following statements concerning permanent bar magnets is NOT true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The north pole of a permanent magnet is attracted to a south pole of another magnet",
            "X": "The direction of a magnetic field is indicated by the north pole of a compass",
            "Y": "All permanent magnets are surrounded by a magnetic field",
            "Z": "When a permanent magnet is cut in half, one piece will be a north pole and one a south pole"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The force exerted by a coiled spring is directly proportional to which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Uncoiled length of the spring",
            "X": "Diameter of the string",
            "Y": "Thickness of the string",
            "Z": "Extension of the string"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A truck starts from rest. After 4 seconds of constant acceleration, its instantaneous speed is 8 meters per second. What is the average speed in meters per second over the first four seconds?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The Leidenfrost effect is what causes water to \"skitter\" across a hot surface such as a pan and can permit a droplet to persist for longer on the hot surface at higher temperatures. On what is the water floating?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A cushion of superheated air",
            "X": "An insulating layer of steam",
            "Y": "An insulating piece of the surface it sublimed",
            "Z": "A transitory cold zone"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If a soldier wants to shoot a projectile as far into enemy territory as possible over level ground, at what angle from the ground should the projectile be shot?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0\u00a1",
            "X": "30\u00a1",
            "Y": "45\u00a1",
            "Z": "60\u00a1"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A dart is shot from ground level over level ground with a speed of 30 meters per second at an angle of 30\u00a1 above the ground. Assuming no air resistance, what is the vertical speed in meters per second of the dart when it hits the ground?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0",
            "X": "9.8",
            "Y": "15",
            "Z": "30"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A golf cart and a fire truck collide. Which vehicle experiences a greater force in the collision?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Golf cart",
            "X": "Fire truck",
            "Y": "Both vehicles experience the same force",
            "Z": "Depends on the speeds of the vehicles"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Before a light marble and a heavy marble experience a head-on elastic collision, the heavy marble has a much higher speed than the light marble. During the collision, which marble experiences greater acceleration?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The light marble",
            "X": "The heavy marble",
            "Y": "Both experience the same acceleration",
            "Z": "In an elastic collision, neither marble accelerates"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "John has twice the mass of Carl. They jump off a cliff into the water below. Just before the splash:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "John has half as much kinetic energy as Carl",
            "X": "John and Carl have the same kinetic energy",
            "Y": "John has twice as much kinetic energy as Carl",
            "Z": "John has four times as much kinetic energy as Carl"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a safety crash test, a big truck and a small car have a head-on collision. What can we say about total system momentum?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is equal to zero",
            "X": "It is less after the crash than before the crash",
            "Y": "It is the same before and after the crash",
            "Z": "It is more after the crash than before the crash"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the potential difference in volts between two points, located 2 meters apart, in a constant electric field of 1 volt per meter?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When a fighter pilot fires on a plane directly in front of her, the momentum of the fighter pilot and her plane changes in what way?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It increases",
            "X": "It decreases",
            "Y": "It stays the same",
            "Z": "It changes direction"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When the distance travelled and displacement are equal and nonzero for a given object in motion, the object must have travelled:  W) Back and forth X) In a straight line without changing direction Y) In a circle Z) In an ellipse",
        "Answer": "X) IN A STRAIGHT LINE WITHOUT CHANGING DIRECTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "For an object to travel in a circle, it must experience acceleration in what direction?",
        "Answer": ""
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A charged particle moves through an area of space at a constant speed and direction. Which of the following statements is TRUE?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "There is no magnetic field",
            "X": "There could be magnetic and electric fields oriented in the same direction",
            "Y": "There could be magnetic and electric fields oriented perpendicularly to one another",
            "Z": "There could be magnetic and electric fields oriented opposite to one another"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A household appliance runs on 120 volts and has an internal resistance of 100 ohms. Providing your answer to the nearest integer, how much power, in watts, does this appliance use?",
        "Answer": "144 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is TRUE of beta particles?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They have a charge equal and opposite to alpha particles",
            "X": "They are more penetrating than gamma particles of the same energy",
            "Y": "They are common decay products of alpha particles",
            "Z": "They can be electrons or positrons"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The resistance of a certain wire is 10 ohms. What would be the resistance in ohms if the radius of the wire were doubled?",
        "Answer": "2.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given g as 10 meters per second squared, if a ball is tossed upward at an initial velocity of 20 meters per second, what will be its velocity in meters per second at 2.5 seconds?",
        "Answer": "-5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The frequency of light from a laser radiation source is 6 X 1014 hertz. Using 3 X 108 meters per second as the speed of light, what is the wavelength of this light in nanometers?",
        "Answer": "500"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Applying Bernoulli's principle to vortices, where in a vortex should the pressure be highest?",
        "Answer": "CENTER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer as a decimal rounded to the nearest tenth, if a normal force of 1 newton is applied to the end of a fixed cylinder with a radius of 1 meter, what pressure, in pascals, is induced in the cylinder?",
        "Answer": "0.3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An elephant steps on an electrical extension cord that is connected to a lit lamp. Assuming that the lamp remains plugged in and the cord unbroken, which of the following happens to the light intensity coming from the lamp?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It goes out",
            "X": "It becomes dimmer",
            "Y": "It becomes brighter",
            "Z": "It is unchanged"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a fuse can dissipate 600 watts of power without blowing, how much current, in amperes, can it pass at 120 volts without melting?",
        "Answer": "5 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 4-kilogram ball is tossed at 5 meters per second. How fast, in meters per second, must a 1-kilogram ball be thrown to have the same kinetic energy?",
        "Answer": "10"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A jogger is moving at a speed of 4 meters per second. When chased by a big dog, she accelerates at 1 meter per second squared for 4 seconds. How far has she travelled in meters since she started accelerating?",
        "Answer": "24"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If in a 2-piston hydraulic device, a 100-newton force is applied to a piston with an area of 0.01 square meters, what will be the resulting force, in newtons, on a piston with an area of 0.5 square meters?",
        "Answer": "5000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the centripetal acceleration in meters per second squared of a point on a bicycle tire of radius 0.81 meters when the bike is moving at 9 meters per second?",
        "Answer": "100 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many layers of doped silicon are needed to make a transistor?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A thin copper rod 1 meter long has a mass of 0.05 kilograms and is in a magnetic field of 0.10 teslas. Given 10 meters per second squared for g, what is the minimum current in amperes needed in the rod for the magnetic force to cancel the weight of the rod?",
        "Answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "On a game show, contestants spin a large wheel to determine the prize associated with correct answers. How should a contestant apply force to spin the wheel as rapidly as possible?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Tangential to the rim of the wheel",
            "X": "At a 45 degree angle to the rim of the wheel",
            "Y": "Away from the center of the wheel",
            "Z": "Towards the center of the wheel"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Nitrogen molecules of mass 4.65 x 10!26 kilograms are contained in a cube with sides that have an area of 6 x 10!4 square meters. If 5.0 x 1023 molecules collide head on elastically each second with one wall at a speed of 300 meters per second, what is the pressure exerted on the wall to the nearest kilopascal?",
        "Answer": "23"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If gE and gM are the accelerations due to gravity on the surfaces of Earth and the Moon respectively, and if Millikan\u00d5s oil drop experiment could be performed on the two surfaces, the ratio of the electronic charge on the Moon to the electronic charge on the Earth would be which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "gE/gM",
            "X": "1",
            "Y": "gM/gE",
            "Z": "(gM/gE)2"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer in scientific notation with two significant digits, how much energy in joules is required to heat a clay pizza baking stone with mass of 4.8 kilograms and a specific heat of 860 joules per kilogram Kelvin from 25\u00a1 Celsius to 235\u00a1 Celsius?",
        "Answer": "8.7 ! 105"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is TRUE about the electric field just outside the surface of a charged spherical conductor?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is zero",
            "X": "It is infinitely large",
            "Y": "It is directed perpendicularly to the surface",
            "Z": "It is directed parallel to the surface"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A projectile is launched over level ground with a velocity of 100 meters per second at an angle of 30 degrees to the horizontal. Given that the acceleration due to gravity is 10 meters per second squared, what will be the horizontal range of this projectile rounded to the nearest meter?",
        "Answer": "866  _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How much work, in joules, is done on a 2000-kilogram car by applying a 1000-newton force to move it 20 meters?",
        "Answer": "20,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 50-kilogram person in an elevator is moving upward at a velocity of 2 meters per second. Given g as 9.8 meters per second squared, and providing your answer to the nearest ten, how much force, in newtons, is she exerting on the elevator floor?",
        "Answer": "490"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A thermodynamic process that takes place at a constant pressure can be described by what adjective?",
        "Answer": "ISOBARIC"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Using 9.8 meters per second squared for g and expressing your answer in scientific notation to one significant digit, what is the water pressure, in newtons per square meter, at a depth of 2 meters in a swimming pool?",
        "Answer": "2 ! 104"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An electrical field does 6 joules of work on a charged particle, moving it from 1 volts to 3 volts. What is the charge of the particle in coulombs?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given g as 10 meters per second squared and the speed of sound as 331 meters per second, if you dropped a pebble down a well and heard a splash 3 seconds later, approximately how far down, in meters rounded to the nearest ten, was the water?",
        "Answer": "40"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A bucket of hot oil weighing 50 newtons is lifted at constant velocity up a castle wall that is 10 meters high. It takes 20 seconds to raise the bucket up the wall. How much power was used to raise the bucket?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "25 watts",
            "X": "25 joules",
            "Y": "500 joules",
            "Z": "500 watts"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 3.5 ampere current is maintained in a simple circuit with a total resistance of 1500 ohms. In coulombs, what net charge passes through any point in the circuit during a 30-second interval?",
        "Answer": "105 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A monochromatic light source incident on a diffraction grating with slit separation d produces a pattern on the wall. What diffraction slit spacing would be required to produce the same pattern on the wall using light of twice the wavelength?",
        "Answer": "2d"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 10-gram bullet is shot with an initial velocity of 600 meters per second into a 2-kilogram ballistic pendulum and emerges from the pendulum with a speed of 200 meters per second. Given 10 meters per second squared as g, to what height in meters does the pendulum rise?",
        "Answer": "0.2 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider charges +Q and +4Q, separated by 3 meters. At which of the following points on a line between the two charges can a charge \u00d0Q be placed so that it will experience no electrostatic force?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1 meter from +Q",
            "X": "1 meter from +4Q",
            "Y": "0.6 meter from +Q",
            "Z": "0.6 meter from +4Q"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A bucket is filled with water to a depth of 20 centimeters. A layer of oil 30 centimeters thick with a specific gravity of 0.7 is poured on top of the water. Given that 1 atmosphere is 1.01 ! 105 pascals and providing your answer in scientific notation with three significant digits, what is the absolute pressure, in pascals, at the bottom of the container?",
        "Answer": "1.05 ! 105 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A common device used to study extreme forms of matter is the magneto-optical trap. Which of the following explains how the trap works?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It heats magnetically contained matter with lasers",
            "X": "It oscillates matter through dipole interactions",
            "Y": "It uses both magnetic fields and lasers to cool matter",
            "Z": "It magnetically accelerates matter through optical lens systems"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In an experiment, 200 grams of aluminum with a specific heat of 0.91 joules per kilogram Kelvin at 100\u00a1 Celsius is mixed with 50.0 grams of water with a specific heat of 4.2 joules per kilogram Kelvin at 20\u00a1 Celsius. The mixture is thermally isolated. What is the equilibrium temperature in degrees Celsius?",
        "Answer": "57\u00a1 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements BEST describes why protons in the nucleus do NOT fly apart due to coulomb repulsion?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The negative charges of the orbiting electrons neutralize the positive charges of the protons",
            "X": "The coulomb force does not manifest within the nucleus",
            "Y": "Neutrons cancel the coulomb repulsion",
            "Z": "The strong force between quarks dominates"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A coil is wrapped with 200 turns of wire on a square frame with sides of 20 centimeters in length. A uniform magnetic field is applied perpendicular to the plane of the coil. If the field changes uniformly from 0.5 to 0 teslas in 8 seconds, what is the average value, to the nearest tenth volt, of the induced electromotive force?",
        "Answer": "0.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The resistance of a hot tungsten filament is about 10 times the cold resistance. What is the resistance, in ohms, of a 100 watt and 200 volt lamp filament when not in use?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "20",
            "X": "40",
            "Y": "200",
            "Z": "400"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An object is 48 centimeters tall. Its image is 40 centimeters tall, and 15 centimeters away from a mirror. How far, in centimeters, is the object from the mirror?",
        "Answer": "18 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following BEST describes the Balmer series:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "a series of quantum numbers indicating certain energy levels",
            "X": "hydrogen atom spectral line emission",
            "Y": "a sequence of elements that are produced chronologically in supernovae",
            "Z": "the energy spectrum of the early universe"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to the Standard Model of Particle Physics, through what force would the top quark decay?",
        "Answer": "WEAK FORCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following did J. J. Thompson use that primarily led him to conclude that electrons were basic particles of atoms and carried electric charge:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "a compass and batteries",
            "X": "a solenoid",
            "Y": "cathode ray tubes",
            "Z": "electromagnets"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider a satellite that is a uniform sphere rotating about its axis.  What is its moment of inertia, giving your answer in scientific notation and in kilogram meters squared, if it has a mass of 10,000 kilograms and a diameter of 200 meters?",
        "Answer": "4 \u00d7 107"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What was the most sensitive device Coulomb used to measure the electric forces between pith balls?",
        "Answer": ""
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Order the following 3 choices from the MOST penetrating through a thin sheet of cardboard to the LEAST:  beta rays;  alpha rays;  x-rays",
        "Answer": "X-RAYS;  BETA RAYS;  ALPHA RAYS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the phrase that describes the process of producing an electron and a positron when a high-energy photon travels through matter, directly converting radiant energy into matter?",
        "Answer": "PAIR PRODUCTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A living room has floor dimensions of 3.5 meters by 4.2 meters and a height of 2.4 meters. Given air density of 1.2 kilograms per cubic meter, g of 10 meters per second squared, and providing your answer to the nearest ten, what does the air in the room weigh in newtons?",
        "Answer": "420 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The period of revolution of a particle traveling in uniform circular motion is a function of what two variables?",
        "Answer": "VELOCITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "You are asked to determine whether a king\u00d5s crown is really made of gold. You weigh the crown; it weighs 8 newtons in air and 7 newtons in water. Its volume is 0.0001 cubic meters. Given that the density of gold is 19,000 kilograms per cubic meter, the density of lead is 11,000 kilograms per cubic meter, and the density of iron is 8,000 kilograms per cubic meter, the king\u00d5s crown is made of which material?",
        "Answer": "IRON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Neglecting friction, a 33-kilogram cart rolls down a slope that is 20 meters high and 60 meters long. Using 10 meters per second squared for g, what is the velocity in meters per second at the base of the slope?",
        "Answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A long straight wire carries a 10 ampere current north. Give the magnitude in teslas and the direction of the magnetic field induced at a point 10 centimeters directly under the wire?",
        "Answer": "2 x 10!5 WEST"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If the coulomb constant is 9 ! 109 newton meters squared per coulomb squared, what force, in newtons, will two particles with charges of +2 and -2 coulombs kept 2 meters apart exert on each other?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "4.5 ! 109 away from each other",
            "X": "4.5 ! 109 toward each other",
            "Y": "9.0 !!109 toward each other",
            "Z": "1.8 !!1010 toward each other"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Pam buys a pendulum clock at a discount store and discovers when she gets home that it loses 6 minutes each day. If the pendulum has a period of 2 seconds, by how much must the length be changed, to the nearest centimeter, so that the clock keeps accurate time?",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, identify all of the following four situations in which an object is NOT in equilibrium: 1) when moving to the right with a constant velocity; 2) when slowing to a stop; 3) when moving with a constant speed in a circle; 4) when in free fall.",
        "Answer": "2, 3, AND 4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A brass ball with a mass of 200 grams at 20\u00a1 Celsius is placed in boiling water until it reaches equilibrium. Given that the specific heat of brass is 0.094 kilocalories per kilogram degree Celsius, and providing your answer as a decimal to the nearest tenth, how much thermal energy in kilocalories is absorbed by the ball?",
        "Answer": "1.5 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following particles are classified as baryons?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Weak boson",
            "X": "Graviton",
            "Y": "Neutrino",
            "Z": "Neutron"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A food shipper pushes a wooden crate of lettuce with a total mass of 14 kilograms across a concrete floor with a constant horizontal force of magnitude 40 newtons. In a straight-line displacement of magnitude 0.50 meters, the speed of the crate decreases from 0.60 meters per second to 0.20 meters per second. How much work, in joules, is done by the horizontal force?",
        "Answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following best represents a closed system?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A 2-liter bottle filled with aquatic plants, a fish, water, and a bit of air, sealed with a tight lid and placed in a window",
            "X": "A terrarium with a closed lid, some plants, and a live boa constrictor",
            "Y": "The Earth",
            "Z": "The universe"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An electron microscope enables observation of detail on a virus down to 6 nanometers. Given h as 6.6 x 10!34 joule seconds and the mass of the electron as 9.1 x 10!31 kilograms, providing your answer in scientific notation with two significant digits, how fast, in meters per second, must an electron in the microscope be moving to observe detail of this size?",
        "Answer": "1.2 ! 105 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Air resistance is a function of the effective cross sectional area of the body, the drag coefficient, and what other two variables?",
        "Answer": "AIR DENSITY AND VELOCITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 2.0 kilogram possum hangs from a tree limb 5 meters above the ground. Assuming that the gravitational potential energy is zero at y = 0 and that g is 9.8 meters per second squared, what is the gravitational potential energy, to the nearest joule, of the possum-Earth system if we take the reference point y = 0 to be 1.0 meters above the limb?",
        "Answer": "-20"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Assuming negligible air resistance, which of the following statements is TRUE about two-dimensional projectile motion?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The vertical motion is dependent on the horizontal motion",
            "X": "The horizontal motion is dependent on the vertical motion",
            "Y": "The horizontal motion and vertical motion are both dependent on the projectile\u00d5s acceleration vector",
            "Z": "The horizontal motion and vertical motion are independent of each other"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A falling cat reaches a first terminal speed of 100 kilometers per hour while it is tucked in and then stretches out, doubling its effective cross-sectional area without changing its drag coefficient. Providing your answer to the nearest ten, how fast is it falling in meters per second when it reaches a new terminal speed?",
        "Answer": "70 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the most accurate description of charging by induction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It depends on putting two objects in actual physical contact with each other",
            "X": "It depends on the use of friction",
            "Y": "It depends on the use of a ground to redistribute charges",
            "Z": "It depends on gain of electrons during chemical reactions"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer in scientific notation with one significant digit, calculate the de Broglie wavelength, in meters, of a car with a mass of 1600 kilograms traveling at a speed of 40 meters per second.",
        "Answer": "1 ! 10!38 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Turbulent flow is more likely to occur under conditions where Reynolds numbers are high. Under these conditions, what forces are dominant in the system's fluid?",
        "Answer": "INERTIAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 10-meter long cannon is pointed directly up and launches a 1-kilogram cannon ball. The cannon ball is accelerated up the length of the cannon with a constant force of 13.2 newtons due to the explosion. Given g as 10 meters per second squared and assuming no energy loss due to friction, what is the velocity, in meters per second, of the cannon ball as it leaves the cannon?",
        "Answer": "8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If we double the voltage in a simple DC circuit and reduce the resistance by half, what will happen to the value of the current?",
        "Answer": "QUADRUPLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, identify all of the following three choices that are apparent differences between a muon and an electron: 1) mass, 2) electric charge, 3) half life?",
        "Answer": "MASS AND HALF LIFE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the frequency, in megahertz, of a wave of period 2 ! 10!8 seconds?",
        "Answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given that the heat of fusion of water is 80 kilocalories per kilogram and providing your answer as a decimal to the nearest hundredth, what is the change in entropy per kilogram, in kilocalories per Kelvin, when ice at 0\u00a1 Celsius is converted into water at 0\u00a1 Celsius?",
        "Answer": "0.29"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An electron is released in space in an electric field. Which of the following statements is TRUE?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The electron will accelerate at a rate directly proportional to its mass",
            "X": "The electron will move parallel to the equipotential lines",
            "Y": "The field will do work on the particle",
            "Z": "The electron will move from positive to negative potential"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A planet orbits a star in an elliptical orbit. When the planet is furthest from the star, which of the following statements is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The angular momentum of the planet is at a maximum",
            "X": "The angular momentum of the planet is at a minimum",
            "Y": "The kinetic energy of the planet is at a minimum",
            "Z": "The kinetic energy of the planet is at a maximum"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A train moving at 35 meters per second emits a whistle with a frequency of 900 hertz. Assuming that the speed of sound in air is 350 meters per second, what is the frequency, in hertz, measured by a stationary observer in front of the train?",
        "Answer": "1000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A particle that is constrained to travel in one dimension moves in simple harmonic motion about the origin with an amplitude of 5 meters and a period of 2 seconds. Providing your answer in terms of !, what is the maximum acceleration experienced by the particle in meters per second squared?",
        "Answer": "5!2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In 15 seconds, 2 ! 1013 protons pass a particular point. Given that the charge on the proton is 1.6 !!10-19 coulombs, and providing your answer as a decimal to the nearest tenth, what is the current in microamperes?",
        "Answer": "0.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the average force, in newtons, exerted on a 25-gram egg by a bed-sheet if the egg hits the sheet at 4 meters per second and takes 0.2 seconds to stop?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.5",
            "X": "1.5",
            "Y": "5",
            "Z": "50"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following represents one advantage of an electromagnet over a permanent magnet?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It does not require a power source",
            "X": "It does not have magnetic polarity",
            "Y": "It can be turned on and off by switching current on and off",
            "Z": "It can readily be found in nature"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 4-ampere current is maintained in a simple circuit with a total resistance of 2 ohms. How much energy in joules is delivered in 45 seconds?",
        "Answer": "1440 ______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements BEST describes specific heat capacity?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The amount of thermal energy required to change the temperature of a substance by a certain amount per unit of mass",
            "X": "The amount of thermal energy required to alter the physical state of a given substance",
            "Y": "The total amount of thermal energy in a specific system",
            "Z": "The average kinetic energy of molecules in a system"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A block with a mass of 20 kilograms is being pulled across a level surface. Assuming other forces are negligible and g is 9.8 meters per second squared, what is the coefficient of friction between the two surfaces if a 60-newton force is required to maintain a constant velocity? Provide your answer as a decimal to the nearest tenth.",
        "Answer": "0.3 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When a proton undergoes beta-plus decay, what two particles are created along with the beta particle?",
        "Answer": "NEUTRON AND NEUTRINO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A position-time graph for position x and time t is defined by the equation x = -t2 + 4t for t \" 0. If positive represents forward motion and negative represents backward motion, during which time intervals in seconds would motion be forward and backward, respectively?",
        "Answer": "FORWARD FOR t < 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following conditions is necessary and sufficient for an object in equilibrium?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is at rest",
            "X": "It is moving with constant velocity",
            "Y": "It is either moving with constant velocity or with constant acceleration",
            "Z": "It is moving with constant acceleration"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An object with a mass of 1 gram is whirled in a horizontal circle with a radius of 0.5 meters at a constant speed of 2 meters per second. What is the work done on the object, in joules, during one revolution?",
        "Answer": "0 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following will INCREASE the current from a solar panel?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Using a lead acid cell in series with the solar cells",
            "X": "Using a wet cell in series with the solar cells",
            "Y": "Connecting the solar cells in series",
            "Z": "Connecting the solar cells in parallel"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given a DC circuit with a voltage source delivering 20 volts and a circuit resistance of 5 kiloohms, what is the value of the current in amperes?",
        "Answer": "0.004 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Neglecting the effect of air resistance, a stone dropped off of a 197-meter high building lands on the ground at which of the following approximate times in seconds?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3",
            "X": "4",
            "Y": "6",
            "Z": "18"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A capacitor has a very large capacitance of 10 farads and is charged by placing a potential difference of 2 volts between its plates. How much energy in joules is stored in the capacitor?",
        "Answer": "20 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the phrase that refers to the energy required by an incident photon to cause the photoelectric effect?",
        "Answer": "WORK FUNCTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, identify all of the following four household items that make use of the Bernoulli principle: 1) refrigerator, 2) can opener, 3) washing machine, 4) vacuum cleaner.",
        "Answer": "VACUUM CLEANER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "As the result of a collision with another particle, a charged particle ends up with its velocity vector completely parallel to a uniform magnetic field. Which of the following best describes the subsequent path of the particle?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A circular arc",
            "X": "A spiral",
            "Y": "A straight line",
            "Z": "A cycloid"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An 80 kilogram person dives horizontally off a 100 kilogram rowboat. If the diver\u00d5s speed after leaving the rowboat is 5 meters per second, what is the speed in meters per second of the rowboat?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two charges, initially 2.0 centimeters apart, experience a repulsive force of 1.0 newtons. Providing your answer as a fraction in simplest form, when the charges are moved to 8.0 centimeters apart, what force in newtons exists between them?",
        "Answer": "1/16"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A solid conducting sphere with a radius of 2 centimeters has a charge of 8 microcoulombs. Concentric with the solid sphere is a hollow conducting spherical shell with an inner radius of 4 centimeters, outer radius of 5 centimeters, and charge of -4 microcoulombs. Find the magnitude of the electric field in newtons per coulomb at a radius of 4.5 centimeters.",
        "Answer": "ZERO _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, which of the following three choices are possible constituents of cold dark matter: 1) axions, 2) photinos, 3) quark nuggets?",
        "Answer": "AXIONS, PHOTINOS, AND QUARK NUGGETS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the wavelength, rounded to the nearest ten meters, for the carrier wave of the AM radio station WDOE 1410?",
        "Answer": "210"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What subatomic particle is considered the messenger of the strong force?",
        "Answer": "GLUON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When connected to a 5-volt battery, how many 5 microfarad capacitors must be connected in parallel in order to store a charge of 100 microcoulombs?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a Bose-Einstein condensate, what general type of particles co-exist in the lowest possible quantum state?",
        "Answer": ""
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 9-volt battery costs $1.49 and will run a portable DVD player for 6 hours, supplying 25 milliamperes of current. What is the cost per kilowatt hour of the battery\u00d5s energy to the nearest $100?",
        "Answer": "$1100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Using 9.8 meters per second squared for g and providing your answer to the nearest kilojoule, what is the gravitational potential energy of a 33 kilogram cart halfway down a 25-meter high slope that is 60 meters long?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assuming that the speed of sound in air is 343 meters per second and providing your answer to the nearest integer, what is the fundamental frequency in hertz produced by a pipe with a length of 3 meters that is open at both ends?",
        "Answer": "57 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Under which of the following conditions is the momentum of a system unchanged?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The system is undergoing acceleration",
            "X": "The system is acted upon by multiple forces",
            "Y": "The net external forces are zero",
            "Z": "The net internal forces are zero"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer to the nearest hundredth, what is the moment of inertia in kilogram meters squared of a solid sphere with a mass of 2.5 kilograms and a radius of 30 centimeters?",
        "Answer": "0.09"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The single electron in the ground state of hydrogen is bound to the proton by 13.6 electron volts. If it is excited to the n = 2 state, by which of the following energies, in electron volts, is it now bound?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3.4",
            "X": "6.8",
            "Y": "13.6",
            "Z": "54.4"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A model truck with a mass of 1.0 kilogram is accelerated by an electric motor from rest to 0.8 meters per second in 20 milliseconds. What is the average power, in watts, delivered by the motor during this time?",
        "Answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following kinds of cells CANNOT be recharged?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Dry",
            "X": "Wet",
            "Y": "Primary",
            "Z": "Secondary"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 600-newton worker is standing 1.00 meters from the left end of a 200-newton scaffold that is 3.00 meters long and supported by cables at each end. What is the tension in newtons in the right-hand cable?",
        "Answer": "300"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The pressure of an ideal gas is kept constant while the volume of the gas is increased from 2 cubic meters to 6 cubic meters. If the initial temperature is 17\u00a1 Celsius, find the final temperature in Kelvin to the nearest integer.",
        "Answer": "870"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, identify all of the following four groups of physical quantities that have the same units: 1) electric flux, electric field, and electric dipole moment; 2) heat, potential energy, and work; 3) pressure, stress, and Young\u00d5s modulus; 4) electromotive force, potential difference, and electric voltage.",
        "Answer": "2, 3, AND 4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, identify how antimatter interacts gravitationally with ordinary matter: 1) it is attracted, 2) it is repelled, or 3) there is no interaction.",
        "Answer": "IT IS ATTRACTED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A solid conducting sphere with a radius of 5 centimeters has a charge of 5 microcoulombs. Given Coulomb\u00d5s constant as 9.0 ! 109 newton meters squared per coulomb squared, what is the magnitude of the electric field in newtons per coulomb at a distance of 5 centimeters from the surface of the sphere?",
        "Answer": "4,500,000 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A person spearfishing from the shore sees a fish located 3 meters from the shore at an approximate depth of 1 meter. To spear the fish, the person should aim in which of the following directions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Directly at the fish\u00d5s image",
            "X": "Above the fish\u00d5s image",
            "Y": "Below the fish\u00d5s image",
            "Z": "Behind the fish\u00d5s image"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Once a rocket\u00d5s fuel runs out, it coasts upwards for another 50 kilometers before falling back to Earth. Given g as 10 meters per second squared, what was the rocket\u00d5s vertical velocity in meters per second the moment the fuel ran out?",
        "Answer": "1000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A ball is thrown vertically upward. Assuming that up is positive, which of the following pairs best describes its velocity and acceleration, respectively, at its highest point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Negative, negative",
            "X": "Zero, negative",
            "Y": "Negative, zero",
            "Z": "Zero, zero"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If an earplug decreases the sound level of sound waves by 20 decibels, providing your answer as a decimal to the nearest hundredth, what is the ratio of the final intensity of the waves to their initial intensity?",
        "Answer": "0.01 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A worker pushes a crate across the floor with a force of 50 newtons for a distance of 10 meters. If a frictional force of 20 newtons acts on the crate, what is the net work, in joules, done on the crate?",
        "Answer": "300"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A horizontal force of 200 newtons is used to push a 50 kilogram box 10 meters across a floor at constant speed. Given 9.8 meters per second squared as g and providing your answer as a decimal to the nearest hundredth, what is the coefficient of kinetic friction between the box and the floor?",
        "Answer": "0.41 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 2 meter by 2 meter raft sinks 10 centimeters into the water. Which of the following approximates its weight in newtons?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "5000",
            "X": "3900",
            "Y": "2500",
            "Z": "1600"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Suppose a bat emits sound waves at a frequency of 83 kilohertz while flying with a velocity of 9.0 meters per second as it chases a moth that flies with a velocity of 8.0 meters per second. Given the speed of sound as 343 meters per second, to the nearest integer, what frequency in kilohertz does the moth detect?",
        "Answer": "83"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the family name for composite particles made from quarks?",
        "Answer": "HADRONS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 1.0-kilogram block is fastened to a spring whose spring constant is 16 newtons per meter. The block is pulled a distance of 11 centimeters from its equilibrium position at x = 0 on a frictionless surface and released from rest at t = 0. What is the period rounded to the nearest tenth of the oscillation?",
        "Answer": "1.6 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The potential voltage difference between two points is 100 volts. If a particle with a charge of 2 coulombs is transported from one of these points to the other, what is the magnitude of the work done in joules?",
        "Answer": "200"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Three particles A, B, and C form an equilateral triangle with a side length of 140 centimeters. A lies at the origin with a mass of 1.1 kilograms. B lies on the x axis with a mass of 2.5 kilograms. C lies in Quadrant I with a mass of 3.4 kilograms. To the nearest centimeter, what is the x coordinate of the center of mass of this system?",
        "Answer": "84 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements concerning the magnetic field inside and far from the surface of a long, current-carrying solenoid is TRUE?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is zero",
            "X": "It is non-zero and nearly uniform",
            "Y": "It varies with 1/r as measured from the solenoid axis",
            "Z": "It is independent of the current in the solenoid"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given that objects that have mass greater than 0, by number, identify all of the following four statements that are TRUE: 1) momentum is a form of energy; 2) if an object has momentum, then it must also have mechanical energy; 3) if an object does not have momentum, then it does not have mechanical energy either; 4) if two objects of different mass have the same momentum, then the less massive object will have the greater kinetic energy.",
        "Answer": "2 AND 4 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Given 9.8 meters per second squared as g, how much kinetic energy in joules is lost when a 100-gram ball dropped from a 2 meter height rebounds to 1.5 meters?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1.96",
            "X": "1.47",
            "Y": "0.98",
            "Z": "0.49"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "As a rock with a mass of 4-kilograms drops from the edge of a 40-meter-high cliff, it experiences air resistance with an average strength of 20 newtons during the descent. Given g as 10 meters per second squared, at what speed, in meters per second, will the rock hit the ground?",
        "Answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the magnitude of the focal length of a spherically curved convex mirror in air, where R stands for the radius of curvature:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "R divided by 1.22",
            "X": "R divided by 2",
            "Y": "R divided by 1.5",
            "Z": "R times 4"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An emergency floodlight draws 1 ampere from its battery pack.  How many coulombs will flow through the light in 4 hours?",
        "Answer": "14,400"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following MOST directly determines the permittivity of a material:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "ability of the material to magnetize",
            "X": "electrical susceptibility",
            "Y": "electrical insulation capacity",
            "Z": "electrical conductivity"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the SI units for permittivity?",
        "Answer": "FARADS PER METER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the general term for the process of making different types of semiconductors by adding slight amounts of impurities into the silicon matrix?",
        "Answer": "DOPING"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What specific type of semiconductor is produced by doping silicon with arsenic?",
        "Answer": "N-TYPE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the electrolysis of water, if the production of each molecule of oxygen requires 4 units of  electricity, each hydrogen molecule will require how many units of electricity?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the maximum number of 100-watt light bulbs that can run on a 110-volt residential circuit protected by a 15-amp fuse without blowing the fuse?",
        "Answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If an ideal gas performs work on its surroundings, then which of the following must be true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Its pressure increases",
            "X": "Its volume increases",
            "Y": "Its temperature increases",
            "Z": "Its internal energy decreases"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 90 kilogram fullback running north at 10 meters per second is tackled by a 120 kilogram linebacker running south at 4 meters per second in a perfectly inelastic collision. Which of the following is the velocity in meters per second of the players after the collision?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3 south",
            "X": "3 north",
            "Y": "2 south",
            "Z": "2 north"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following will double the power dissipated by a resistor?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Doubling the voltage across the resistor",
            "X": "Decreasing the voltage to one half of the original value",
            "Y": "Increasing the voltage by a factor of the square root of 2",
            "Z": "Decreasing the voltage by a factor of the square root of 2"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given c as 3 X 108 meters per second, what is the wavelength in meters to the nearest tenth of a radio wave with a frequency of 94.7 megahertz?",
        "Answer": "3.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following particles has an electric charge of zero?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Electron",
            "X": "Quark",
            "Y": "Gluon",
            "Z": "Muon"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A swimming pool water pump draws about 4.2 amperes when connected to 240 volts. If energy costs 10 cents per kilowatt hour, what is the bill to the nearest cent for running the pump continuously for 1 day?",
        "Answer": "$2.42"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A spinning skater draws her arms in closer to her body to rotate faster. Which of the following conservation principles is being applied?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Rotational kinetic energy",
            "X": "Torque",
            "Y": "Angular momentum",
            "Z": "Energy"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An object with a moment of inertia of 2 kilogram meters squared about its axis of rotation makes 6 revolutions per minute. A second stationary object is now gently placed on the first so that the combined moment of inertia about the spin axis is 4 kilogram meters squared. What is the spin rate in revolutions per minute of the composite object?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 9 volt DC power supply is connected to a 10 henry inductor and a 30 ohm resistor in series. Providing your answer as a decimal to the nearest tenth, after the circuit has been connected for a very long time, how much current in amperes flows through the circuit?",
        "Answer": "0.3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 9 volt battery is composed of six 1.5 volt cells, which are connected in series. Each cell has an internal resistance of 0.2 ohms. Providing your answer to the nearest tenth, what is the maximum current in amperes that can be obtained from such a battery?",
        "Answer": "7.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The sound level of a normal conversation is measured at 65 decibels. If the intensity of the sound waves in the conversation was multiplied by a factor of 100 as people began to yell, what would the new sound level measure in decibels?",
        "Answer": "85"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given acceleration due to gravity as 9.8 meters per second squared, how much horizontal force, to the nearest newton, is required to keep a 30 kilogram block moving at constant speed across a horizontal surface, with a frictional coefficient of 0.20 between the floor and the block?",
        "Answer": "59"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Tripling the power output from a speaker emitting a single tone will result in an increase in sound intensity in decibels that is closest to which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.3",
            "X": "2",
            "Y": "4",
            "Z": "5"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When subjected to a potential difference of 100 volts, a parallel-plate capacitor builds up a charge on one plate of 0.2 coulombs. Providing your answer to the nearest thousandth, what is this capacitor's capacitance in farads?",
        "Answer": "0.002"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of an ideal Carnot engine operating between temperature reservoirs of 27\u00ba Celsius and 227\u00ba Celsius?",
        "Answer": "40%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A parachutist lands on the ground at a speed of 6 meters per second. Providing your answer to the nearest tenth and given acceleration due to gravity as 10 meters per second squared, what is the height in meters from which a free-falling object would have to fall to reach the same speed?",
        "Answer": "1.8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The electron transitions responsible for the generation of light have durations on the order of 10-8 seconds. Which of the following best represents the natural linewidth in hertz of the resulting visible light?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10-8",
            "X": "3",
            "Y": "108",
            "Z": "1016"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following types of thermometer is based on the difference in the voltage induced by a temperature gradient in two metals?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Beckman",
            "X": "Silicon band gap",
            "Y": "Thermistor",
            "Z": "Thermocouple"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In your interferometry [in-ter-fuh-ROM-i-try] experiment, you measure a minimum intensity of 1 watt per meter squared and a maximum intensity of 19 watts per meter squared. What is the visibility of your fringes?",
        "Answer": "0.9"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The sound source of a ship\u2122s sonar system operates at a frequency 22 kilohertz. The speed of sound in water is 1482 meters per second. Providing your answer to the nearest hundredth, what is the wavelength of the waves in meters emitted by the source?",
        "Answer": "0.07"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to Maxwell\u2122s equations, which of the following does NOT exist?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Infinitely separated charges",
            "X": "Magnetic monopoles",
            "Y": "Magnetically contained plasma",
            "Z": "Superconductivity"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A person who weighs 200 pounds on Earth, where acceleration due to gravity is 9.8 meters per second squared, is standing in a circular rotating space station in outer space, with a tangential speed of 300 meters per second. If the radius of the station is 9184 meters, what will the person weigh in the space station?",
        "Answer": "THE SAME"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 2 kilogram box is pushed starting from rest along a horizontal surface with a force of 10 newtons. If the frictional force is 4 newtons, how long in seconds will it take the box to reach a speed of 15 meters per second?",
        "Answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A rock is tied to the end of a 1 meter long string and spun in a vertical circle. Providing your answer as a decimal to the nearest hundredth, what is the minimum speed in meters per second it can travel and just get around the top, given acceleration due to gravity as 10 meters per second squared?",
        "Answer": "3.16"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two identically sized conducting spheres, A, with a charge of +3.2 x 10-19 coulombs, and B, with a charge of -6.4 x 10-19 coulombs, are allowed to touch. While they are touching, sphere A does which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gains three protons",
            "X": "Loses three protons",
            "Y": "Gains three electrons",
            "Z": "Gains four electrons"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A car's starter motor draws a current of 100 amperes at 12.0 volts when starting the engine. The mechanical power required to turn the engine is 960 watts. At what rate, in watts, is energy from the battery converted to heat?",
        "Answer": "240"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When a resistor, inductor, and capacitor are connected in series to an AC generator, the current through the capacitor must be in phase with the voltage across which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The capacitor",
            "X": "The inductor",
            "Y": "The entire circuit",
            "Z": "The resistor"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a series resonant circuit, the circuit impedance at resonance is always which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Equal to the resistance",
            "X": "Equal to the capacitive reactance",
            "Y": "Equal to the inductive reactance",
            "Z": "Greater than the capacitive reactance"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The root mean square voltage of a sinusoidal AC coupled circuit is approximately equal to its maximum value multiplied by which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.5",
            "X": "0.7",
            "Y": "1.4",
            "Z": "1.7"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In one cycle, a heat engine exhausts 3000 joules of heat while performing 1500 joules of work. What is its percentage of efficiency to the tenths place?",
        "Answer": "33.3%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A wire of radius A carries a uniform current I. The total magnetic energy per unit length contained within the wire is which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Proportional to A2",
            "X": "Proportional to A",
            "Y": "Independent of A",
            "Z": "Zero"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The period of a mass bouncing on a spring is measured in the reference frame of an observer as T. If the system were instead moving past the observer with a velocity of 0.8c, which of the following is closest to the period she would observe?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.44T",
            "X": "0.6T",
            "Y": "1.7T",
            "Z": "1.9T"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following best describes why arches and domes are more stable than flat roofed structures?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They transmit compressive forces along their length to the ground, uniformly bearing the load of gravity upon the structure",
            "X": "Each section is under great tension, using the stronger dimension of the components",
            "Y": "Torsional resistance to sideways swaying ensures that such structures are stable, even in high winds",
            "Z": "The surface tension of the arched shape allows the building components to be hollowed out, saving weight"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given a piece of glass with an index refraction of 2, what is the optimal index of refraction, to one decimal place, for an antireflection coating?",
        "Answer": "1.4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A nubbin-on-a-spring keeps a door from hitting the wall. If the nubbin is flicked, such that the nubbin passes its rest point more than once before coming to rest, which of the following is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is undamped",
            "X": "It is underdamped",
            "Y": "It is criticially damped",
            "Z": "It is overdamped"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A potential of 10 volts is applied to a parallel plate capacitor with capacitance of 1 microfarad and a plate separation of 10 micrometers. What is the electrical force in newtons between the plates?",
        "Answer": "10"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Work W is done to extend a spring beyond its natural length by a small distance x. Assuming a spring constant of 1, which of the following is the magnitude of the maximum force done by the person stretching the spring?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "x",
            "X": "x/2W",
            "Y": "2W/x",
            "Z": "2W/x2"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a spaceship moving at relativistic speed v appears to be shortened to 4/5 its original length, what is its speed as a fraction of the speed of light, c, in lowest terms?",
        "Answer": "3c/5 OR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What two word phrase describes an electromagnetic wave in which the electric field lies in a single plane along the direction of propagation?",
        "Answer": "LINEARLY POLARIZED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Planets A and B are in circular orbits about the same star. Planet A's orbital radius is three times as large as Planet B's. Which of the following is the ratio of Planet A's orbital period to Planet B's?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "",
            "X": "/2",
            "Y": "33/2 [three to the power of the quantity three over two]",
            "Z": "32/3 [three to the power of the quantity two over three]"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two charges, Q and -Q, are placed at x = -3 and x = +1 on the x-axis. Where on the x-axis between +Q and -Q can another charge be placed so that it experiences no net force?",
        "Answer": "NOWHERE, DOES NOT EXIST"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Suppose that you support a meter stick horizontally by positioning one finger under one of the ends and the other finger about one-quarter of the way from the opposite end. Now suppose you move your fingers slowly together until they touch. By number, identify what will most likely happen to the meter stick: 1) it will fall off the side with the finger under the end; 2) it will fall off the side with the finger about one quarter of the way from the end; or 3) it will stay balanced on your fingers.",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A source travelling towards us at (3/5)c emits photons in a direction perpendicular to its velocity. If the source emits photons with energy of 0.5 electron volts in its own rest frame, which of the following energies, in electron volts, do the photons have in our rest frame?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.3",
            "X": "0.4",
            "Y": "0.5",
            "Z": "0.6"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An unknown particle with rest energy of 1 mega-electron volt is traveling with a speed of (3/5)c along the x-axis in our rest frame when it decays into two photons, also travelling along the x-axis. What are the energies of the photons in mega-electron volts?",
        "Answer": "0.25"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "As a photon travels from water to air, which of the following quantities changes?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Frequency",
            "X": "Wavelength",
            "Y": "Energy",
            "Z": "Phase"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A starship is heading towards Earth at 0.7c. To begin slowing down, it enables a forward thruster that emits fuel at 0.8c in the direction of Earth. Relative to Earth, which of the following is the approximate speed of the fuel?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.8c",
            "X": "0.96c",
            "Y": "0.99c",
            "Z": "1.5c"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Three masses are arranged at the vertices of an equilateral triangle and are connected by springs along the edges of the equilateral triangle. How many normal modes for vibration does this mass-spring system have?",
        "Answer": "THREE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When a charged particle moves in a dielectric medium at a speed greater than the speed of light in that medium, what kind of radiation do the atoms in the medium emit?",
        "Answer": "CHERENKOV"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following principles of fluid dynamics does an airplane use to create an upward force?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Archimedes\u2122",
            "X": "Pascal\u2122s",
            "Y": "Venturi\u2122s",
            "Z": "Bernoulli\u2122s"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If magnetic monopoles exist, which of the following Maxwell\u2122s equations would be changed?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gauss\u2122s law for magnetism only",
            "X": "Gauss\u2122s law for magnetism and Ampere\u2122s law",
            "Y": "Gauss\u2122s law for magnetism and Faraday\u2122s law",
            "Z": "Gauss\u2122s law for magnetism, Ampere\u2122s law, and Faraday\u2122s law"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two electromagnetic waves are incident upon a gerbil. They are identical and coherent except for a phase difference of 60 degrees. If the intensity of each wave in isolation is 10 watts per meter squared, what is the intensity of light in watts per square meter experienced by the gerbil?",
        "Answer": "30"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An ideal gas is enclosed within a container with a movable piston as the lid. The gas is initially at a pressure of 3 atmospheres and occupies a volume of 2 liters. The piston is lowered so that the gas now occupies 1.5 liters at a pressure of P. If the process was carried out slowly, maintaining constant temperature in contact with a suitable reservoir, what is P in atmospheres?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When an object with a volume of 10 cubic meters is completely submerged in water, given that acceleration due to gravity is 9.8 meters per second squared, what is the buoyant force on the object in newtons if the density of water is 1000 kilograms per cubic meter?",
        "Answer": "98,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Stress-strain curves show how real materials respond to forces that are applied to them. Materials such as steel have a region of elasticity where they approximate an ideal spring and a region where they start to deform plastically. Where the materials are acting like an ideal spring, how do we find their Young's modulus?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is the slope of the stress-strain curve",
            "X": "It is the integral of the curve in the elastic region",
            "Y": "It is the y-intercept of the stress-strain curve",
            "Z": "It is the second derivative of the curve just after transition into the region of plastic deformation"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What type of antineutrino [an-tee-noo-TREE-noh] is produced in beta decay?",
        "Answer": "ELECTRON ANTINEUTRINO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "There is an electrostatic force of attraction between any two of three metal spheres P, Q, and R. Which of the following is a possible combination for the charges on P, Q, and R?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "P: positive, Q: negative, R: positive",
            "X": "P: positive, Q: negative, R: neutral",
            "Y": "P: positive, Q: positive, R: positive",
            "Z": "P: neutral, Q: positive, R: neutral"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A rock is thrown vertically upwards with speed v from the edge of a cliff. At the same moment, a second rock is thrown vertically downwards with the same initial speed v. Neglecting air resistance, which of the following statements is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The rock that was thrown upwards reaches the bottom of the cliff with a higher velocity",
            "X": "The rock that was thrown downwards reaches the bottom of the cliff with a higher velocity",
            "Y": "Both rocks reach the bottom of the cliff with the same velocity at the same time",
            "Z": "Both rocks reach the bottom of the cliff with the same velocity but at different times"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A mass is spun horizontally at the end of a string. If its speed is changed so that the centripetal force is doubled, in simplest decimal form to the nearest tenth, what is the ratio of final speed to initial speed?",
        "Answer": "1.4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A string 40 centimeters long produces a fundamental frequency of 384 hertz. To produce a note one octave higher, the tension in the string must be increased by which of the following factors?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.7",
            "X": "1.4",
            "Y": "2",
            "Z": "4"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A meter stick is held by a low-friction support on a stand. A single weight and an air-filled balloon hang from the left side of the meter stick; a weight hangs from the right side of the meter stick. The fulcrum is adjusted so that the system is balanced and level. If the string holding the balloon is burned so as to exert no torque when the string breaks, identify by number what will happen when the string breaks: 1) the right side of the meter stick will go down; 2) the left side of the meter stick will go down; or 3) the meter stick will remain balanced.",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If two inductance coils of inductance L are connected in parallel, but are well separated, the equivalent inductance of the system is which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.5L",
            "X": "L",
            "Y": "2L",
            "Z": "L2"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two balls are dropped one second apart from a tall building. Given g as 10 meters per second squared and neglecting air resistance, what is the approximate distance in meters between the two balls three seconds after the first ball is dropped?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "20",
            "X": "25",
            "Y": "45",
            "Z": "Depends on the masses"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "White light is incident on a diffraction grating. Which of the following colors will be diffracted through the largest angle?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Red",
            "X": "Yellow",
            "Y": "Blue",
            "Z": "Green"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A square conducting loop of length L on a side carries a current i. Which of the following best characterizes the magnetic field at the center of the loop?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Independent of L",
            "X": "Inversely proportional to L",
            "Y": "Proportional to L",
            "Z": "Proportional to L2"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which Greek scientist discovered that, when an object is immersed in a fluid, there is a buoyant force acting upward on the object equal to the weight of the displaced fluid?",
        "Answer": "ARCHIMEDES"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is true for a cyclist applying her brakes while traveling west on a straight path?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Her acceleration is zero",
            "X": "She accelerates to the east",
            "Y": "She accelerates to the west",
            "Z": "She accelerates both to the east and the west"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Pascal\u2122s law governs the actions of forces in which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gases",
            "X": "Solids",
            "Y": "Incompressible fluids",
            "Z": "A vacuum"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What current, in amperes, is carried in a lightning stroke that lasts 0.5 seconds and transfers 100 coulombs of charge?",
        "Answer": "200"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The two leaves of an electroscope repel each other and stand out at an angle. What force balances the electrical force so the leaves don\u2122t stand out farther?",
        "Answer": "GRAVITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A block of wood, when floating in water, displaces 300 cubic centimeters of water. When completely submerged, the block displaces 400 cubic centimeters of water. What is the specific gravity of the block?",
        "Answer": "0.75"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What force does a charged particle moving through a magnetic field experience that is perpendicular to the direction the particle is traveling?",
        "Answer": "LORENTZ"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the mass, in kilograms, of a 2 kilogram rock on a planet with a gravitational acceleration of 8.2 meters per second squared?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An alpha particle consists of what types and numbers of subatomic particles?",
        "Answer": "TWO PROTONS AND TWO NEUTRONS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The rotor of a helicopter blade turns at an angular speed of 5 revolutions per second, which is approximately which of the following in radians per second?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "22",
            "X": "31",
            "Y": "35",
            "Z": "40"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following wave types does not exhibit polarization?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gravitational",
            "X": "X-ray",
            "Y": "Acoustic",
            "Z": "Visible light"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three choices that may define the phase velocity of a wave: 1) frequency, 2) period, 3) wavelength.",
        "Answer": "ALL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A person standing on a scaffold lowers an object with a weight of 250 newtons by means of a rope, at constant speed. If the weight of the rope is negligible, what is the force in newtons that the person exerts on the rope?",
        "Answer": "250"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Relative to the ground, how many joules of potential energy does a 1000 newton boulder have at the top of a 5 meter ledge, relative to the bottom of the ledge and given g as 10 meters per second squared?",
        "Answer": "5000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An unpowered open truck is coasting horizontally with a constant velocity along a frictionless track underneath a grain bin when grain falls vertically into the truck, partly filling it as it moves along. Which of the following will happen to the horizontal momentum of the truck with the accumulating grain?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It will decrease",
            "X": "It will increase",
            "Y": "It will stay the same",
            "Z": "It will first increase and then decrease"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A mass is suspended by two springs of equal length connected in parallel. The mass stretches the springs by a distance A beyond their equilibrium length. The springs are rearranged to be connected in series, so that now the mass stretches the springs by a distance B beyond their equilibrium length. By number, identify which of the following is true: 1) A is greater than B, 2) A is less than B, 3) A and B are the same distance.",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a series-connected string of holiday lights, which of the following is most likely to occur if one bulb gets shorted without breaking the filament?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "All other bulbs will go out",
            "X": "The current in the string will increase",
            "Y": "The current in the string will decrease",
            "Z": "The current in the string will remain unchanged"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a car goes from zero to 20 meters per second in 8 seconds, providing your answer to the nearest tenth, what is its average acceleration in meters per second squared?",
        "Answer": "2.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An object of mass m sits on a flat table. The Earth pulls on the object with force mg. Which of the following is the corresponding reaction force?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The table pushing down on the floor with force mg",
            "X": "The object pushing down on the table with force mg",
            "Y": "The object pulling upward on the Earth with force mg",
            "Z": "The table pushing up on the object with force mg"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A projectile is fired from a gun at an angle of 45o with respect to the horizontal. Given 9.8 meters per second squared as the acceleration due to gravity, and neglecting air resistance, what are the magnitude and direction of the acceleration of the projectile when it reaches its maximum height?",
        "Answer": "9.8 METERS PER SECOND SQUARED, DOWNWARD"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the mathematical relationship between the period of a wave and the frequency of a wave?",
        "Answer": "INVERSE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a radio station broadcasts with a wavelength of 2.5 meters, what is the frequency of the radio station in megahertz, given the speed of light as 3 X 108 meters per second?",
        "Answer": "120"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A massless, rigid, insulating rod of length R is attached at one end to a wall by a hinge so that it is free to swing vertically. The other end of the rod is attached to a sphere of mass m with charge -Q. If the rod and sphere are released in a horizontal position, which of the following electric fields is required to maintain the horizontal position of the rod?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "mg/Q, down",
            "X": "mg/Q, up",
            "Y": "mgQ/R, down",
            "Z": "mgR/Q, up"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The majority of helium originating in the dust cloud that formed the Earth has since evaporated into space. Most present-day terrestrially available helium comes from which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nuclear fusion reactors",
            "X": "A by-product of nuclear fission",
            "Y": "Harvested from the ionosphere",
            "Z": "Radioactive decay of heavier elements"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following cells cannot be recharged?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Dry",
            "X": "Wet",
            "Y": "Primary",
            "Z": "Secondary"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Changing which of the following will NOT result in a change in the voltage induced in a rotating wire coil?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Rate of rotation",
            "X": "Wire resistance",
            "Y": "Number of coil loops",
            "Z": "Average loop area"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In 1868, observers of a solar eclipse first noticed a bright yellow spectral line. They theorized that this was due to a new element and gave it what sun-inspired name?",
        "Answer": "HELIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An electroscope is negatively charged, with the leaves at an angle of about 45\u00b0. When a negatively charged rod is slowly brought near the plate of the electroscope, the leaves do which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Repel",
            "X": "Attract",
            "Y": "Repel then attract",
            "Z": "Fall to zero then repel"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A lunar vehicle on Earth moves at 10 kilometers per hour. When it travels at the same speed on the Moon, what is its momentum in comparison to its momentum on Earth, assuming that the Moon\u2122s gravitational force is one fifth that of Earth\u2122s?",
        "Answer": "THE SAME"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Coulomb\u2122s law states that an electric force between two charges is inversely proportional to the square of what quantity?",
        "Answer": "DISTANCE BETWEEN THEM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the SI unit of inductance?",
        "Answer": "HENRY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A radioactive element has a half life of 50 seconds. Which of the following is true of a sample of such an element?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Every atom of the element decays after 50 seconds",
            "X": "Every atom of the element decays after 100 seconds",
            "Y": "After 100 seconds, one fourth of the sample has decayed",
            "Z": "After 100 seconds, three fourths of the sample has decayed"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The acceleration of an object that is in free fall in a vacuum is which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Proportional to the mass of the object",
            "X": "Proportional to the inverse of the mass of the object",
            "Y": "Independent of the mass of the object",
            "Z": "Equal to the product of force and mass"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name of the phenomenon that explains why the surface of water might look like a mirror when viewed from underwater?",
        "Answer": "TOTAL INTERNAL REFLECTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An object is suspended from a spring balance in an elevator. The reading of the balance is 200 newtons when the elevator is at rest. If the balance reading later is 190 newtons, which of the following best describes how the elevator could be moving at that time?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Downward at constant speed",
            "X": "Downward and increasing in speed",
            "Y": "Upward at constant speed",
            "Z": "Upward and increasing in speed"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A small object is 10 centimeters in front of a plane mirror. Standing 20 centimeters behind the object, 30 centimeters from the mirror, at what distance in centimeters must you focus your eyes to see the object\u2122s mirror image clearly?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "20",
            "X": "30",
            "Y": "40",
            "Z": "50"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following products has the same units as power?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Work and time",
            "X": "Force and distance",
            "Y": "Force and velocity",
            "Z": "Force and acceleration"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When turned on, a ceiling fan reaches 100 revolutions per minute in 30 seconds. When turned off, it coasts to a stop in 60 seconds. What is the ratio of the average angular acceleration in the first 30 seconds after it was turned on to that observed after it was turned off?",
        "Answer": "-2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A girl runs up one flight of steps. Which of the following factors does NOT affect the work done by the girl against gravity?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Her mass",
            "X": "Height of the flight of steps",
            "Y": "Her speed",
            "Z": "Acceleration due to gravity"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of the body when a cyclist expends 1000 watts of power to deliver mechanical energy to the bicycle at a rate of 100 watts?",
        "Answer": "10%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What type of particle mediates the strong nuclear force?",
        "Answer": "GLUON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A car with a mass of 1100 kilograms moves at 24 meters per second. What is the magnitude of the braking force, in newtons, needed to bring the car to a halt in 20 seconds?",
        "Answer": "1320"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a 0.20 kilogram apple fell 7.0 meters, hitting Newton\u2122s head, given acceleration due to gravity as 10 meters per second squared, what was the change in potential energy in joules?",
        "Answer": "14"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Taking the acceleration due to gravity to be 10 meters per second squared, what kinetic coefficient of friction will exert a force of 20 newtons on a 4 kilogram object as it moves over a horizontal surface?",
        "Answer": "0.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A current of 4 milliamperes flows when a resistor is connected across a 12-volt battery. What is the resistance of this resistor in ohms?",
        "Answer": "3000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two asteroids that are 10,000 kilometers apart attract each other with a gravitational force of F. If the two asteroids move further away from each other to a distance of 20,000 kilometers apart, what will the gravitational force be in terms of F?",
        "Answer": "\u00bc F"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A wheel with moment of inertia m is mounted horizontally to a frictionless axle.  At time t = 0 the initial angular speed is . A constant torque Q is applied to the wheel, bringing it to a stop in time t. Which of the following is the average power required to dissipate the wheel\u2122s energy in this time?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "m/2t",
            "X": "m\u00b2/2t",
            "Y": "m/t",
            "Z": "m"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A pole vaulter wishes to clear a bar 5 meters above her center of mass. Given an ideal pole and launch, assuming her mass is uniformly distributed, and given 10 meters per second squared as the acceleration due to gravity, how fast must she run in meters per second?",
        "Answer": "10"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A bicycle wheel undergoes constant angular acceleration for time t. Identify all of the following three choices at which the average acceleration equals the instantaneous acceleration: 1) 0.5t, 2) 0.67t, 3) 0.707t.",
        "Answer": "ALL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the average force in newtons exerted on a 25 gram egg by a bed sheet if the egg hits the sheet at 4 meters per second and takes 0.2 seconds to stop, given acceleration due to gravity as 10 meters per second squared?",
        "Answer": "0.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Four particles are moving from north to south through a region with magnetic field directed from west to east. Which of the following particles bends downward?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Alpha",
            "X": "Beta",
            "Y": "Neutron",
            "Z": "Graviton"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Forty-five joules of energy are added to a quantity of ideal gas, and the gas expands and does 34 joules of work. What is the change in internal energy of the gas, in joules?",
        "Answer": "11"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When a tennis racket hits a tennis ball, how do the forces on each object compare?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The force on the tennis ball has a greater magnitude than the force on the racket",
            "X": "The force on the racket has a greater magnitude than the force on the ball",
            "Y": "The magnitude of the force on each object is the same",
            "Z": "The forces depend on the level of impact"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A wave with a frequency of 40 hertz has a wavelength of 2.5 meters. What is the phase velocity in meters per second?",
        "Answer": "100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Sue and Ben are 5 and 10 meters, respectively, away from a balloon when it pops loudly. Sue's sound pressure meter recorded a level of 80 decibels. What did Ben's identical meter record in decibels to the nearest decibel?",
        "Answer": "74"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A current-carrying wire changes diameter from larger to smaller gauge. In which of the following locations would the current be greater?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Larger section",
            "X": "Smaller section",
            "Y": "At the location where the wire changes diameter",
            "Z": "It would be the same at all points"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A train approaches a station with a velocity of +15 meters per second relative to the ground. If a person on the train is moving towards the rear of the train at a speed of 1.5 meters per second relative to the train, what is the velocity, in meters per second, of the person relative to the ground?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "+13.5",
            "X": "\u0152 13.5",
            "Y": "+16.5",
            "Z": "-16.5"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A set of non-zero vectors is added to obtain a sum of zero. What is the minimum number of vectors in the set if they are a) equal in magnitude or b) unequal in magnitude?",
        "Answer": "EQUAL = 2; UNEQUAL= 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The breakdown electric field of air is approximately 3 million volts per meter. Providing your answer in scientific notation, if a typical storm cloud is at an altitude of 2,000 meters, what is the voltage drop between the ground and the storm cloud just before the lightning strike?",
        "Answer": "6 x 109"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A circuit consists of 5 capacitors of 5 microfarads each and a voltage source of 20 volts. If the capacitors are connected in series, what is the potential difference across each of them?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "4 microvolts",
            "X": "4 volts",
            "Y": "10 volts",
            "Z": "20 volts"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "One hundred resistors have minimum, mean, and maximum values of 110 ohms, 150 ohms, and 300 ohms, respectively. If all 100 resistors are connected in parallel, which of the following ranges could contain the equivalent resistance?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The provided information is insufficient to answer the question",
            "X": "Less than 110 ohms",
            "Y": "More than 110 ohms but less than 300 ohms",
            "Z": "More than 300 ohms"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The breakdown electric field of air is approximately 3 million volts per meter. Assuming that lightning moves uniformly through a cylinder of air with a cross-sectional area of 1 square meter and providing your answer in scientific notation with one significant digit, if a typical storm cloud is at an altitude of 2,000 meters and the resistivity of air is about 10 ohm-meters at breakdown, what is the current in amperes of a cloud-to-cloud lightning strike?",
        "Answer": "3 x 105"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A spaceship going away from you at a speed 0.2c sends an electromagnetic signal to you. What is the speed at which the signal approaches?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.2 c",
            "X": "0.8 c",
            "Y": "c",
            "Z": "1.2 c"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A box slides with friction up a ramp, comes to rest briefly, and then slides back down. Which of the following statements about this motion is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The magnitude of the acceleration of the box at any point sliding up the ramp is greater than the magnitude of the acceleration at the same point down the ramp",
            "X": "The magnitude of the acceleration of the box at any point sliding down the ramp is greater than the magnitude of the acceleration at the same point up the ramp",
            "Y": "The magnitude of the acceleration of the box at any point sliding up the ramp is the same as the magnitude of the acceleration of the box at the same point down the ramp and is non-zero",
            "Z": "The magnitude of the acceleration of the box at any point sliding up the ramp is the same as the magnitude of the acceleration of the box at the same point down the ramp and is zero"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If it takes 60 pounds-force to loosen a lug nut with a 5 inch wrench, how much force in pounds-force would it take if you used a 12 inch wrench instead?",
        "Answer": "25"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "On a sunny clear day, the sky seems to be bluer directly overhead than it does toward the horizon. Which of the following is the reason?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Light from the Sun undergoes more scattering with distance",
            "X": "The atmosphere has higher density at the zenith versus closer to the Earth\u2122s surface",
            "Y": "There is more oxygen in the air closer to the Earth\u2122s surface than high in the atmosphere",
            "Z": "The upper atmosphere is colder than the Earth\u2122s surface"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If object A and object B are in thermal equilibrium, and object B and object C are in thermal equilibrium, then object A and object C are also in thermal equilibrium. This situation is an example of what law of thermodynamics?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Zeroth",
            "X": "First",
            "Y": "Second",
            "Z": "Third"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is nearest escape velocity on the surface of the Earth, in miles per hour?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1000",
            "X": "25,000",
            "Y": "66,000",
            "Z": "670 million"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Fluid pressure is caused by which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gravitational interactions among atoms and molecules of the fluid",
            "X": "Collisions of fast moving atoms and molecules of the fluid",
            "Y": "Strong nuclear force among nucleons",
            "Z": "Weak forces among particles"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A projectile is launched with a speed of 10 meters per second from the top of a 30 meter tall cliff at an angle of 30\u00b0 above the horizontal. Assuming that g is 10 meters per second squared, how many seconds after launch will it take this particle to strike the ground at the bottom of the cliff?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A proton initially at rest is accelerated through a potential difference of 1 megavolt. What is its final kinetic energy in electronvolts?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "103",
            "X": "1.6 \u00d7 106",
            "Y": "106",
            "Z": "1.6 \u00d7 106"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 2 kilogram ball experiences a force according to the relation =6, where F is the force in newtons and t is the time in seconds. Assuming that the ball started from rest, how fast in meters per second is the ball moving after experiencing this force for 5 seconds?",
        "Answer": "125"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two cars of unequal mass crash and stick together in a head on collision. Which of the following statements is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The car with the larger mass experiences the larger magnitude impulse",
            "X": "The car with the smaller mass experiences the larger magnitude impulse",
            "Y": "Both cars experience the same magnitude impulse in the same direction",
            "Z": "Both cars experience the same magnitude impulse in opposite directions"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two balls are thrown perfectly horizontally off a cliff on Mars, where the acceleration due to gravity is 3.7 meters per second squared. If ball 1 lands 30 meters further than ball 2, which of the following statements is correct about their initial velocities?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The velocity of ball 1 is 30 meters per second greater than the velocity of ball 2",
            "X": "The velocity of ball 2 is 30 meters per second greater than the velocity of ball 1",
            "Y": "The velocity of ball 1 is 30 times larger than the velocity of ball 2",
            "Z": "The exact relationship cannot be determined without knowing the height of the cliff"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An Atwood\u2122s machine is built with a massless and frictionless pulley with a mass of 1 kilogram on one side and a mass of 4 kilograms on the other side. Assuming that the acceleration due to gravity is 10 meters per second squared, which is the speed of the masses in meters per second three seconds after being released?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "5",
            "X": "6",
            "Y": "15",
            "Z": "18"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "You sit on a pier and look straight down into the pond below. The apparent depth of the pond from the surface of the water is 5.0 meters. Given that the refractive indexes of air and water are 1.0 and 1.3, respectively, what is the real depth of the pond in meters?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.3",
            "X": "3.8",
            "Y": "5.0",
            "Z": "6.7"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If a light ray passes from air (n = 1.00) to acetone (n = 1.36), what is the critical angle?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "47\u00b0",
            "X": "67\u00b0",
            "Y": "87\u00b0",
            "Z": "There is no total internal reflection"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a science lab, a sphere rolls on a horizontal flat surface until it eventually comes to rest, but not as a result of a frictional force. Which of the following is the best explanation of why the sphere comes to rest?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The spherical shape and/or flat surface must not be ideal and the sphere will stop where a defect makes that location a minimum potential-energy position",
            "X": "Some other force, like fluid friction, must be acting on the sphere",
            "Y": "Angular momentum between the rolling sphere and the spinning Earth must be conserved",
            "Z": "The force of gravity must not be constant even though the surface is flat"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 1 nanocoulomb charge is held 1 meter above an infinite sheet with a surface charge density of 1 nanocoulomb per meter squared. If the charge is moved to 2 meters from the sheet, then by what factor does the electric force on the charge change?",
        "Answer": "THERE IS NO CHANGE IN THE ELECTRIC FORCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "You are in a spaceship and you bounce a ball off of a wall and catch it. The time between the instant you throw the ball and when it returns is 1.5 seconds. Another spaceship is travelling at a speed 4/5 the speed of light relative to your ship. From the frame of reference of the other ship, providing your answer to the nearest tenth, how long does it take in seconds for you to throw and catch the ball?",
        "Answer": "2.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A field emission microscope requires which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A conductor with a very fine point",
            "X": "High energy alpha particles",
            "Y": "A light source with a wavelength shorter that the smallest observable feature size",
            "Z": "A low amplitude, time-varying magnetic field"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 2 kilogram object experiences a force with respect to time according to the relation F = 4t newtons from time t = 0 seconds to time t = 3 seconds. What is the impulse that the object experiences in kilogram meters per second during these three seconds?",
        "Answer": "18"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the units of the dielectric constant?",
        "Answer": "UNIT-LESS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A parallel plate capacitor has an area of 2 square meters and plate separation of 1 millimeter. If the electric field between the plates is 10 volts per meter, and given 9 x 10-12 coulombs 0 [epsilon naught], providing your answer in scientific notation with one significant figure, what is the energy in joules stored by the capacitor?",
        "Answer": "9 x 10-13"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "As an object falls to the Earth with air resistance present, what happens to the acceleration of the object?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It remains a constant 9.8 meters per second squared",
            "X": "It increases from 0 to 9.8 meters per second squared",
            "Y": "It remains at a constant 0 meters per second squared",
            "Z": "It decreases from 9.8 to 0 meters per second squared"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rounded to the nearest thousand, how many joules of work are done in pulling a wagon with a force of 2000 newtons over a horizontal surface of 10 meters, with a chain that makes a 45\u00ba angle with the surface?",
        "Answer": "14,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A ball is dropped from rest at a height of 60 meters above the ground. If the potential energy is zero at the ground, then at what height in meters is the potential energy 60% of its initial potential energy?",
        "Answer": "36"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the minimum current in amperes a circuit breaker fuse must be able to handle in order to run a 1450 watt refrigerator hooked up to a 110 volt kitchen circuit, assuming fuses are only available in whole number increments?",
        "Answer": "14"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the efficiency of a Carnot heat engine in which 500 joules of heat enters from the hot reservoir and 300 joules exits into the cold reservoir?",
        "Answer": "40%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A typical incandescent light bulb wastes 90% of its power as heat. Ignoring the contribution of the walls and any furniture, if you left a 100 watt incandescent bulb on in a 5 by 5 by 5 meter room for 100,000 seconds, how much would the temperature of the air in the room increase, in degrees Celsius? Assume, for simplicity, that the room is a closed thermodynamic system, the heat capacity of air is 1 joule per gram per degree, and the mass density of air in the room is 1.2 kilograms per cubic meter.",
        "Answer": "60"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A small rubber duck is held underwater at a depth of 10 meters, then released. When the duck reaches a depth of 5 meters, how much has the buoyant force on the duck changed?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It has decreased by half",
            "X": "It is unchanged",
            "Y": "It has doubled",
            "Z": "It has quadrupled"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Charged particles in a uniform magnetic field will undergo circular motion with a period of m/(qB). The magnetic field of the Earth is roughly 10-4 tesla, assuming it is uniform. Given the mass of a proton to be 1.6 x 10-27 kilograms and its electric charge to be 1.6 x 10-19 coulombs, providing your answer in scientific notation to one significant figure, what period in seconds would you measure for a proton?",
        "Answer": "6 x 10-4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What law describes the relationship between the direction of incident and refracted light rays?",
        "Answer": "SNELL\u2122S LAW"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A container contains 3 moles of helium. The volume remains constant after 2 moles of gas are added and the temperature is halved. Providing your answer as a fraction, what is the ratio of the initial gas pressure to the final gas pressure?",
        "Answer": "6/5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following quark compositions does NOT have a total of zero strangeness quantum number?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Up, down",
            "X": "Up, strange",
            "Y": "Strange, antiparticle strange",
            "Z": "Down, down"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A concave spherical mirror has a radius of 200 centimeters. What object distance in centimeters from this mirror is needed to form a real image that is one fourth of the size of the object?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "100",
            "X": "125",
            "Y": "250",
            "Z": "500"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A body with a 2 kilogram mass has position vector r = 3i + 2t 2j meters. What is the velocity at t = 1 second?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1j",
            "X": "4j",
            "Y": "3i + 4j",
            "Z": "1i + 1j"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two objects with masses m1 and m2 are hanging vertically by different springs of spring constants k1 and k2. If m1 = 3m2 and k1= 2k2, what is the ratio x1/x2 of their stretches?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2/3",
            "X": "3/2",
            "Y": "4",
            "Z": "6"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If the tension in a stretched string is multiplied by a factor of 9, the speed of the transverse wave is multiplied by what factor?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1/9",
            "X": "1/3",
            "Y": "3",
            "Z": "9"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Assuming the Boltzmann constant k = 1.38 \u00d7 10-23 joules per Kelvin, what is the average translational kinetic energy in joules of molecules of an ideal gas at 127o Celsius?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2.6 \u00d710-21",
            "X": "8.28 \u00d7 10-21",
            "Y": "2.6 \u00d710-22",
            "Z": "8.28 \u00d710-22"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What physical unit is the product of velocity, magnetic field, and length?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Volt",
            "X": "Newton meter per ampere second squared",
            "Y": "Joule per second squared",
            "Z": "Newton per ampere"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 1 meter long wire lying along the x-axis carries a current of 10.0 amperes in the negative x direction. The wire is in a uniform magnetic field 1.0 \u00d7 10-3 teslas per square meter. Expressing your answer in scientific notation with one significant figure, what is the magnitude of the magnetic force on the wire in newtons?",
        "Answer": "1 X 10-2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to the Standard Model, protons and neutrons are made of quarks. What are the quark constituents of protons?",
        "Answer": "TWO UPS AND ONE DOWN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What famous nuclear reaction bypasses the \"mass 8 gap\" in stellar burning and proceeds mainly through the Hoyle state in carbon-12?",
        "Answer": "TRIPLE-ALPHA PROCESS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a consequence of Gauss's law for magnetism?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A changing magnetic flux through a loop creates an electric current around the loop",
            "X": "Charges must be moving to produce magnetic fields",
            "Y": "A time-varying electric flux acts as a current and produces a magnetic field",
            "Z": "Magnetic monopoles do not exist"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which of the following three choices has the longest period: 1) a pendulum [PEN-juh-luhm] on Earth with a cord length of 3 meters, 2) a pendulum on the Moon, where the acceleration due to gravity is roughly 1.6 meters per second squared, with a cord length of 1 meter, or 3) a pendulum on Jupiter, where acceleration due to gravity is 26 meters per second squared, with a cord length of 10 meters?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A square loop of wire with a resistance of 2 ohms and a side length of 2 meters has a magnetic field of 5 teslas passing straight through it. If the field is uniformly reduced to zero in 10 seconds, what is the magnitude of the current generated in the loop in amperes?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.5",
            "X": "1",
            "Y": "2",
            "Z": "4"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A rod of length 1 meter and mass 2 kilograms is pivoted perpendicularly to its length and through its center of mass. If two point masses, each with a mass of 1 kilogram, are attached to each end of the rod, what is the total moment of inertia in kilogram meters squared of this collection of objects?",
        "Answer": "2/3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A simple pendulum [PEN-juh-luhm] is pulled back to a large angle less than 90\u00b0, so that the small angle approximation is no longer valid for this situation. Which of the following statements is true about the period of oscillation of the pendulum?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is independent of the amplitude",
            "X": "It is larger than the small angle approximation",
            "Y": "It is smaller than the small angle approximation",
            "Z": "It depends on the square root of the amplitude"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A motor has a DC resistance of 5 ohms. The motor operates on 220 volt AC, and when running at full speed, it generates a back electromotive force of 200 volts. What is the current, in amperes, drawn when the motor operates at top speed?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.4",
            "X": "4",
            "Y": "40",
            "Z": "44"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Assuming g = 10 meters per second squared and the density of freshwater is 1000 kilograms per cubic meter, what is the buoyancy force in newtons exerted on a rock with mass of 100 kilograms and a volume of 10,000 cubic centimeters sitting at the bottom of a freshwater lake?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10",
            "X": "100",
            "Y": "1000",
            "Z": "10000"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following best estimates the momentum carried by an electromagnetic wave with energy of 30 joules?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10-7",
            "X": "10-5",
            "Y": "3 x 10-7",
            "Z": "9 x 10-5"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Given R = 1.097 \u00d7 107 inverse meters, which of the following represents the wavelength of the longest wavelength Lyman line of the hydrogen spectrum in meters and the region of the electromagnetic spectrum in which it lies?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1.22 \u00d7 10-7; ultraviolet",
            "X": "1.22 \u00d7 10-7; visible",
            "Y": "1.22 \u00d7 10-6; infrared",
            "Z": "1.22 \u00d7 10-6; visible"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Assuming a metabolic rate of 500 watts, how much energy in joules is transformed by a 70 kilogram person while exercising for 1 hour?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1500",
            "X": "1.8 million",
            "Y": "5 .4 million",
            "Z": "6.3 trillion"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the speed of a particle that has a Lorentz factor of 3.0?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "23",
            "X": "(32)/2",
            "Y": "(2 2)/3",
            "Z": "(2 )3"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A sports car driver slams the brakes and the car slows from 90 miles per hour to a complete stop in 4 seconds. In terms of g, which of the following is closest to the car\u2122s acceleration?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "-0.5 g",
            "X": "-g",
            "Y": "-2g",
            "Z": "-5g"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a nuclear plant, 1 kilogram of mass is converted to energy. Given c = 3 x 108 meters per second, how much energy would be produced?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "9 megajoules",
            "X": "9 gigajoules",
            "Y": "3 terajoules",
            "Z": "90 petajoules"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Bats find their prey in the dark via echolocation [ek-oh-loh-KAY-shuhn]. Given that the speed of sound is 300 meters per second, if a bat emits a chirp at a frequency of 66 kilohertz, what is the smallest size of insect in millimeters it is able to detect?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.2",
            "X": "1",
            "Y": "5",
            "Z": "16"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Water flows at 2.0 meters per second through a tube of radius 1 centimeter. The dynamic viscosity of the water is 1.0 \u00d7 10-3 pascal seconds. Which of the following best represents the Reynolds number and the nature of the flow, given that the density of water is 1.0 \u00d7 103 kilograms per cubic meter?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "40,000; turbulent",
            "X": "40,000; laminar",
            "Y": "20,000; turbulent",
            "Z": "20,000; laminar"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 1000-watt oven is connected to a 240-volt AC power source. Which of the following is nearest the peak voltage across the oven?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "120",
            "X": "270",
            "Y": "340",
            "Z": "370"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following experiments provided evidence in favor of the wave theory of light?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Young's double slit experiment",
            "X": "Michelson-Morley experiment",
            "Y": "Robert Millikan's oil-drop experiment",
            "Z": "Huygens' experiment"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If bombarding a beryllium target by alpha particles produces a neutron, which of the following must also be produced?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Lithium",
            "X": "Boron",
            "Y": "Carbon",
            "Z": "Nitrogen"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following ways will allow you to increase the capacitance of a parallel-plate capacitor?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Decreasing the plate separation",
            "X": "Increasing the plate separation",
            "Y": "Decreasing the surface area of each plate",
            "Z": "Increasing the charge on the plates"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An electron and positron collide and annihilate [uh-NY-uh-layt] one another. Which of the following is nearest the energy released, in mega electronvolts?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.5",
            "X": "1",
            "Y": "2",
            "Z": "10"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The wavelength shift of light from a quasar gives the recessional speed v 108 meters per second. If the Hubble constant is 21.8 millimeters per second per light year, what is the approximate distance of the quasar in light years?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "108",
            "X": "109",
            "Y": "1010",
            "Z": "1011"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A lady in a spacecraft travelling away from the Earth at 4/5 the speed of light gives birth to a child at 1:00 p.m., which, according to the spacecraft\u2122s clock, is only 3 hours after the spacecraft departed from the Earth. Assuming constant acceleration during those 3 hours, what is the child's birth time according to a stationary clock on the Earth?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2:00 p.m.",
            "X": "4:00 p.m.",
            "Y": "6:00 p.m.",
            "Z": "7:30 p.m."
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If the magnitude of a magnetic field is multiplied by 4, by what factor is the magnitude of the energy difference E [delta E] between electron states  ms = \u00b1 122T multiplied?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "4",
            "X": "2",
            "Y": "1/2",
            "Z": "1/4"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "During Bragg diffraction, x-rays are shone on a crystal to determine the crystal's structure. Providing your answer in scientific notation, if x-rays with 1 nanometer wavelength are incident on a crystal and the second maximum appears at 30 degrees, what is the lattice spacing, in meters, of the crystal being studied?",
        "Answer": "2 x 10-9"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If the viscous force acting on an object moving through a liquid or gas is modeled as F = -bv, where F is the resistive force, v is the velocity, and b is a constant, which of the following types of equation will need to be solved in order to determine the acceleration as a function of time?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Transcendental",
            "X": "Differential",
            "Y": "Hyperbolic",
            "Z": "Logarithmic"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two objects of masses m1 and m2 with speeds v1 and v2, where  v2 = 0, suffer collision, stick together, and move off with speed V. Which of the following equals the ratio v1/V?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1 + m2/m1",
            "X": "1 + m1/m2",
            "Y": "1 - m2/m1",
            "Z": "1 - m1/m2"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "You are at a party where the sound level is 70 decibels. Someone turns up the radio and the sound level suddenly increases to 100 decibels. By what factor has the sound intensity been multiplied?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "30",
            "X": "100",
            "Y": "1000",
            "Z": "10,000"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "After running for 20 minutes, a person\u2122s diastolic blood pressure is 100 millimeters of mercury. Providing your answer to two significant figures, what is the equivalent height in centimeters of a column of water, assuming the mass density of mercury is 13.6 grams per cubic centimeter and the mass density of water is 1.0 grams per cubic centimeter?",
        "Answer": "140"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the main difference between transverse and longitudinal waves?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Wavelength",
            "X": "Frequency",
            "Y": "Direction of the medium displacement with respect to the direction of wave propagation",
            "Z": "Phase difference"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the wavelength in nanometers of a photon of period 3.33 \u00d7 10-18 seconds?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1",
            "X": "3",
            "Y": "6",
            "Z": "9"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The number of lines per centimeter in a transmission grating is 10,000. What is the distance in meters between the lines of the grating?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10-3",
            "X": "10-4",
            "Y": "10-5",
            "Z": "10-6"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A proton is travelling with a speed of 300,000 meters per second to the east in a region where there is a magnetic field of 4 teslas pointing to the north. What is the magnitude and direction of the electric field in newtons per coulomb that must be present if the proton is to move through this region undeflected?",
        "Answer": "1,200,000, DOWN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A top is spinning at a rate of 2 radians per second when it slows uniformly to a stop in 15 seconds. Through how many revolutions did the top turn before stopping?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "7.5",
            "X": "7.5",
            "Y": "15",
            "Z": "15"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 100 microfarad parallel plate capacitor with air between the plates is connected to a 1.5 volt battery and becomes fully charged. The battery is disconnected from the capacitor and a dielectric with a dielectric constant of 7 is inserted between the plates. What is the charge in microcoulombs on one plate of the capacitor after the dielectric is inserted?",
        "Answer": "150"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A box is sitting on a ramp with a coefficient of static friction of 0.7. Which of the following is closest to the smallest ramp angle for which the box will begin to slide down the ramp?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "30\u00b0",
            "X": "35\u00b0",
            "Y": "45\u00b0",
            "Z": "60\u00b0"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Assuming that 1 atmosphere = 1.01 \u00d7 105 pascals and the density of water is 1000 kilograms per cubic meter, at what depth of water will the absolute pressure be 10.8 times the atmospheric pressure?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10.1 meters",
            "X": "101 meters",
            "Y": "1,010 meters",
            "Z": "10.1 kilometers"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In order to play a low C followed by a high C, one octave up, on a violin string, the violinist must increase the frequency of the string by what factor?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A large water rocket is in the process of taking off. It is noted that when the rocket weighs 600 newtons and has an exhaust speed of 5 meters per second that it doesn\u2122t leave the ground and it also ceases to apply a force on the ground. What must be the volume flow rate of the exhaust in liters per second?",
        "Answer": "120"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two satellites of masses m1 and m2, where m1 = 4m2, are deployed in circular orbits of the same radius in the gravitational field of Earth. What is the ratio of their linear speeds v1/v2?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1/4",
            "X": "1",
            "Y": "2",
            "Z": "4"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Assuming h = 6.63 x 10-34 joule seconds, what is the approximate energy of a photon in joules in a 1000 nanometer light beam?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2 \u00d7 10-19",
            "X": "2 \u00d7 10-18",
            "Y": "2 \u00d7 10-17",
            "Z": "4 \u00d7 10-18"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In order to see a full height image of your body, the vertical size of a mirror should be at least which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "One-fourth of your height",
            "X": "Half of your height",
            "Y": "Your height",
            "Z": "Twice your height"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A mass spectrometry experiment is performed with a magnetic field of 0.2 newtons per ampere meter and an electric field of 3.0 \u00d7 105 volts per meter. What is the speed of the ions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "750 meters per second",
            "X": "1500 meters per second",
            "Y": "150 kilometers per second",
            "Z": "1500 kilometers per second"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A light ray passes from air (n1 = 1.00) to three layers of the human eye: cornea (n2 = 1.33), lens (n3 = 1.41), and vitreous humor (n4 = 1.33). The speeds of light in these mediums are, respectively, v1, v2, v3, v4. Which of the following must be true about the relationships between the speeds of light in the different media?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "v1 < v2 < v3 < v4",
            "X": "v4 < v3 < v2 < v1",
            "Y": "v3 < v2 and v4 < v1",
            "Z": "v2 < v3 and v1 < v4"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two satellites are orbiting in circular orbits of radii r1 and r2 around a planet, where r1 = 4r2. What is the ratio of their periods of revolutions T1/T2?",
        "Answer": "8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A human eye has three layers with refractive indices n1 , n2 , and n3, where n1 < n2 and n1 = n3 . Which of the following properties of a light ray is the same in all layers?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Frequency only",
            "X": "Speed only",
            "Y": "Wavelength only",
            "Z": "Frequency and speed"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A door of area 3 square meters and thickness 4 centimeters is composed of a material whose thermal conductivity is 0.10 watts per meter Kelvin. What is the heat flow, in watts, through the door when the temperature difference is 10 Kelvin?",
        "Answer": "75"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A cheetah has an ability to accelerate from 0 to 30 meters per second in three seconds. Assuming constant acceleration, what distance in meters can the cheetah cover in this time interval?",
        "Answer": "45"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A pilot in training is placed into a human centrifuge where she will experience 5 g of force pulling her inward, the acceleration at which most people will begin to lose consciousness. Given g as 10 meters per second squared, if the centrifuge has a mechanical arm that holds her at a radius of 8 meters, how fast will the pilot be traveling in meters per second?",
        "Answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A chunk of gold with a density of 19,300 kilograms per cubic meter and volume of 0.3 cubic meters is completely submerged in water. Assuming g = 10 meters per second squared and the density of water is 1000 kilograms per cubic meter, what is the apparent weight of the gold in newtons?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "54,900",
            "X": "64,900",
            "Y": "183,000",
            "Z": "193,000"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "At the bottom of a loop-the-loop on a roller coaster, Mike\u2122s apparent weight is three times his weight. Assuming g = 10 meters per second squared and the diameter of the loop-the-loop is 20 meters, what is Mike\u2122s speed as a whole number in meters per second?",
        "Answer": "14"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, rank from greatest to least the moments of inertia for a golf club rotated about the following axes: 1) through the center of mass and parallel to the long axis of the club; 2) through the end of the handle and perpendicular to the long axis of the club; 3) through the center of mass and perpendicular to the long axis of the club.",
        "Answer": "2, 3, 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Properly match the type of energy transfer with the following four situations described: A) mechanical work; B) matter transfer; C) electromagnetic radiation; D) mechanical waves; with 1) pushing a box across the floor; 2) listening to music; 3) seeing a bright light bulb; 4) filling a gas tank with fuel.",
        "Answer": "A = 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A metal rod with coefficient of linear expansion 1.7 x 10-5 per degree Celsius and length 10.0 meters is at 20\u00b0 Celsius. What is the increase in length in millimeters when it is heated to 30\u00b0 Celsius?",
        "Answer": "1.7"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two pipes of diameters  and  are connected. What is the ratio of kinetic energy per unit volume (k1/k2) of water flowing through these pipes?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "[open parenthesis d2 over d1 close parenthesis to the power of 4]",
            "X": "[open parenthesis d2 over d1 close parenthesis to the power of 2]",
            "Y": "[open parenthesis d1 over d2 close parenthesis to the power of 4]",
            "Z": "[open parenthesis d1 over d2 close parenthesis to the power of 2]"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which law of physics explains how a changing magnetic field can produce an electric current?",
        "Answer": "FARADAY\u2122S"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A wireless router transmits an 802.11a Wi-Fi radio signal at 5 megahertz with a speed up to 54 megabits of data per second. What is the wavelength of the router\u2122s signal in meters?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10",
            "X": "15",
            "Y": "60",
            "Z": "150"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A particle is constrained to move in one dimension according to the relation x = 3t3 [x equals 3 t cubed], where x is the position from the origin in meters and t is time in seconds. What is the acceleration in meters per second squared of the particle at t = 7 seconds?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "18",
            "X": "126",
            "Y": "441",
            "Z": "1029"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An RLC circuit consists of a 2 henry inductor, a 1000 ohm resistor, an 8 farad capacitor, and a power supply in series. With what frequency in hertz must the power supply operate in order to establish resonance in the circuit?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1/8",
            "X": "1/4",
            "Y": "4",
            "Z": "8"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 1 kilogram object is travelling to the left at 3 meters per second when it explodes into 2 equal pieces. One piece is travelling at 7 meters per second to the left after the explosion. What is the velocity in meters per second of the other piece after the explosion?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1 to the right",
            "X": "1 to the left",
            "Y": "4 to the right",
            "Z": "4 to the left"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the root mean square voltage of a power supply that outputs a sinusoidal voltage with a frequency of 60 hertz and peak voltage of 120 volts?",
        "Answer": "85"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An electron is travelling due north when it experiences a magnetic field that is pointing vertically upward. In what direction will the electron be deflected when it initially encounters the field?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "North",
            "X": "South",
            "Y": "East",
            "Z": "West"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 35.4 x 10-11 coulomb charge is placed into a spherical Gaussian [GOUS-ee-uhn] surface with a radius of 5 meters. Given that epsilon naught is 8.85 x 10-12 farads per meter, what is the electric flux through this surface in newton meters squared per coulomb?",
        "Answer": "40"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A box of proper length l, proper width w, and proper height h is falling right-side up without tumbling toward the ground. The Lorentz contraction predicts that which of the following dimensions will be contracted?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Only height",
            "X": "Only height and length",
            "Y": "Only length and width",
            "Z": "Height, width and length"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A curve banked at 45\u00b0 has a radius of 62.5 meters. Assuming g = 10 meters per second squared, if a car is to navigate through the curve with no friction needed, with what speed, in meters per second, should the car travel?",
        "Answer": "25"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Electrons, protons, and neutrons obey the Pauli exclusion principle",
            "X": "The Pauli exclusion principle applies to all fermions",
            "Y": "All fermions have a spin of 1/2",
            "Z": "Electrons, protons, and neutrons obey Fermi-Dirac distribution"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two light waves travel the same distance of 6 \u00d7 10-7 meters but in mediums of refractive indices 1.54 and 1.00. Providing your answer in scientific notation to one significant figure, what is the time delay in seconds between waves?",
        "Answer": "1 \u00d7 10-15"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A projectile is launched tangentially to the Earth's surface with a speed such that it will neither collide with the Earth nor escape its gravity. Ignoring air resistance, this projectile's trajectory will have what shape?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Parabolic",
            "X": "Circular",
            "Y": "Elliptical",
            "Z": "Hyperbolic"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 100 meter spaceship moves past you with speed 3/22T. At what length in meters do you measure the spaceship?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "50",
            "X": "50 3",
            "Y": "",
            "Z": "200"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following quantities has an inverse-cubic relationship with distance?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The magnitude of the gravitational force between two point masses",
            "X": "The electric potential energy for a point charge",
            "Y": "The magnetic field strength at an axial point from the center of a current loop",
            "Z": "The speed of a satellite in circular orbit around the Earth"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A horizontal water pipe tapers so that the cross-sectional area of the pipe decreases. If the water moves at 3 meters per second in the larger portion of the pipe and at 15 meters per second in the smaller portion, what is the change in pressure, in pascals, as the water moves from the larger portion to the smaller portion of the pipe? Assume the density of water is 1000 kilograms per cubic meter and incompressible.",
        "Answer": "-108000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Schr\u00f6dinger's equation is a fundamental part of what scientific theory?",
        "Answer": "QUANTUM MECHANICS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A rocket sled can accelerate to 40 meters per second in 0.05 seconds. What force, in newtons, would a 100 kilogram test dummy on the rocket sled experience from this motion?",
        "Answer": "80,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two spheres, each with a charge of 3 microcoulombs, are separated by 9 meters. Given that k = 9 x 109 meters per farad, how much electric potential energy in joules is stored in this combination of charges?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "9 x 10-6",
            "X": "1 x 10-3",
            "Y": "9 x 10-3",
            "Z": "9 x 109"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In 1955, a soldier's parachute failed to deploy, causing him to fall 1200 feet from the plane to the ground. However, he managed to land in a snow bank, surviving the fall and suffering only minor injuries. Assuming the paratrooper weighed 100 kilograms, that he had reached terminal velocity of approximately 50 meters per second, and that the snow exerts an average force of 120,000 newtons, what minimum depth of snow, in meters to one decimal place, was necessary to stop him?",
        "Answer": "1.0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A wire carries a current of 2 amperes vertically upward. What is the magnitude and direction of the magnetic field in teslas produced by the wire 4 millimeters to the North of the wire?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1 x 10-4, West",
            "X": "1 x 10-4, East",
            "Y": "2 x 10-4, West",
            "Z": "2 x 10-4, East"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A solid sphere of uniform density rolls down an incline without slipping. At the bottom of the incline, what fraction of the kinetic energy of the sphere is rotational kinetic energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2/7",
            "X": "5/7",
            "Y": "1/2",
            "Z": "7/10"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 500 kilogram roller coaster car rounds the top of a hill with a radius of 25 meters at a speed of 15 meters per second. Given that the acceleration due to gravity is 10 meters per second squared, what is the normal force in newtons on the car at this point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "500",
            "X": "4500",
            "Y": "5000",
            "Z": "5500"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The coefficient of kinetic friction between a car\u2122s tires and a flat road is 0.8. The car is travelling at 40 meters per second when the driver slams on the brakes, causing the tires to lock. Assuming the acceleration due to gravity is 10 meters per second squared, how far will the car travel in meters after the driver hits the brakes?",
        "Answer": "100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 3 kilogram mass, a 4 kilogram mass, and a 5 kilogram mass are placed in a line at positions of 3 meters, 4 meters, and 5 meters, respectively, from the origin. Which of the following is nearest the location of the center of mass of this set of masses in meters from the origin?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.24",
            "X": "1.00",
            "Y": "4.17",
            "Z": "12.0"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 10 ohm resistor, a 20 ohm resistor, and a 30 ohm resistor are connected in series to a 12 volt battery. How much energy in joules is dissipated in heat through the 30 ohm resistor in 60 seconds?",
        "Answer": "72"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 20 kilogram mass is suspended from the end of a spring with a spring constant of 5 newtons per meter. If the mass is displaced 10 centimeters from equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm], what is the maximum speed of the mass in meters per second?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.05",
            "X": "0.25",
            "Y": "0.5",
            "Z": "2"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A distant planet has a 3:2 spin-orbit resonance due to tidal influences from its nearby host star. If this planet\u2122s sidereal day is 50 Earth days, how long, respectively, in Earth days, are its year and its solar day?",
        "Answer": "YEAR=75, SOLAR DAY=150"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following light movement directions is NOT able to produce total reflection from a surface perpendicular to a light beam?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "From water to air",
            "X": "From air to water",
            "Y": "From glass to air",
            "Z": "From oil to air"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 100 watt current of heat flows via conduction between two stable temperature reservoirs through a material of length 5 centimeters and cross-sectional area 0.5 square meters. If the length of material is extended to 1 meter and the cross-sectional area increased to 1 square meter, what is the new heat current in watts?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "5",
            "X": "10",
            "Y": "20",
            "Z": "50"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Three unequal forces act on an object. If the forces have magnitudes of 30 newtons, 50 newtons, and 70 newtons, what is the minimum net force in newtons that can act on this object?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0",
            "X": "10",
            "Y": "50",
            "Z": "90"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If we could capture one second of the total energy output of the Sun, store it, and use it with just 20% efficiency, how long, in years and to two significant digits, would this energy last based upon current global energy consumption? Assume the current global energy consumed per year is about 500,000,000 terajoules and the current luminosity of the Sun is 4 x 1026 watts.",
        "Answer": "160,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A 2 kilogram piece of clay is moving with a velocity of 4 meters per second to the north when it collides perfectly inelastically with another 2 kilogram piece of clay that is moving with a speed of 3 meters per second to the east. Which of the following is nearest the angle in degrees that the combined clay's velocity will make with the east after the collision?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "30\u00b0",
            "X": "37\u00b0",
            "Y": "53\u00b0",
            "Z": "60\u00b0"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given h = 6.6 x 10-34 joule seconds and providing your answer in scientific notation to one significant figure, what is the energy of a photon in joules with a wavelength of 0.1 micrometers?",
        "Answer": "2 x 10-18"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If the proper energy of 15 grams of matter is 1.35 x 10n joules, what is the value of n?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "9",
            "X": "12",
            "Y": "15",
            "Z": "18"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given that the elementary charge is 1.6 x 10-19 coulombs and providing your answer in scientific notation to one significant digit, how many excess electrons would be present in an object with a net negative charge of 2.5 coulombs?",
        "Answer": "2 x 1019"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "How many types of quarks are there in nature?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3",
            "X": "5",
            "Y": "6",
            "Z": "10"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the approximate distance in kilometers covered by a photon in one year?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "9 thousand",
            "X": "9 million",
            "Y": "9 billion",
            "Z": "9 trillion"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "You are traveling down a level highway in your car with mass 1000 kilograms at 30 meters per second when you see a deer and hit the brakes. How much time, in seconds, would it take to stop fully if the applied braking force is 5000 newtons?",
        "Answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Epsilon naught, o, and mu naught, o, are permittivity and permeability constants of free space, respectively. The speed of light is found in terms of these constants as which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1/ [1 over the square root of the quantity epsilon naught mu naught]",
            "X": "[the square root of the quantity epsilon naught mu naught]",
            "Y": "[the fraction with numerator mu naught and denominator 4 pi epsilon naught]",
            "Z": "/ [epsilon naught over mu naught]"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The power input in a perfectly efficient step-up transformer is which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Larger than the power output",
            "X": "Equal to the power output",
            "Y": "Smaller than the power output",
            "Z": "Not related to the power output"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A high energy photon near a nucleus can produce an electron-positron pair. What is the minimum energy a photon must have for this to happen?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Half of the proper energy of the electron",
            "X": "The proper energy of the electron",
            "Y": "Two times the proper energy of the electron",
            "Z": "Ten times the proper energy of the electron"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The Fahrenheit and Kelvin scales give the same reading at approximately which of the following temperatures?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0",
            "X": "212",
            "Y": "273",
            "Z": "575"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In neutron decay, a neutron decays into a proton, an electron, and what else?",
        "Answer": "AN ELECTRON ANTI-NEUTRINO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is true when light enters a denser medium and is refracted?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Wavelength remains unchanged",
            "X": "Wave speed increases",
            "Y": "Wavelength increases",
            "Z": "Frequency remains unchanged"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A one-dimensional electrical potential has the form V(x) = 4x2 - x. What is the electrical field associated with this potential in terms of x?",
        "Answer": "-8x + 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the excitation of an atom by light, what specific particle is responsible for the absorption of the photon?",
        "Answer": "ELECTRON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the power, in watts, dissipated by a circuit that supplies a potential difference of 1.5 volts and has a current of 0.1 amperes?",
        "Answer": "0.15"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What elementary particle is the carrier of the electromagnetic force?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Electron",
            "X": "Gluon",
            "Y": "Photon",
            "Z": "Neutrino"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What particle, recently confirmed to exist at the Large Hadron Collider, is postulated by electroweak theory to explain the origin of mass?",
        "Answer": "HIGGS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A stone is dropped out of a horizontally moving train. Which of the following is the shape of the path that the stone follows before hitting the ground?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Straight line",
            "X": "Circular",
            "Y": "Hyperbolic",
            "Z": "Parabolic"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If in a given DC circuit we double the voltage and halve the resistance, by what factor will the power be multiplied?",
        "Answer": "8 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Indicate, by number, all of the following three statements that explain why the actual acceleration due to gravity at any point on the Earth\u2122s surface would be different from the value calculated for that point using Newton\u2122s law of gravitation: 1) The earth\u2122s mass is not uniformly distributed; 2) The earth is not perfectly spherical; 3) The earth is rotating.",
        "Answer": "1, 2, 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What type of radiation, also known as braking radiation, is emitted whenever a charged particle is deflected by another charged particle?",
        "Answer": "BREMSSTRAHLUNG RADIATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following was the cause of the collapse of the Tacoma Narrows suspension bridge in 1940?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Aeroelastic flutter causing standing wave oscillations",
            "X": "Too much weight passing over the center of the bridge",
            "Y": "Bolt snapping due to mechanical resonance caused by marching soldiers",
            "Z": "Iron beams cracking and failing"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The electric field of a given charge is measured to be 1 newton per coulomb at a distance 10 centimeters away from the charge. According to Gauss\u2122s Law, what would the field be in newtons per coulomb at the same location if we were to double the charge?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.1",
            "X": "2",
            "Y": "10",
            "Z": "20"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A uniform magnetic field is applied perpendicularly to the velocity vector of a moving charged particle. What shape will the path of the charged particle be?",
        "Answer": "CIRCLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name for the resistive force that is related to Reynolds number and acts on objects in the direction of relative fluid flow velocity?",
        "Answer": "DRAG FORCE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The period of oscillation of a given simple pendulum on a grandfather\u2122s clock here on earth is 1 second. What would be the period in seconds of the same pendulum on another planet where the gravitational acceleration is 1/4 that of the earth?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.25",
            "X": "1",
            "Y": "2",
            "Z": "4"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the resistance of a resistor that has a 20 milliampere current when connected across the terminals of a 1.5 volt battery?",
        "Answer": "75 OHMS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A light ray passes from air (n = 1.00) to the cornea (n = 1.33) of the eye. If the angle of incidence is 30\u00b0, which of the following is true of the angle of refraction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Less than 30\u00b0",
            "X": "Equal to 30\u00b0",
            "Y": "Between 30\u00b0 and 45\u00b0",
            "Z": "Equal to 45\u00b0"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If Z = atomic number and A = mass number, the radius of an approximately spherical nucleus [NOO-klee-uhs] is proportional to which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Z3",
            "X": "A1/3",
            "Y": "A3",
            "Z": "Z1/3"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Light travelling through air strikes a transparent material of index of refraction n = 2 at an angle of 30 relative to the normal to the surface, and is then refracted an angle  [theta]. What is the value of sin() [sine theta] to two significant figures?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.10",
            "X": "0.25",
            "Y": "0.66",
            "Z": "1.0"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What group of subatomic particles, known to be emitted by the reactions that take place in the Sun, were recently confirmed to oscillate between three flavors, explaining the discrepancy between expected and observed numbers of these particles emitted by the Sun?",
        "Answer": "NEUTRINOS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An ideal refrigerator absorbs heat at -23\u00fbC and exhausts it at 27\u00fbC. What is its coefficient of performance?",
        "Answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An antihydrogen atom is made of what two components?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "An antiproton and a positron",
            "X": "An antiproton and an electron",
            "Y": "A proton and a positron",
            "Z": "A proton and a neutrino"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A capillary tube with an inner radius of 0.1 millimeter is partially dipped in a liquid with a surface tension of 0.1 newtons per meter, with approximately 0 degrees of contact angle. The density of the liquid is approximately the same as that of water. Calculate the liquid rise in the tube.",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2 millimeter",
            "X": "2 centimeter",
            "Y": "20 centimeter",
            "Z": "2 meter"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following does not interact with a magnetic field?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A magnet at rest",
            "X": "Moving electric charges",
            "Y": "A moving magnet",
            "Z": "Electric charges at rest"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The closest distance at which Gina can properly focus is 100 cm from her eye. The distance of normal vision is 0.25 m. Find the power in diopters [dy-OP-ters] of the converging lens for her eyeglass.",
        "Options": {
            "W": "-3",
            "X": "-0.03",
            "Y": "0.03",
            "Z": "3"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assuming the heat of fusion for water is 80 calories per gram, what is the increase in entropy, in calories per Kelvin, for a 273 gram block of ice at 0 degrees Celsius when it melts?",
        "Answer": "80"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An -particle [alpha particle] and a proton, both initially at rest, are accelerated through a potential difference of 105 kilovolts. Find the ratio (K/Kp) [k alpha over k proton] of their final kinetic energies.",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1/4",
            "X": "1/2",
            "Y": "2",
            "Z": "4"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What fundamental physical constant is a baseline that gives the value of the absolute dielectric [dy-i-LEK-trik] constant of a classical vacuum?",
        "Answer": "PERMITTIVITY CONSTANT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A cord making a 60o angle with the floor pulls on a crate with a tension of 100 newtons along a 10 meter distance. How much work, in joules, is done on the crate by the pulling cord?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0",
            "X": "50",
            "Y": "500",
            "Z": "5000"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the principle quantum number of the only orbital of the hydrogen atom that has no angular dependence?",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A room has a uniform magnetic field of 0.5 tesla, directed into the floor. A 2.0-meter copper rod parallel to the floor and with one end pointed toward you is moving to the right with a speed of 100 meters per second. What is the motional electromotive force in volts, and which end (near or far) is at higher potential?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "25.0, far",
            "X": "25.0, near",
            "Y": "100.0, far",
            "Z": "100.0, near"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Unstable particles muons [MYOO-ons], pions [PY-ons], kaons, and sigmas have half-life times in the range of which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10-6 to 10-23 seconds",
            "X": "10-1 to 10-3 seconds",
            "Y": "10 to 1 seconds",
            "Z": "10-1 to 10-8 seconds"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Nuclear magnetic resonance, electron spin resonance spectroscopy, and Mossbauer spectroscopy are all based on what physical effect that is associated with the splitting of spectral lines in the presence of a magnetic field?",
        "Answer": "ZEEMAN EFFECT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An electromagnetic wave goes into a block of glass with an index of refraction of n = 1.1. In terms of the speed of light C, which of the following is closest to the speed at which the wave propagates inside the glass medium?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "C",
            "X": "0.1C",
            "Y": "0.9C",
            "Z": "1.1C"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Water is warmed by an immersed coil that generates 1000 joules of heat per second when an electric potential difference of 10 volts is applied across its ends. What is the resistance, in ohms, of the heater wire?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.1",
            "X": "1",
            "Y": "10",
            "Z": "100"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What physical quantity does the reciprocal of the square root of the product of vacuum magnetic permeability and electric susceptibility represent?",
        "Answer": "THE SPEED OF LIGHT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The compressibility of an object\u2122s volume is dependent on which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Young\u2122s modulus",
            "X": "Bulk modulus",
            "Y": "Volume stress",
            "Z": "Tensile stress"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What must be the capacitance in farads of a capacitor storing 10 joules of energy and having 1 volt potential difference between its plates?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2",
            "X": "20",
            "Y": "200",
            "Z": "2000"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A necessary condition for a standard laser is that a population of atoms or molecules must have more members in an excited metastable state than in a lower energy state. What is the term for this scenario?",
        "Answer": "POPULATION INVERSION  _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A single semiconductor crystal that has been selectively doped with small amounts of phosphorous on one end, and aluminum on the other end, creates what type of connection?",
        "Answer": "P-N JUNCTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider a linear temperature scale, J, on which the boiling point of water is 65 degrees J and the freezing point is negative 15 degrees J. To what temperature in degrees Fahrenheit does a temperature of negative 55 degrees J correspond?",
        "Answer": "-58"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What phenomenon, often observed when nuclear waste is stored in water, occurs when charged particles travel through a medium faster than the speed of light in that medium?",
        "Answer": "CHERENKOV RADIATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A rocket is at rest in deep space. It suddenly experiences a linear acceleration of 50 meters per second squared for 5 seconds, coasts for 3.0 seconds, and then decelerates at 2.0 meters per second squared until coming to a halt. How far, in meters and to two significant figures, does the rocket travel during the deceleration phase of its journey?",
        "Answer": "16,000 METERS _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following laws or principles gives a physical interpretation for the sign convention used in Faraday\u2122s law of induction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Lenz\u2122s law",
            "X": "Ampere\u2122s law",
            "Y": "Coulomb\u2122s law",
            "Z": "Gauss\u2122s law"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, give all of the following three statements that are true of Carnot engines: 1) Carnot\u2122s theorem limits the efficiency of engines to less than that of a Carnot engine; 2) The Carnot cycle consists of only reversible steps; 3) The concept of entropy arose from the limits stated by the Carnot cycle.",
        "Answer": "1, 2, 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three experiments that demonstrate the particle nature of light: 1) photoelectric effect; 2) dual-slit experiment; 3) Davisson-Germer experiment.",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT featured in the Bohr model of the atom?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Quantized energy levels",
            "X": "Densely packed nucleus",
            "Y": "Atomic orbitals",
            "Z": "Electrostatic attraction"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number rank the following three systems of materials, from lowest to highest, in terms of their coefficients of kinetic friction: 1) rubber on concrete; 2) human joints; 3) ice on ice.",
        "Answer": "2, 3, 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the behavior of black bodies?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "At high enough temperatures, black bodies will stop emitting in the microwave region",
            "X": "The Stefan-Boltzmann law relates the power radiated by a black body to temperature squared",
            "Y": "Approximating a human as a black body shows that most of a person\u2122s energy is radiated away as ultraviolet light",
            "Z": "Wien\u2122s law can be used to predict the color of a black body"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What type of electrical circuit component can be used to store energy electrostatically?",
        "Answer": "CAPACITOR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Indicate, by number, all of the following three forces that would act on a rock as it slides along the ground after being kicked:  1) gravity; 2) friction; 3) air resistance.",
        "Answer": "1, 2, AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three quantities that are constant for a body in uniform circular motion:  1) kinetic energy; 2) speed; 3) angular velocity.",
        "Answer": "1, 2, AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Indicate, by number, all of the following three optical properties that are involved in the production of rainbows:  1) dispersion; 2) absorption; 3) total internal reflection.",
        "Answer": "1 AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The idea that energy is quantized in order to explain the observed black-body radiation was first postulated by what German scientist?",
        "Answer": "MAX PLANCK"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What scientist first described the wave mechanics of quantum particles with his namesake wave function?",
        "Answer": "ERWIN SCHRODINGER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What physical constant is the magnitude of electric charge per mole of electrons?",
        "Answer": "FARADAY CONSTANT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many baryons [BAR-ee-ons] and leptons, respectively, are found in a single alpha particle?",
        "Answer": "FOUR AND ZERO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Unpolarized light is passed through a single polarizing filter. What fraction of the intensity of the light emerges from the filter?",
        "Answer": "1/2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If 15 joules of work are required to move 3.0 coulombs of charge between two points, what is the potential difference in volts between these two points?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3",
            "X": "5",
            "Y": "15",
            "Z": "45"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "To the nearest whole decibel, a doubling of sound intensity is equal to an increase of how many decibels?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Indicate, by number, all of the following quantities that would change if the radius of the Earth decreases but the mass remains the same:  1) length of day; 2) kinetic energy of rotation; 3) length of year.",
        "Answer": "1 AND 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Indicate, by number, all of the following three quantities that would change for a wave of light entering water from the air:  1) frequency; 2) wavelength; 3) velocity.",
        "Answer": "2 AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By what factor is the energy required to increase the speed of a car from rest to 10 meters per second multiplied to find the energy required to increase the speed of the same car from 10 meters per second to 20 meters per second?",
        "Answer": "3 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In order for a process to have no change in entropy, which of the following properties must it possess?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Spontaneous",
            "X": "Reversible",
            "Y": "Endothermic",
            "Z": "Exothermic"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assume the speed of sound in air is 344 meters per second, and a string vibrates at 20 Hertz.  To the nearest tenth of a meter, what is its wavelength?",
        "Answer": "17.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two point charges, Q1 and Q2 [Q one and Q two], that have charges of +10 [ plus ten] Nanocoulumbs and -10 [minus ten] Nanocoulombs, respectively, are placed at two vertices of an equilateral triangle. If a third charge, Q3 [Q three], of +5 [plus five] Nanocoulombs is placed at the third vertex, what is the potential energy associated with Q3?",
        "Answer": "ZERO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is correct regarding the phenomenon of redshift with respect to a light source?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It occurs when a light source is moving away from the observer",
            "X": "It occurs when a light source is moving towards the observer",
            "Y": "It only occurs when a light source is accelerating away from the observer",
            "Z": "It only occurs when a light source is accelerating towards the observer"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three phenomena that could be observed in a radio wave:  1. diffraction, 2. interference, 3. deflection in an electric field.",
        "Answer": "1 AND 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "From least to greatest, order the magnitudes of the following three quantities for a wheel on a car that is skidding along the road, if the wheel continues to rotate:  1. Translational kinetic energy, 2. Rotational kinetic energy, 3. Total kinetic energy.",
        "Answer": "2, 1, 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Indicate, by number, all of the following three particles that are considered to be force-carrying particles by the Standard Model:  1) photon; 2) gluon;  3) graviton",
        "Answer": "1, 2, AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following four particles that can be found in isolation:  1) up quark; 2) electron; 3) neutrino; 4) proton.",
        "Answer": "2, 3, AND 4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term used to describe a process that exchanges no heat energy with its environment?",
        "Answer": "ADIABATIC"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle states that the product of the uncertainty of position and the uncertainty of momentum must be greater than the reduced form of what constant?",
        "Answer": "PLANCK CONSTANT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A spring with spring constant k = 200 Newtons per meter with a 0.5 kilogram mass attached is released from rest at x = 0.02 meters. In meters per second, what is the magnitude of the maximum velocity attained by the mass?",
        "Answer": "0.4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How much energy, in joules, does a circuit containing a 9 volt battery and a 6 ohm resistor dissipate over 8 seconds?",
        "Answer": "108"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the radius of a body is smaller than its Schwarzschild radius, the body becomes what?",
        "Answer": "BLACK HOLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two objects collide in a perfectly inelastic collision. Which of the following quantities is not conserved in the collision?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Kinetic energy",
            "X": "Momentum",
            "Y": "Potential energy",
            "Z": "Total energy"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A Carnot [kahr-NOH] engine takes 2000 joules of heat from a reservoir at 500 kelvin, does some work, and then discards some heat to a reservoir [REZ-er-vwahr] at 300 kelvin. How much heat, in joules, is discarded by the Carnot engine?",
        "Answer": "1200 JOULES"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The statement that all points on a wavefront will serve as point sources for secondary wavelets is based on what principle?",
        "Answer": "HUYGENS PRINCIPLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three statements that are true of the cosmic microwave background radiation:  1) The temperature of the radiation can be approximated by a black body; 2) The thermal black body spectrum is at a temperature of approximately 6 Kelvin; 3) The radiation is strongest in the radio and microwave regions of the electromagnetic spectrum.",
        "Answer": "1 AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Millikan\u2122s oil-drop experiment was used to calculate what physical value?",
        "Answer": "CHARGE OF THE ELECTRON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true regarding a system undergoing rotation?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Torque is the physical quantity describing a force causing rotation about an axis",
            "X": "Moment of inertia describes the tendency of an object to resist changes in angular momentum",
            "Y": "Torque is required to tilt the axis of rotation",
            "Z": "Conservation of angular momentum explains why pulsars will never stop spinning"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An object is placed 20 centimeters in front of a thin convex lens of focal length 10 centimeters. What must be the image distance in centimeters?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2",
            "X": "5",
            "Y": "10",
            "Z": "20"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two people slide a 22 kilogram box across a frictionless floor a distance of 8 meters. Person 1 applies a force of 10 newtons to the box, while Person 2 applies a force of 12 newtons to the box in the same direction as Person 1. What is the velocity of the box, in meters per second, when it reaches the end of the 8 meters?",
        "Answer": "4  _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A horizontally polarized electromagnetic wave is travelling in the positive x direction. When the electric field is pointing in the negative z direction, what direction is the magnetic field pointing?",
        "Answer": "POSITIVE Y DIRECTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following 3 changes that would be observed if you were a stationary observer watching a spaceship pass by travelling at 99% of the speed of light:  1) The ship would appear longer; 2) A clock on the ship appears to run slower than your wristwatch; 3) As the ship travels away from you, it appears to be bluer.",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What values in quantum systems are used to describe conserved quantities that tend to take on integer or half-integer values, examples of which are spin, azimuthal, and parity?",
        "Answer": "QUANTUM NUMBERS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A cannonball is shot vertically upward from ground level with an initial speed of 100 meters per second. Approximating g as 10 meters per second squared, and ignoring air resistance, what is the maximum height, in meters, that the cannonball reaches?",
        "Answer": "500  _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A truck moving at 50 meters per second begins to brake, which applies a constant force of 1000 newtons to the truck. The truck rolls 20 meters before stopping. In joules, what is the initial kinetic energy of the truck?",
        "Answer": "20,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following quarks does NOT have an electric charge of +2/3 [plus two-thirds]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Up",
            "X": "Strange",
            "Y": "Charm",
            "Z": "Top"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A gold leaf electroscope is negatively charged by touching it with a negatively charged conductor. You then bring a positively charged glass rod close to, but not touching, the top of the electroscope. Which of the following occurs?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The leaves do not move",
            "X": "The leaves spread further apart",
            "Y": "The leaves get closer together",
            "Z": "The leaves first spread further apart, then move closer together"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Indicate, by number, all of the following four particles that are acted upon by gravity:  1) electron; 2) photon; 3) neutrino; 4) top quark.",
        "Answer": "1, 2, 3 AND 4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "\u0152 Short",
        "Question": "Answer    An 80 kilogram hockey player is skating towards the blue line at a speed of 4.5 meters/second. He briefly looks away and accidently collides with a 100 kilogram teammate head on who was standing in place. At what speed, in meters per second, do the two players slide across the ice if they get tangled up with each other after the collision?",
        "Answer": "2  ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "PHYSICS",
        "Type": "\u0152 Multiple",
        "Question": "Choice    Which of the following components of a car provides the best example of a damped oscillator?   W) Brakes   X) Shock absorbers    Y) Rack-and-pinion steering column   Z) Differential",
        "Answer": "X) SHOCK ABSORBERS"
    }
]